<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-06T22:45:39-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush</title><subtitle>Random Thoughts</subtitle><entry><title type="html">You need time to think</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/think/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You need time to think" /><published>2021-04-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-04-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/time-to-think</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/think/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/think.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@elijahdhiett?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Elijah Hiett&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/think?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between acquiring knowledge and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our gadgets are such that they remove any need for thinking. We can find all information in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem this leads to is that we always search for a ready made answer instead of thinking ourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen this during development a lot where some developers would search open source solutions or paid solution when in reality creating solution was easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens because of not thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking means you’ll question things from the first principles. To see if they are valid or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you scrutinize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals search for truth. Groups search for concensor. By always finding information rather than thinking, you increase chances of being same as others. Of course logical facts are undeniable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can think and articulate, you are powerful. You can influence people. People give you money. Ask for your advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning happens when you compare and contrast. Compare and contrast require time to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your problems get solved when you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear thinking also allows you to explain easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you dont use you lose you lose. So make time to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note talking is also probablatic. One should only write what they think about a topic if something is new and carefully thought through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest obstacle to thinking is we resist boredom. Boredom is important as it sparks creativity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/think.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/think.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">DRAFT On telling the truth and speaking up</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/truth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DRAFT On telling the truth and speaking up" /><published>2021-04-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-04-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/telling-the-truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/truth/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/truth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@brunovdkraan?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Bruno van der Kraan&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/truth?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By telling the truth, you won’t have to remember much. You won’t have to remember who you lied to and what. And so you can express yourself without second guessing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you always tell the truth, you won’t lie to yourself. Wishful thinking is a trap which will have an easier time avoiding if you always tell the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;foundation&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telling the truth is easier when you believe certain assumptions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By telling the truth, the best possible scenario that can happen will happen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While speking the truth even if you are afraid to think you are alone know that others exists. they are just as afraid as you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are overwhelmed, see if you are telling the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;telling-the-truth-unhides-the-fog-truth-always-shines&quot;&gt;Telling the truth unhides the fog. Truth always shines.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not telling the truth is bad for self estime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-speak-up&quot;&gt;Why you should speak up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At meetings, everybody does not understand. By speaking up and asking questions, giving suggestion everyone benifits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By speaking up, likeminded people will come to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By speaking up, you increase trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By speaking up, you never have the regret of being silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By speaking up, if someday you are on a wrong track others will speak up and tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;framing&quot;&gt;Framing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framing is something we use all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every information has to be compressed in some way else it will take forever to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we have to make sure we be as precise as possible without taking forever to convey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-speak-up-and-tell-the-truth&quot;&gt;How to speak up and tell the truth?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tell-the-truth-or-atleast-not-lie&quot;&gt;Tell the truth or atleast not lie.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philosophy is not mathematics. There are no hard rules let’s assume their is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have have to hide facts from let’s say kids, that is okay. But don’t lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;speak-your-mind-and-always-tell-the-truth&quot;&gt;Speak your mind and always tell the truth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-it-fast&quot;&gt;Tell it fast&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be precise in your speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-it-fully&quot;&gt;Tell it fully&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-not-do-things-that-you-hate&quot;&gt;Do not do things that you hate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;act-so-that-you-can-tell-the-truth-about-how-you-act&quot;&gt;Act so that you can tell the truth about how you act&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live by the truth. Listen to your consons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;express-your-intend-properly&quot;&gt;Express your intend properly.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be polite. Don’t try to humilate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By framing make sure your express the intend of solving the problem else your speaking truth will backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are good at articulations, you should articulate for someone else specially with the person you are having the argument. The goal is to get to the truth and understanding, and not to win.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/truth.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/truth.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">DRAFT: Applied Information/Knowledge</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/applied-info/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DRAFT: Applied Information/Knowledge" /><published>2021-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/information</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/applied-info/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/applied-info.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@pro321?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;prottoy hassan&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/thinking?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information is clutter. Finding applicable information is power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more applicable information you can find, the more you can apply them and make better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-information-should-be-applied&quot;&gt;Why information should be applied?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information if not applied is meaningless unless it is your profession to find and document new information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By appling information faster, you will solve your problems faster or atleast move towards solving your problems faster.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The information that is not learned will be forgotten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-applicable-information&quot;&gt;Finding applicable information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to find applicable information, these are a few that come to mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;planning&quot;&gt;Planning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A plan may or may not be used, but planning is useful because it uncovers many aspects of the problem. It is easier to discovers paths to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;asking-questions&quot;&gt;Asking Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing People who can answer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching and Googling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reading-books&quot;&gt;Reading Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have yet to understand the structure of many types of books so I haven’t practices this yet: skip pages liberay. Read only chapters that are applicable then close the book and live your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being multidisciplinary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mental-models-and-heuristics&quot;&gt;Mental Models and Heuristics.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;segregation-of-duties--friends-who-what-the-best-for-you&quot;&gt;Segregation of Duties / Friends who what the best for you.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge vs Thinking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need time to think&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having knowledge is not enough. You need time to think. Absorb the information and make it your own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/applied-info.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/applied-info.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keeping Web Dev Code proper</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/web-dev-clean/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keeping Web Dev Code proper" /><published>2021-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/keeping-web-dev-clean</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/web-dev-clean/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/web-dev-clean.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@markusspiske?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Markus Spiske&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/web-development?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choose-a-stable-framework&quot;&gt;Choose a stable framework.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe Angular is a more stable long term solution than React which requires too much learning. Less modification is required therefore your code will last longer. At least it seems that way right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-very-small-modular-pieces&quot;&gt;Make very small modular pieces.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Angular, create components even for small things like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;img&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;video&lt;/code&gt; tag. You’ll find that there are certain attributes you assign to every &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;img&lt;/code&gt; tag that can be taken care of from one place&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate app logic from business logic. You should be able to copy-paste these modules into another code base and use it without changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In angular, make use of everything: components, service, directives, pipes, interceptors, etc/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-layout-components&quot;&gt;Make layout components&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are common layouts you use throughout the application. Coding them in one place reduces unnecessary duplications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to deal with CSS is to write less of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS gets messy fast. By keeping your components small. You are halfway there to a good CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also make good use of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;display: flex&lt;/code&gt;. It gets most of the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to keep HTML clutter-free is to not write javascript/typescript logic in it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angular provides a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ts&lt;/code&gt; file, use it for everything. Even for ngStyle or ngClass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will keep your HTML very clean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;get&lt;/code&gt; method to keep things clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-very-few-utility-classes&quot;&gt;Have very few utility classes.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s stupid to have too many utility classes spread throughout your codebase. Have only a few at a single place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only keep a utility class or method if it is used. Remove unnecessary code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsBjURrPoezykLs9EqgamOA&quot;&gt;YouTube channel: Fireship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WA95EJGhbLc&quot;&gt;How to Properly Structure Angular Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/web-dev-clean.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/web-dev-clean.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">DRAFT The Personal MBA</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/mba/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DRAFT The Personal MBA" /><published>2021-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/personal-mba</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/mba/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been thinking and writing a lot of article but the amount of time it was taking me was huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this book eliminates 80% of my future blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that it would be better that starts with general ideas which I could later look deeply into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are total 271 concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me 3 months to read the book. I think it will take next 3 months to summarize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;book-summary&quot;&gt;Book Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses are opened by ordinary people like us. You don’t need to fixate of getting a business angst, certification or imposter syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-dont-need-to-know-it-all&quot;&gt;You Don’t Need To Know It All&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principles are less. Methods are too many. The one who knows principles can choose his own methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do not need to learn everything. You only need to know a small set of business concepts to make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-experience-necessary&quot;&gt;No Experience Necessary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions-not-answers&quot;&gt;Questions, Not Answers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education is the answer to all questions not just one. If you know how to ask the right question, you’ll find answers to your problems faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mental-models-not-methods&quot;&gt;Mental Models, not Methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;business&quot;&gt;Business&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;value-creation&quot;&gt;Value Creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;marketing&quot;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is about finding the right prospespects, keeping their attention and make them interested in what you have to offer. Every business needs to do it because no matter how good your product is, you won’t have profit until your customers can find you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direct-Marketing&lt;/strong&gt; sometimes reduces the lines between itself and sales because it reduces amount of time to close the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But overall, Marketing and Sales are completely different activities. Marketing is about keeping attention. Sales is about closing the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The product that does not sell without advertising. Will not sell with advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attention&quot;&gt;Attention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number 1 rule of marketing is that attention is limited and every other company is trying to grab attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are only interested in things they like and the things that are important to them. Therefore high quality attention is important. And high quality attention must be earned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the aim is not be popular. The aim is to increase profits. So if you can get yourself on TV, you’ll be popular but you’ll waste a lot of time not finding the &lt;strong&gt;right customer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;receptivity&quot;&gt;Receptivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People ignore what they don’t care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Receptiveless is how open a person is to your message. There are three parts to this: message, timing and medium&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message&lt;/strong&gt;: The person should be interested in the message you are offering.
&lt;strong&gt;Timing&lt;/strong&gt;: The person should recieve the message at the right time.
&lt;strong&gt;Medium&lt;/strong&gt;: The person should recieve message from the right medium. Example: A personlized message will likely be more effective than same commercial message to every person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a business perspective, you want your customers to be as receptive as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;remarkability&quot;&gt;Remarkability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remarkability is being enough different to pique the interest of your customers. Being remarkable voiletes customer’s usual expectations and grabs their attention for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High remarkability generated word of mouth. Advertisement is what is done when you are not remarkable (or not remarkable enough).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;probable-purchaser&quot;&gt;Probable Purchaser&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming everyone will purchase your product is bad. There are only a set of people who would. So it makes no sense to try to appeal to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appeal to the right customer at the right time. Every good marketing compain does this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preoccupation&quot;&gt;Preoccupation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always assume that your prospect has preoccupied himself/herself with something. Your goal is to be interesting enough so that you can grab their attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The threshhold for this maybe low or high depending on your environment and type of product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;level-of-awareness&quot;&gt;Level of Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be sensitive to how much your probable customer cares about your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 5 levels to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unaware&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem Aware&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solution Aware: Knows solution but not aware of specific offer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offer Aware&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full Aware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to identiy the level the prospect is at the push them towards upper level -&amp;gt; The &lt;strong&gt;Funnel&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to do it is to personalize your message for each prospect and level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;end-result&quot;&gt;End Result&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans don’t always do what the think they are doing. Eg: People who buy SUV don’t use it for it’s purpose. They use it to feed their status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out what they really desire and appeal to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ankush: Combine this with Education Based Selling. You cannot sell loads of crap just because it makes someone feel high status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;demonstration&quot;&gt;Demonstration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demonstration is one of the oldest tricks which significantly increases probability of sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demonstrate your product to the customer. Make them use it. Let them see the results themself. This removes a lot of doubts the prospect may have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;qualification&quot;&gt;Qualification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is better to screen prospects and find the right customers that to have bad customers. This has to happen before sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally your funnel should remove bad customer. Bad onces will consume un-neccesary time, attention and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that you can focus on better serving the right once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prospect who is not right for you may be right for your competitors. You don’t have to be jumpy about not serving bad prospects, help them by refer them to competitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;point-of-market-entry&quot;&gt;Point of Market Entry&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point of market entry is the point at which the random prospect becomes interested in finding the solution to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain markets have obvious entry point and exit point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having the attention of the prospect during point of entry is valuable because the prospect will set you as a standard while comparing with your competitors. This increases your likelihood of sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point of entry is the reason why organic and paid-ad search are so valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;addressability&quot;&gt;Addressability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain problems and types of prospects that open up in public. These can be sensitive issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’re not going to find a TV Ad style boadcast to do much of a trick or expect a viral word of mouth recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can position yourself in places where they are more liekly to find you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example for sensitive health issues, doctors are an easy medium to get to your prospect compared to TV ad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays people also Google the solution to their problem, therefore targetted ads are also useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressability is how easy it is to get in touch with your prospects. Ideally you wannt high addressibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose an already addressable market, you’ll reduce your efforts significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;desire&quot;&gt;Desire&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desire is one of the part of marketing that get’s people off. If someone does not desire your product, no one will purchase it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scammy marketters are people who promise a product which is different for what they deliver. But it is almost impossible to sell someone something that they don’t desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal is not to appeal to people who don’t desire, it is to find people who can convince themself of how your offer will benifit them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more core human drives your marketting offer connects to the more effective it will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;visualization&quot;&gt;Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When your work speaks for itself, don’t interrupt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test driving is one of the most effective tactics. The prospects stop rationlizing, the emotional part of their brain takes in and they start wanting. Once that is done, it is only a matter of time before sale is made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our minds are designed to visulize the consiquences of our actions. By making it easy (by putting as much sensory info as possible) for your prospects to visulize how purchasing the product solves the problem and makes them feel, they will conclude with “I want this”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;framing&quot;&gt;Framing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everything we hear is an opinion, not a fact. Everything we see is a perspective, not the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framing a natural form of communication. There is always some sort of compression when we tell the image. Therefore it pays attention to be concious about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framing your communication to be persuasive and exact can get the point accross faster while honoring the listener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framing is not same as deciet, you are not lying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While framing make sure that the listener know what they need to know because if not done it will harm your reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Getting attention is not the same as getting paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offering free value is a quick way to attract potential customers. But the free value should be such that additional sales negate the amount of resources spent of free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done well, this will lead to sales you wouldn’t otherwise have made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;permission&quot;&gt;Permission&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one likes spam. So it is better to ask for people’s permission to send them more information in case of newletters, phonecalls, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not abuse your privilage. if you keep you keep providing real value in those newsletters, etc. you’ll find more people interested in your paid offering and will create a deeper relationship with the prospect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before asking for permission, make it clear what they’ll be getting and how it will benifit them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the next best thing since it reduces marketing cost and increase likelyhood of prospect purchase overtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hook&quot;&gt;Hook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smaller your message, the less likely people are to forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hook is a small enough message that keeps people’s attention and conways to them what you are offereing and who you are. It also makes it easy for people to tell about you to their firends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A million songs in your pocket -&amp;gt; IPod&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 hour work week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hook can be title, subtitle, slowgan etc. Use it in as many places as possble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generate a lot of hooks and test which onces work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hook grabs attention and the remainder of your marketing sales activities close the deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;call-to-action-cta&quot;&gt;Call To Action (CTA)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your prospects won’t know what to do next, so tell them and make it obvious for them.
CTA should be simple, single and obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best CTA ask for either sale or permission to follow up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure that every message you create has a clear CTA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;narrative&quot;&gt;Narrative&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common format of a narrative is “Hero’s Journey”. The hero recieves call of adventure and overcomes obstacles to achieve his goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customer wants to be a hero. Knowing that others are already walked on the path makes it easy for them to follow the path themself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore testomonials, case studies and other stories make it easy for customer to choose your call to adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;controversy&quot;&gt;Controversy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your position is to agree with everyone else, then you’ll become boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controvery means taking a stand for something you care about even if people disagree with it. Controversy promote discussion and attract peopl’e attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all controversty is good. As logn as you are able to maintain a sense of bigger picture of how you’re trying to help, a bit of controvery can create useful awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reputation&quot;&gt;Reputation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Like it or not, the market’s perception becomes your perception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branding often means increasing and maintaining reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are willing to pay to premium for a good reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reputation is not under direct control you can only try to improve it overtime. It includes everything: products, advertisement, customer service, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building reputation takes time and effort but is one of the most important marketing out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sales&quot;&gt;Sales&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People don’t like being sold. But they love to buy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sales process starts with a prospects and ends with an exciting new customer and more money in the bank. No sales = No Money = No Business&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best companies are earn trust of their prospects by making them understand why the offer is worth paying for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transaction&quot;&gt;Transaction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is only one boss, the customer who can fire everyone from CEO down just by spending money somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction is exchange of value between two or more party. It is a defining moment in any business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales is the only point in business cycle where resources flowes in. Therefore it is essential to remove any blockers to transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A transaction won’t happen if things are not of economic value. Often businesses fail to know what prospects want, therefore it is important to develop MVP and test fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When starting a new business, the objective is to make your first profitable transaction: that’s the point where your project turns into a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOU’s and Promises are not transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trust&quot;&gt;Trust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a certain amount of trust between the parties, a transaction cannot take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to build trust is by overtime dealing fairly and honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also signal trust worthyness: online reviews, credit and background check services and financial arrangement like escrow accounts exists to overcome lack of trust between parties. These can be very important in breaking mutual barriers towards transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easier it is to verify trust worthyness between parties, the better success of transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-ground&quot;&gt;Common Ground&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A compromise is the art of diving the cake in such a way that everyone believes that they have the biggest piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common ground is the state of overlaping interest between parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your job is the find where those circles overlap, which is much easier if you understadn what your customer wants or needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common ground is the precondition of any type of transaction. Else the transaction would not make any sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sales isn’t about convincing somebody to do something that is not in their interest. The more your interests align the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many paths to a successful transaction, which is the essense of negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negotiation is the process of exporing different common ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more open you are, the more liekly you will ind a acceptable common ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-pricing-uncertainity-principle&quot;&gt;The Pricing Uncertainity Principle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All prices are arbitary and malleable. Pricing is a executive decision. There is nothing stoping you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you must be able to support your asking price before a customer accepts it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you expect people to pay you good money for what you are offering, you must be able to prove a reason why the offered price is worth paying for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auctions are often an efficient way to establist the true market price for something that is difficult to reprove and for which no comparable item exists in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;four-pricing-method&quot;&gt;Four Pricing Method&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replacement Cost Method: How much would it cost to replace?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replacement cost is usually a cost plus calulator: figure out how much it costs to create, add your desired markup and set your price appropritately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Market comparison method: How much are other things like this selling for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discounted Cash Flow/ Net Present Value method: How much is it worth if it can bring in money over time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DCF/NPV is used onlt for pricing things that can produce an ongoing cash flow, whoch makes it a very scommon way to price businesses when they’re sold or acquired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Value Comparison: Who is this particularly valuable to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use other methods to set baseline but Value comparison is usually the optimal way to price since the value of an offer to a specific group can be quite high, resulting in a much better price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;price-transition-shock&quot;&gt;Price Transition Shock&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;value-based-selling&quot;&gt;Value Based Selling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;education-based-selling&quot;&gt;Education Based Selling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exclusivity&quot;&gt;Exclusivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-universal-currencies&quot;&gt;Three universal currencies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-dimensions-of-negotiations&quot;&gt;Three Dimensions of Negotiations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buffer&quot;&gt;Buffer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;value-delivery&quot;&gt;Value Delivery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finance&quot;&gt;Finance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-human-mind&quot;&gt;The Human Mind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businessed are built for people and by people. By learning how human mind works, we can find simpler and more efficient ways to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caveman-syndrome&quot;&gt;Caveman Syndrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our biology (body and mind) are made to survive in hunter gatherer world and not modern world. We haven livved long enough so that our bodies can adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we should not hard on ourselves and other since no one is made for the job we do. We are all using Ancient hardware wiwzaqth latest software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-yourself&quot;&gt;Working With Yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-with-others&quot;&gt;Working With Others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;systems&quot;&gt;Systems&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-systems&quot;&gt;Understanding Systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;analyzing-systems&quot;&gt;Analyzing Systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-systems&quot;&gt;Improving Systems&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/mba.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/mba.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">User Experience</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/ux/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="User Experience" /><published>2021-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/ux</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/ux/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ux.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@alvarordesign?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Alvaro Reyes&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;/s/photos/ux?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started learning about UX a few months ago. This post summarizes things I have learned far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-experience&quot;&gt;User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User Experience (UX) is about making a product or service in a way that is useful, easy and delightful for end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UX is something that has to be actively worked on. It won’t happen automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because if UX is not good,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User will get frustrated using the product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User will not find the product attractive to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And therefore they won’t use your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sympathize-with-the-user&quot;&gt;Sympathize with the user.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to understand what the users want is by sympathizing with the struggles that user’s face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video src=&quot;/images/ux/meme.mp4&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;test-fast&quot;&gt;Test fast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The earlier you can get feedback from the user, the shorter your product development cycle will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user can only know what he/she likes when he/she can experience the product. But since product development takes resources, prototyping helps to make the process faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to do it is to create paper prototypes. Paper is inexpensive, quick and has zero learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can prototype not just User Interface but also physical products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the paper prototype is created, you can increase the fidelity of the prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If a picture can say a thousand words, a prototype can save a thousand meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s best to involve the end-users as much as possible in the design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototype also helps engineers to build exactly what the end-users want and reduces overall development time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ui-is-part-of-ux-not-the-other-way-around&quot;&gt;UI is part of UX, not the other way around.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UX includes more than the User Interface. It includes every interaction the user has with the product or the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UX is concerned with how the user feels when using the product and not just how it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such things can include reducing the number of steps needed to perform a task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-checklist-for-beauty-of-user-interface&quot;&gt;A Checklist for “beauty” of User Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
    &lt;img class=&quot;docimage&quot; src=&quot;/images/ux/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
      &lt;figcaption&gt;As a developer how can I become a better designer.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ha_ooKAWAJI&quot;&gt;“As a developer how can I become a better designer?” ANSWERED!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/ux.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/ux.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/testing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing" /><published>2021-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/testing/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/testing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@mykjohnson?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Mykenzie Johnson&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/testing?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking&quot;&gt;Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not make assumptions. Always test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;productivity&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing makes it certain that you are moving in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test small, test often, and test fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your test coverage 100%. A good way to do that is that every line of commit should have test coverage 100%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test isolated pieces (Unit Test) before testing with other components (Integration Test).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TDD is 50% more efficient in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing is insurance. It may not find anything but when it does it saved big time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cleaner your code, the cleaner the tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing unit tests first only works well when you know exactly what you want to write. If you are experimenting. It may be useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;medical-field&quot;&gt;Medical Field&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you test, the more data points you have. The easy it will be to isolate the infected and avoid disease spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;maths&quot;&gt;Maths&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never accept the alternative hypothesis. You always reject it. You would almost never know if a hypothesis is 100% current. Unless it is a logical statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test, you can plug the numbers right in and see if the equation holds true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are learning, you can only know if you have learned right by testing yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/testing.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/testing.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to recover from injuries faster</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-think/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to recover from injuries faster" /><published>2021-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/injury-recovery</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-think/">&lt;p&gt;To recover from physical injuries faster like tightness and muscle soreness, your blood should be flowing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are someways to do it and all of them are important to do and lead to similar level of benifits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;massage&quot;&gt;Massage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not have to have a lot of pressure. It can be as soft as possible. Even little bit will help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cannot directly massage the area in pain, massage the area around it. This will atleast let blood flow near the effected area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cold-exposure&quot;&gt;Cold Exposure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take cold showers. Atleast 90 seconds. And don’t be afraid of the cold and start taking heavy breaths. Be calm, take deep breaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your’s body will start pumping blood faster to keep your body warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do atleast 30 seconds on the area that is directly effected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;move-and-exercise&quot;&gt;Move and Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problems multiply when you don’t move the part. Your body does not fully know how to recover a part until you show it how you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So move as much as you can. It’s okay if you can only do quater motion. Do it before it starts paining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you cannot move the specific body part because it is too painful. Move other parts, keep blood flowing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rest-enough-but-not-too-much&quot;&gt;Rest Enough but not too much.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest enough. You want to increase the probability that you’ll work the next day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To recover from physical injuries faster like tightness and muscle soreness, your blood should be flowing well.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ethical Capitalism</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/ethical-capitalism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethical Capitalism" /><published>2021-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/ethical-capitalism</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/ethical-capitalism/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ethical-capitalism.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@billow926?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;billow926&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/market?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capitalism-is-pure-genius&quot;&gt;Capitalism is Pure Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism involves pushing oneself to help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurs find a problem, solve it, and earn money as a reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In capitalism terms, money is proof that you are adding value to the world. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who don’t own a business, help others by becoming an employee, thus adding value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path-to-high-impact-is-through-capitalism&quot;&gt;The Path To High Impact Is Through Capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is efficient to adapt ourselves to the world than to do the opposite. Money is a form of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re going to need money to have the effect of any kind and at any stage. Being a capitalist (employee or entrepreneur), providing value, and being compensated with cash is the best way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capitalism--ethics&quot;&gt;Capitalism + Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism is not perfect. If not kept in check, it can turn evil (Example: East India Company) and provide no value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethics is not intrinsic to capitalism. And it probably never be as it is hard to map out. A combination of the two leads to more results than one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethics enables you to play long-term games, be trustworthy and win social trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mix of the two is probably why companies like Apple and Tata Group are so successful and trusted for so long. They provide high value while not compromising on ethics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems better to think in terms of adding value than to think in terms of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Naval Ravikant &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/ethical-capitalism.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/ethical-capitalism.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Path / Ethics</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Path / Ethics" /><published>2021-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/staying-on-the-path</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/path/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;sub style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jakeblucker?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Jake Blucker&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/road?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path&quot;&gt;The Path&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path is trying to be the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not the best you can be, you create or neglect problems. These problems accumulate and will make you suffer. And it’s not just you who will suffer. It will engulf all the people around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it’s an ethical crime to be weak&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and not be the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dThe reason to be consistent is that you experience compount effect. Small changes overtime can significantly change things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at yourself from 5 years ago. Any habit that was small would have been really small for the first 2 years. then suddently it started growing significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that at first don’t seem significant become significant when you compound them over a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are cleaning your room, planning the day, meditating, etc. You are on the path! Their is light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;staying-on-the-path&quot;&gt;Staying on the Path&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sacrifice&quot;&gt;Sacrifice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to give up who you are to be who you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The boy shall die and the man will live.  &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dark-side&quot;&gt;The Dark Side&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark side is the easy path. It’s a path devoid of responsibility. Blame, complain and general disinterest is forms of the dark side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;humility&quot;&gt;Humility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is tempted to go to the dark side when he/she is not humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if not one overestimated himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should try fixing problems around him starting from the smallest. Smallest problems like making your bed make a man humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;taking-on-the-burden&quot;&gt;Taking on the burden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between being handed something and taking it on voluntarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should take on the burden voluntarily because what is neglected is rushes in when things go bad. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;default-aggresive&quot;&gt;Default Aggresive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be the one who does things. Who solves the problems. Not the one who just reacts to the the situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-you-on-the-path&quot;&gt;Are you on the path?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fast, lift, sprint, stretch, and meditate.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Build, sell, write, create, invest, and own.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Read, reflect, love, seek truth, and ignore society.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Make these habits. Say no to everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Avoid debt, jail, addiction, disgrace, shortcuts, and media.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Relax. Victory is assured. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know if you are on the path?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foundations are build and maintained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are optimally between order and chaos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are default aggressive. You fix problems before they occur.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can choose the short term pleasure, but you choose not to. in favor of long term.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You always tell the truth. And are not afraid of the consiquences/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your productivity level is high.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are always calm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Jordan Peterson &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Naval Ravikant &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Photo by Jake Blucker on Unsplash</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/path.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/path.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>