<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-30T21:23:18-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush</title><subtitle>Random Thoughts</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sapiens Book Summary</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/sapiens/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sapiens Book Summary" /><published>2020-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/sapiens</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/sapiens/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vialogue.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/sapiens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot; width: 250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-this-summary&quot;&gt;Why this summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book took around two months to complete. I am a slow reader. I am trying to write this as a way to better process what I understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summary may spoil your reading experience if you have not read the book yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order of points is random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-book&quot;&gt;The book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is a brief history. It transitions fast and beautifully from one topic to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also presents arguments and counter-arguments in a way that tries to explain the whole thing from maximum points of view. This kind of writing and thinking is something I aspire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons&quot;&gt;Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cousins&quot;&gt;Cousins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We had a lot of cousin humans. Once upon a time, Around &lt;strong&gt;six species of humans&lt;/strong&gt; roamed the earth at the once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are not unique&lt;/strong&gt;. 3 billion years ago our universe was born. It will stay for billions. We are not even the human species that has survived the longest (as of yet).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are countless species. We are just specie that got lucky thanks to our intellect and imagined realities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;imagined-realities&quot;&gt;Imagined Realities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History is random&lt;/strong&gt;. There are cause and effect to certain events but there is no reason why history could not have turned in some other way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Religion is a recent thing. (10,000 years ago).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The way we interact and work together with stranger and form groups larger than 150 is by imaging things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Societal constructs&lt;/strong&gt; like nation, company, ethics, etc are imagined realities shared by billions. It’s so strong that we act according to them in the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no justice in history&lt;/strong&gt;. Even a human right is an imagined construct. There is nothing in biology that suggest it to be a truth. These constructs do help keep people sane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;destroyer-of-species&quot;&gt;Destroyer of Species&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huntergathers were healthier&lt;/strong&gt; than us but they did not live for that long.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no going back once the Agriculture Revolution started. Why would someone want to go back to hunting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are &lt;strong&gt;Thanos&lt;/strong&gt; for other species. Our species has captured and killed and effected almost all animals on earth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We don’t look at animals with the same view as we look at other humans. We abolished human slavery but are okay with animal slavery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;capitalism&quot;&gt;Capitalism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science is largely a product of Capitalism and politics&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capitalism allowed us to progress fast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capitalist if not checked can do anything for money&lt;/strong&gt;. Slave trading companies were listed in the London Stock Exchange. This seems kind of similar to current privacy breaching companies or how we farm animals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stock investor would not care what happens in the company. he is just interacted in making a return.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government and legal checks are necessary to keep Capitalists in check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;accepting-ignorance&quot;&gt;Accepting Ignorance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;scientific revolution was a result of Europeans accepting that they are ignorant&lt;/strong&gt;. That they don’t know things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reason the Scientific revolution took place in Europe instead of India or China (even if Asia controlled 80% of world GDP) is because of social constructs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asians did not accept their ignorance&lt;/strong&gt; and did not venture out to find answers to things they did not know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New material discovered increase progress rapidly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unification&quot;&gt;Unification&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The 3 things that brought humankind together; &lt;strong&gt;Empired, Religion, Money&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money crossed lines which religion could not&lt;/strong&gt;. Everybody loves money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There have been many types of money and does not include just a coin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are all influenced by European culture. No country has an original culture. It’s a mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;math&quot;&gt;Math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maths allowed us to predict the future&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time and timetable tracking is recent. Though it is very efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buddhism&quot;&gt;Buddhism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Western liberals mix their view with the Buddhist view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Buddhist view is not that the happiness in individual and it must be protected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The main part is the &lt;strong&gt;internal states are fleeting&lt;/strong&gt; and they change every moment. &lt;strong&gt;There is no point in chasing after it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;credit&quot;&gt;Credit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Banks and the whole financial system are built on credit&lt;/strong&gt;. They provide more money than they have hoped for a future return. This is a large contributor to human progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lone-individual&quot;&gt;Lone Individual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual needs are now satisfied by state&lt;/strong&gt; and organizations instead of family and community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want money, you can take a loan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you want an education you go to school.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you are unemployed there are un-employment schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you are old, there are retirement schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transendance&quot;&gt;Transendance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans have &lt;strong&gt;transcended genetic boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We learn faster and adapt quicker. Unlike other animals whose genes dictate what they do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have created medicines and technologies that far exceed and extend our natural limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;communication&quot;&gt;Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A band of good communication sapiens of 500 could beat Neanderthals with a pack of 5 times more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gossip is natural to us&lt;/strong&gt;. Gossip conveys important information like who to avoid, what to do, what not to do, etc which helps us be safe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;peace-in-our-time&quot;&gt;Peace in our time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humans have been safer than ever&lt;/strong&gt;. And we seem to be moving towards more peace.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compared to history, the decolonization of colonies has been relatively peaceful. &lt;strong&gt;Everyone seems to be tired of war&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nature&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biology is always changing&lt;/strong&gt;. It is never constant or fixed. If you go by this line of thinking, more than human 2 genders are possible and biology won’t have any problem with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://vialogue.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/sapiens.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://vialogue.files.wordpress.com/2017/04/sapiens.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Developer Productivity</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/dev_productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developer Productivity" /><published>2020-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/developer-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/dev_productivity/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dev_productivity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@ymoran?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;MORAN&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/developer?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are things that affect improves developer productivity significantly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hardware&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Fast Computer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bigger Display&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple Monitors
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can preview the application on one screen and keep the IDE or DB open on the next.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;software&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Good IDE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plugins to automate things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A modern programming language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dev-himself&quot;&gt;Dev Himself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Typing without looking at the keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating tiny scripts (.bat/.sh) to automate repeated actions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding the requirement properly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prototyping the User Interface to avoid confusion. Paper prototyping is enough for many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thinking and having the thoughts organized before writing the code instead of thinking while coding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knowing if the algorithm needed is common that an open-source solution is readily available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Googling the right thing while debugging.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not over-engineering. Example: Don’t use microservices if your application isn’t big. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keeping code clean&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Single tasking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zzMLg3Ys5vI&amp;amp;t=499s&quot;&gt;The Problem With Microservices&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/dev_productivity.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/dev_productivity.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How I learned basics of programming.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/learn_programming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I learned basics of programming." /><published>2020-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/how-i-learned-programming</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/learn_programming/">&lt;p&gt;The following is a beginner-focused essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a dumb programmer for the most part. I knew syntax and understood solutions to problems but could not solve them myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed of my progress was slow because there was no need for me to code well. My academic assignments were relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;syntax&quot;&gt;Syntax&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first programming language (C), I watched YouTube while writing all syntaxes by hand. The video taught me the importance of indentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;algorithm-and-competitions&quot;&gt;Algorithm and Competitions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to prepare for a job interview and coding competitions. So I started practising on HackerRank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;book-think-like-a-programmer&quot;&gt;Book: Think Like A Programmer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew syntax pretty well but could not write code myself. I always needed a tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across a YouTube series and book of the same name:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLKQ5LYb497AZIZe9dBWy8GwLluVaMQVj0&quot;&gt;Think Like A Programmer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched all the videos, read books and tried applying them. I was not good initially thought I had learned some ways to estimate what end program would look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thoughts were getting structured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;book-automate-the-boring-stuff-with-python&quot;&gt;Book: Automate the Boring Stuff with Python&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew beginner level Java. I wanted to automate some parts of my computer but found it very difficult to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had learned the syntax of Ruby. Ruby was huge at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have hesitated to learn Python. I did not want to revisit the same things with different syntax. But the Automate The Boring Stuff book was compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started reading the book and would often read and try out cheatsheets. I even had cheat sheets printed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python reduced the complexity of development. I was able to focus less on syntax and more on what the code does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;book-cracking-the-coding-interview&quot;&gt;Book: Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was getting better. This book improved it further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not solve all the problems. I had read through the theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;practicing&quot;&gt;Practicing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I build all my academic projects myself without asking for help. That helped me a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was trying to build things for myself. Like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a python script that would automatically empty desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A python selenium script that would log in to Facebook and wish Happy Birthday to people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A script to download Anime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took around four years. I wasted the first three years and got focused on the last one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The following is a beginner-focused essay.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Research</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research" /><published>2020-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/research</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/research/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/research.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plateau-of-progress&quot;&gt;Plateau of progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many fields where the reward of discovering new things are a long time before there is implementation. (Like pure maths, theoretical physics, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the colonial era, Europeans gained a significant advantage over other civilizations. One reason was their willingness to accept things that they don’t know and to find ways to understand the world better. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of scientific progress was as important as anything political.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though today we live in an era were a lot of scientific progress is made. The increase is because a large number of people are working on the problem. Even if the problems they are trying to solve are trivial (like social media).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of effort required to research in the pre-colonial and colonial era was far greater. This should increase productivity and it does in some sense. But it has lead to a reduction of effort on the human part and therefore the result is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research gets an entitlement. People think it is hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s likely how people define it. You just have to work at something. And if you work on it you may discover things that you don’t even know are new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason research gets a bad entitlement of because of ready-made solutions and the things that are already been discovered/made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We miss the point that all the polished discoveries we see today had humble beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would argue that if the discovery you made or a solution you made even is it already exist and you didn’t know about it is still an act of research. You may even find some improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act of research does not have to be big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-made-solutions---globalisation&quot;&gt;Ready-made solutions - Globalisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Globalisation has allowed us to take fruits of someone else’s research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 2020, China and the USA dominate technology. We Indians (and many from other countries) are more of a witness to this domination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also different issues to solve. The social issues in India and different than those in developed nations. And therefore globalisation has a faster positive impact compared to research activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sapiens by Yuval Harari &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/research.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/research.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hurrying does not help.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/hurrying/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hurrying does not help." /><published>2020-12-17T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/hurrying</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/hurrying/">&lt;p&gt;Hurring is similar to stock market investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you rush, you make a profit some times and you losses some times. In the end, you are in the same place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching YouTube videos at 2x speed won’t help. Especially if it is a field you are not familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you write super fast, you’ll not be able to understand what you wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read too fast, you won’t have enough comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you push yourself to work, you’ll burn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a point before you rush called the minimum effective dose (MED) &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go beyond MED the speed will fast but progress will be slow.
If you go below MED the speed will be slow and progress will be slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are the MED, your speed will be optimum and progress will be optimum. The tricky thing is MED for any task changes in moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No rush. No pause. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;4 Hour Body &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Tim Ferriss &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hurring is similar to stock market investing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Software Engineers Should Enter Other Fields.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/engineer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Software Engineers Should Enter Other Fields." /><published>2020-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/engineers-other-field</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/engineer/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;software-engineers&quot;&gt;Software Engineers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Engineers solve problems by building solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We keep iterating on the solutions, make it better and eventually replace the solution with something completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have efficient processes for managing projects and handling productivity. Even if a deadline is near, the solution is shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software developers ability to get so much done is because of the nature of software and focus on efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-problem-to-solve&quot;&gt;What problem to solve&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A non-technical person does not know the problem that can be solved using technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A technical person does not know what problems to solve. The result is that time is solved solving problems on trivial issues like social media instead of more important fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-other-fields-can-benefit&quot;&gt;How other fields can benefit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some fields have slow progress rate. There is a long delay in medical research getting to production (Approx 20 year &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). There hasn’t been much innovation in the field even in engineering fields like Civil engineer or biotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason is likely because these fields require physical products and take longer to build and test. A technology solution can help speed up some of their processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graphics Modelling and Simulations to speed to testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Organization and Retrieval Systems to make sure the right information is accessed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deep Learning Models to help search for replacing overdependence of specialized hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automation of manual tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to ensure these fields get benefits of innovations in computer technology is to work closely with experts in the field or to get into it ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/engineer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;sub&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@nci?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;National Cancer Institute&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/cells?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Tim Ferriss - 4 Hour Body &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Software Engineers</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/engineer.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/engineer.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Eventually Perfect Feature</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/eventually_perfect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eventually Perfect Feature" /><published>2020-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/eventually-perfect</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/eventually_perfect/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/eventually_perfect.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@hostreviews?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Stephen Phillips - Hostreviews.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/gmail?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two approaches to building a new feature to existing software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;approach-1-ship-with-all-sub-features-on-the-first-release&quot;&gt;Approach 1: Ship with all sub-features on the first release&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach works well when the feature is small or needs to be secret to gain a competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;approach-2-ship-with-minimum-sub-features-then-iterate&quot;&gt;Approach 2: Ship with minimum sub-features. Then iterate.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach works better because most software features never get used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you are a FANG company or even if you are, you should save your resources to focus on the area that matters most. Which you only understand after the feature is in the wild for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the feature is secret, allowing beta of minimum required feature is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/eventually_perfect.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/eventually_perfect.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Write Tests after Cleaning Code.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/writing_test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Write Tests after Cleaning Code." /><published>2020-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/test-coverage-after-cleaning-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/writing_test/">&lt;p&gt;Quality of code determines the quality of the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An unclean code will lead to an unclean test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the tests will be as hard to understand and modify as the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one decides to improve code quality, then all of the tests to be refactored too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the workload will be about thrice more work than it needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better alternative is to write code, clean it, and write tests.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Quality of code determines the quality of the test.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Plan quickly. Move fast. Break things.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/move/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plan quickly. Move fast. Break things." /><published>2020-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/move</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/move/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/move.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@chaseelliottclark?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Chase Clark&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/move?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made this mistake a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent too much time planning and too much time deciding the perfect strategy which often took months to come up and then either never implemented it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I found out that the hard way was much shorter and would often take me just a few hours or at max a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an analogy in programming which says that a programmer will spend six hours automating something that takes six minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If something is repeated so every frequently then the six minutes saving in time is justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for most things, it is better to move on fast and break things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/move.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/move.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Age is not a perfect measure of experience</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/age/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Age is not a perfect measure of experience" /><published>2020-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/age</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/age/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/age.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@paige_cody?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Paige Cody&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/kids-piano?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kids-learn-too&quot;&gt;Kids learn too&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some kids learn hard skills like playing the piano at a very young age. They often get labelled as a child prodigy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This categorization assumes that the child is born with talents and ignores the fact that he/she has to spend years learning the skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most child piano prodigies start at age 4, by the time they are age 10  they already have 6 years of Piano experience. No doubt they have skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;people-who-learn-faster&quot;&gt;People who learn faster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, some people put in more effort to learn to skills properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They either grasp the ideas or maybe had better learning resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, they learned skill with no formal learning/training would take years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;argument&quot;&gt;Argument&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most corporate environments favour “years of experience spent at work” at a primary factor for determining salary and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ignores the ability of the person to get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/age.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/age.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>