<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-24T12:31:57-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush</title><subtitle>Random Thoughts</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How to recover from injuries faster</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-think/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to recover from injuries faster" /><published>2021-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/injury-recovery</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-think/">&lt;p&gt;To recover from physical injuries faster like tightness and muscle soreness, your blood should be flowing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are someways to do it and all of them are important to do and lead to similar level of benifits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;massage&quot;&gt;Massage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not have to have a lot of pressure. It can be as soft as possible. Even little bit will help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cannot directly massage the area in pain, massage the area around it. This will atleast let blood flow near the effected area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cold-exposure&quot;&gt;Cold Exposure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take cold showers. Atleast 90 seconds. And don’t be afraid of the cold and start taking heavy breaths. Be calm, take deep breaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your’s body will start pumping blood faster to keep your body warm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do atleast 30 seconds on the area that is directly effected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;move-and-exercise&quot;&gt;Move and Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problems multiply when you don’t move the part. Your body does not fully know how to recover a part until you show it how you use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So move as much as you can. It’s okay if you can only do quater motion. Do it before it starts paining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if you cannot move the specific body part because it is too painful. Move other parts, keep blood flowing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rest-enough-but-not-too-much&quot;&gt;Rest Enough but not too much.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest enough. You want to increase the probability that you’ll work the next day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To recover from physical injuries faster like tightness and muscle soreness, your blood should be flowing well.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ethical Capitalism Is A Game Everyone Needs To Win At</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/ethical-capitalism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ethical Capitalism Is A Game Everyone Needs To Win At" /><published>2021-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/ethical-capitalism</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/ethical-capitalism/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ethical-capitalism.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@billow926?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;billow926&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/market?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capitalism-is-pure-genius&quot;&gt;Capitalism is Pure Genius&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism involves pushing oneself to help others. That is what capitalists do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They find a problem, solve it, and earn money as a reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In capitalism terms, money is proof that you are adding value to the world. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who don’t own a business, help others by becoming an employee, thus adding value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path-to-high-impact-through-capitalism&quot;&gt;The Path To High Impact through Capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is efficient to adapt ourselves to the world than to do the opposite. Money is an important form of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have the impact of any form and at any level, you are going to need money. The best way to do it is to be a capitalist, add values to people’s lives, and be rewarded in the form of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some sense, you are a capitalist if you are earning i.e you have a job or a business. And you are a really good capitalist if you are earning more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;capitalism--ethics&quot;&gt;Capitalism + Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capitalism is not perfect. If not kept in check, it can turn evil (Example: East India Company). There are ways to earn money without adding value to people’s life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethics is not intrinsic to capitalism. And it probably never be as it is hard to be laid out concretely. A combination of the two leads to more results than one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethics allows you to play long-term games and be trustworthy but unlike money, it helps you earn social trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mix of the two is probably why companies like Apple and Tata Group are so successful and trusted for so long. They provide high value while not compromising on ethics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems better to think in terms of adding value than to think in terms of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Naval Ravikant &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/ethical-capitalism.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/ethical-capitalism.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Path / Ethics</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Path / Ethics" /><published>2021-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/staying-on-the-path</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/path/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;sub style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jakeblucker?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Jake Blucker&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/road?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-path&quot;&gt;The Path&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path is trying to be the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not the best you can be, you create or neglect problems. These problems accumulate and will make you suffer. And it’s not just you who will suffer. It will engulf all the people around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it’s an ethical crime to be weak&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and not be the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consistency&quot;&gt;Consistency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dThe reason to be consistent is that you experience compount effect. Small changes overtime can significantly change things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at yourself from 5 years ago. Any habit that was small would have been really small for the first 2 years. then suddently it started growing significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that at first don’t seem significant become significant when you compound them over a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are cleaning your room, planning the day, meditating, etc. You are on the path! Their is light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;staying-on-the-path&quot;&gt;Staying on the Path&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sacrifice&quot;&gt;Sacrifice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to give up who you are to be who you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The boy shall die and the man will live.  &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dark-side&quot;&gt;The Dark Side&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark side is the easy path. It’s a path devoid of responsibility. Blame, complain and general disinterest is forms of the dark side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;humility&quot;&gt;Humility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is tempted to go to the dark side when he/she is not humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if not one overestimated himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should try fixing problems around him starting from the smallest. Smallest problems like making your bed make a man humble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;taking-on-the-burden&quot;&gt;Taking on the burden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between being handed something and taking it on voluntarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should take on the burden voluntarily because what is neglected is rushes in when things go bad. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;default-aggresive&quot;&gt;Default Aggresive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be the one who does things. Who solves the problems. Not the one who just reacts to the the situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-you-on-the-path&quot;&gt;Are you on the path?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fast, lift, sprint, stretch, and meditate.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Build, sell, write, create, invest, and own.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Read, reflect, love, seek truth, and ignore society.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Make these habits. Say no to everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Avoid debt, jail, addiction, disgrace, shortcuts, and media.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Relax. Victory is assured. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know if you are on the path?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foundations are build and maintained&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are optimally between order and chaos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are default aggressive. You fix problems before they occur.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can choose the short term pleasure, but you choose not to. in favor of long term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Jordan Peterson &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Game of Thrones &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Naval Ravikant &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Photo by Jake Blucker on Unsplash</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/path.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/path.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You need time to think</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-think/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You need time to think" /><published>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/think</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-think/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;knowledge-vs-thinking&quot;&gt;Knowledge vs Thinking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between acquiring knowledge and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acquiring Knowlege would including activities like attending lectures, reading books and googling to find solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking would involve looking into yourself for the answers and thinking from the first principles to validate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;balancing-knowledge-and-thinking&quot;&gt;Balancing Knowledge and Thinking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-thinking-is-important&quot;&gt;Why thinking is important&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;youll-be-too-caught-up-in-the-specifics&quot;&gt;You’ll be too caught up in the specifics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By acquiring knowledge one can only remember “terms” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but they won’t know how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our gadgets are such that they remove any need for thinking. We can find all information in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem this leads to is that we always search for a ready-made answer instead of thinking about ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen this during development a lot where some developers would search open-source solutions or paid solution when in reality creating solution was much easier to just code yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens because of not thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be the best at something, you can get half the way by copying/absorbing other people’s methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But soon you’ll come to a point where YouTube videos, random advice and even books won’t help as much. You have to chart your own course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rational-opinions&quot;&gt;Rational Opinions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals search for truth. Groups search for consensus. Of course, you cannot deny logical facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;losing-what-you-dont-use&quot;&gt;Losing What You Don’t Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you don’t use you lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note Taking is also problematic. One should only write what they think about a topic if something is new and carefully thought through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learning-happens-when-you-compare-and-contrast&quot;&gt;Learning happens when you compare and contrast.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;boredom-spark-of-creativity&quot;&gt;Boredom: Spark of Creativity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We resist boredom. Boredom is important as it sparks creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking-is-powerful&quot;&gt;Thinking is powerful&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your problems get solved when you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear thinking allows you to explain easily&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can think and articulate, you are powerful. You can influence people. People give you money. Ask for your advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-you-know-is-not-true&quot;&gt;What you know is not true.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In statistics, there is a thing called hypothesis testing. The goal of it is not to accept a hypothesis. To goal is to perform tests to reject the hypothesis. The hypothesis is never “accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know that you understand a topic well enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You say it in your own words.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t overexplain. You need limited set of words to convey the same information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can explain the topic from several different points of views with different examples.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can simplify the topic enough so that everyone understands it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If someone is struggling with a particular aspect of topic and they don’t know what, you can guess what might they be struggling with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Elon Musk on MBAs &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Knowledge vs Thinking There is a difference between acquiring knowledge and thinking.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">More on Facade Companies</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/more_facade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More on Facade Companies" /><published>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/more_facade</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/more_facade/">&lt;p&gt;I have started noticing trends after reading Sapiens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-paper-companies&quot;&gt;On Paper Companies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am realized a weird Ponzi Scheme recently. One that is totally legit. That is valuation of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies don’t actually make profit. And if we look at their market valuations, it will be huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like whatsapp, it was a free product for the most part but it’s valuation was 16 billion when it was sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The likely reason for their customer base was because they offered free product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing such a model would cause people to flee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s similar to WeWork a startup that got a lot of funding but got bankrupt. It never had a good business model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;innovating-is-hard&quot;&gt;Innovating is hard.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effect of globalization, internet and software have been such that distribution has become cheap and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has probably never been easier to start a company and reach millions of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such a scenario, finding new profitable business ideas are hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People need work. They need busineeses to provide for their family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we assume really profitable top teir business they must be a 50% of the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So atleast these facade companies provide people salaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-is-hard-to-be-profitable&quot;&gt;It is hard to be profitable.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many facade companies do bring in innovation. Since billions of dollars are put into the facade company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times ever founders and VCs do not know if the company is facade.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have started noticing trends after reading Sapiens.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Influence of Giant Tech Companies</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/fang/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Influence of Giant Tech Companies" /><published>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/influence-of-faang</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/fang/">&lt;p&gt;A companies valuations can be seen as hour influential the company is. As of Jan 2021, FAANG companies are the most influential companies with a very high market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These companies are hailed by software engineers and the competition to get is tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the below details I am excluding Netflix as it not as big as the other 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of the post is not to say that FAANG is good or bad. This post initially started as analysis but the post was getting too large so to keep things short analysis is replaced by examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some examples of how much influence FAANG influence us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attention&quot;&gt;Attention&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-1&quot;&gt;Example 1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of products are ad models. If the amount of time a person spends on the product is high, more ad revenue can come in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the user’s attention has now shifted from physical to digital, grabbing the user’s attention in online space is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;example-2-usage-time&quot;&gt;Example 2: Usage Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people spent 90% of their time on the application created by top companies like FAANG and less than 10% on apps built by smaller companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about how much time you spent on services provided by FANG companies including search engine, video, browser, social media and messaging. Plus they make their products addictive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend about 6-9 hours each day on one of their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-3-apple-vs-facebook&quot;&gt;Example 3: Apple vs Facebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iOS 14.5 is going includes a feature that lets users allow permission to apps to track them. Facebook spread an ad campaign and lawsuit against Apple saying that it will be bad for small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is estimated that Facebook could lose up to 10 billion dollars in revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of FAANG services are data-driven. They require a huge amount of data. Though Apple’s current stance seems to be based on protecting user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data is collected from almost every service and especially squeezed from the free ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even cloud computing services collect a huge amount of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-3&quot;&gt;Example 3:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-4&quot;&gt;Example 4:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;money-and-small-businesses&quot;&gt;Money and Small Businesses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most FAANG companies benefit from being middlemen between 2 parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They earn data and improve their services on the user side, they use the improved service to provide better advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-5&quot;&gt;Example 5:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of every dollar, a VC invests into a startup, 40 cents goes to Facebook, Amazon and Google. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-6&quot;&gt;Example 6:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus every small company needs to be careful of the moves made by FAANG as if a FAANG decides to enter the same market as a small business, the odds are low that the small business will succeed. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;power&quot;&gt;Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-7-aws-outage&quot;&gt;Example 7: AWS Outage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Web Services, the most profitable of Amazon’s companies, control nearly half of Global Cloud Infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A few years ago, a single code bug caused a lot of known websites to crash. Websites like Netflix, Tinder, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-8-facebook-user-research&quot;&gt;Example 8: Facebook User “Research”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook has been known to perform user testing on people without their consent. A test was performed to determine whether&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-9-ban-on-trump-and-parler&quot;&gt;Example 9: Ban on Trump and Parler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook and Google have been known to influence attention and start mass movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook and Twitter removed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Chamath Palihapitiya &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Gary Vaynerchuck on Planet of the Apps. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A companies valuations can be seen as hour influential the company is. As of Jan 2021, FAANG companies are the most influential companies with a very high market cap.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Employee Ethics</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/employee-ethics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Employee Ethics" /><published>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/employee-ethics</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/employee-ethics/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/employee-ethics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@shridhar?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Shridhar Gupta&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/employee?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous posts, I discussed the &lt;a href=&quot;/why_ethics/&quot;&gt;reasons to be ethical&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/business-ethics/&quot;&gt;how it related to businesses&lt;/a&gt;. For employees, ethics can be summarised with the Principal-Agent Problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;principal-agent-problem-&quot;&gt;Principal-Agent Problem &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Principal wants agents to act like in the best interest of the agent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The agent who does act like Principal get rewarded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organization-structure&quot;&gt;Organization Structure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organization need to foster an environment for employees to be more ethical. Though there are some things the sole hand of employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ethics&quot;&gt;The Ethics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not accepting bribes and not stealing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not engaging in office politics and maintaining good company culture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focusing on efficiency and conflict resolution.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This means working together to find a solution.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take on accountability and responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting work done&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t feel like part of the company, move on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Naval Ravikant &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/employee-ethics.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Source Software (OSS)</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/open-source/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Source Software (OSS)" /><published>2021-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/open-source</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/open-source/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/open-source.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@richygreat?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Richy Great&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/github?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I think about open source, the more confusing things get. In some sense, Open Source projects are pretty similar to Non-Profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;impact-of-oss&quot;&gt;Impact of OSS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall impact of OSS has been high. If there was no OSS, we would either have to buy everything or build everything from scratch every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the libraries I use daily are open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;types&quot;&gt;Types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most OSS are libraries for developers to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some exceptions are Signal, VLC and Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-companies-make-their-project-open-source&quot;&gt;Why companies make their project open source?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recognition&quot;&gt;Recognition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies, especially smaller ones, gain a lot of recognition by being developing open-source software. An example of this is BaseCamp which built Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;market-capture&quot;&gt;Market Capture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprises and even smaller companies prefer free open source software over the paid ones if it gets their work done faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hiring&quot;&gt;Hiring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open-source software help companies find and recruit good talent. Though it is likely not the main reason for making open-source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;revenue&quot;&gt;Revenue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most companies don’t depend on their open-source software for profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The once which do usually rely on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide additional proprietary features at Premium. Like: Cloud Support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problems-with-open-source&quot;&gt;Problems with open source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all OS projects are equal. Some projects are better maintained than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sustainability&quot;&gt;Sustainability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revenue does not seem sustainable. The companies which only focus on open source products  either require a lot of Donation (like Ubuntu) or have to pivot heavily to be sustainable (like RedHat recently)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deception-and-priorities&quot;&gt;Deception and Priorities&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSS often doesn’t openly admit to having bugs. If a developer knows of bugs in the OSS they can choose not to use the product. But usually, developers get to realize the bugs themself after a few months of using the products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critical bugs may be ignored as open-source projects have their own set of priorities. Sometimes the prioritize the number of issues fixed over addressing critical once. There is low/no accountability &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; since it is free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paid products provide priority support for paid customers, thus resolving issues faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When choosing an open-source project, check GitHub issues first. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, open-source projects do get abandoned which does not happen with paid products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L3iqmyoogfA&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=21&quot;&gt;Flutter EXPOSED: Extreme JANKY animations. “A nightmare framework”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/open-source.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/open-source.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Business Ethics</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/business-ethics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Business Ethics" /><published>2021-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/business-ethics</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/business-ethics/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/business-ethics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@charles_forerunner?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Charles Forerunner&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/business?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/why_ethics/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I discussed the reasons to be ethical. In short, ethics provides leverage. This post addresses points specific to businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;competition-and-revenues&quot;&gt;Competition and Revenues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most profitable companies create a monopoly. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: Google, Facebook, Amazon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monopolies are bad for innovation long term. Competition is good for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often publically traded companies listening to shareholders focus on short term gains while neglecting ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: Slave Trading Companies during the Colonial Era. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recent Example:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Facebook is known for copying features from smaller competitors then purchasing them&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Amazon is known for bankrupting competitors by:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Investing in companies then launching their copy of cheaper product under Amazon brand &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Forcing business to be sold to Amazon by selling the same product at a massive loss and waiting for a competitor to go bankrupt before restoring price. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some companies choose to stay private, avoiding being influenced by shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Example: SpaceX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your business is no longer needed, pivot and move to something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customer&quot;&gt;Customer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal as a company is to help your customers. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you cheat, you’ll create a bad word of mouth about your brand. Word of mouth is the most powerful marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be the kind of business whose customer wants you to succeed. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protect customer data by providing 100% encryption. Even you should not be able to read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;employee&quot;&gt;Employee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more you take care of your employees. The more employees take care of you. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies should run on ideas, not hierarchy. You have to let the best ideas win. Which means that people at Leadership position should listen to their employees and sort out solutions. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Peter Thiel &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sapiens by Yuval Noah Harari &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pBffKzWECUQ&quot;&gt;The Amazon monopoly and the problem with Jeff Bezos’ business model&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Mark Cuban &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Simon Sinek &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/business-ethics.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/business-ethics.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Piano</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/piano/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Piano" /><published>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/learning-piano</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/piano/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/piano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;sub style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@dolodol?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Dolo Iglesias&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/piano?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; style=&quot;user-select: auto;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The piano is the most important thing I have learned in a long time. I am still learning and far from being good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some sense, it is just a speaker which is manual and more satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some thinking I learned while playing the Piano:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little things add up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Break the problem into chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress is not linear. Or at least it does not seem linear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;material-beats-method&quot;&gt;Material Beats Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a keyboard since childhood though I never learned it. Random tutorials did not seem to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changed was purchasing SimplyPiano and free time (lockdown).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;upfront-work&quot;&gt;Upfront work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many try taking the shortcut of avoiding sheet music and go directly to the song. It is much easier to get started with Sheet Music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning sheet music seems to be a boon. I did not memorize most of my songs until Fur-Elise. I can play almost all Begineer level songs from SimplyPiano directly from the sheet music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-of-a-whole&quot;&gt;Part of A Whole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that a lot of times I was skipping parts of the practice. Skipping chords, going through the lessons too fast, Not practising enough before the next lesson. Not learning left hand properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though all of these things were small in the beginning they started to slow me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;isolation&quot;&gt;Isolation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A specific section of pieces can be practised in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;playing-regularly&quot;&gt;Playing regularly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I was playing about thrice a week for 15 minutes each. ROI of early progress high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later practising every day for 15 minutes became a hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concentration-and-being-calm&quot;&gt;Concentration and Being Calm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes playing the Piano requires concentration like reading a good book. Often time my brain would be on full throttle flow mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calm&quot;&gt;Calm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being calm makes it hard to concentrate. 
If I am not calm it will be hard for me to concentrate and I will not only make mistakes but I will not know why I am sucking at this piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;being-gentle&quot;&gt;Being gentle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banging your fingers on the piano is a sure way to suffer. I made this mistake a lot earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, my hands were stiff. Over the months they have got lighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;joy-of-playing-sheet-music&quot;&gt;Joy of playing sheet music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure how many others learned Piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;searching-for-information&quot;&gt;Searching for Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost always after playing for a while, I’ll have questions. I would search and find answers on YouTube. The reason was that SimplyPiano did not include a lot of details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some things I had trouble with where YouTube helped:
Playing with a left hand
Hand Coordination
D Position
Proper Posture
Hand Injury&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gearing-up&quot;&gt;Gearing up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, I kept my keyboard over a pillow. A YouTube video suggested getting a proper stand so I got one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stand instantly improved my playing by 30%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later I got sustain pedal while practising Fur-Elise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;humility&quot;&gt;Humility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piano taught me to be patient and humble. Often watching kids on YouTube play better than me makes me cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often if I suck as a new lesson, I’ll get it after 15 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Piano is a rabbit hole. I have seen YouTuber learning after 10-12 year. I don’t wish to be only associated with a piano. So after SimplyPiano. I’ll stop. I’ll try to focus on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably take up something else. I hope to find something as step by step as SimplyPiano.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Photo by Dolo Iglesias on Unsplash</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/piano.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/piano.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>