<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-22T11:14:05-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush Choubey</title><subtitle>Full Stack Developer - Cloud/Microservices</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What separates BDD from TDD, VDIs, etc.</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/bdd-vs-tdd" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What separates BDD from TDD, VDIs, etc." /><published>2023-03-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-what-should-go-into-bdd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/bdd-vs-tdd"><![CDATA[<p>We are often confused about what constitutes BDD.</p>

<p>This makes us add un-necessarily details to BDD spec file.</p>

<p>Here’s how one should think about this</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Stop thinking about how the product would look or feel. And focus on the customer’s interaction with the product.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Does your product behaviors actually solve the customer’s problem.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If yes, find the best way to implement and represent those behaviours. This means UI design in wireframes and UI functionality covered by UI TDD and backend implementation covered by BackendTDD are not relevant here.</p>

<p>Therefore, <strong>BDD drives your UI/UX and TDD</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vRONWHyF6MDLxwYnnUeZHvg9jPjWjKoxTOfaJdu_roqlYPvS2LA3FLhGp-h2xM2iUAF3I76yylz4pFd/pub?w=1232&amp;h=875" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="example">Example</h2>

<p>You believe the customer would often forget his/her password. So, how should you solve this problem.
Doing some brainstorming you come up with an example map.</p>

<p>User comes and logges in. He leaves the tab and comes back. He is shown an prompt to enter his 4 digit pin.</p>

<p>This leads to another example where he sets his 4 digit ping.</p>

<p>When user selects a password, he is allowed to set a shorter 4 digit pin.</p>

<p>Now you convert this into Gherkin.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Given a user has logged in
When they leave the tab untouched for 10 minutes
Then they should be prompted to enter their 4 digit pin.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Given user is prompted 4 digit pin
When pin is valid
Then user’s session should resume</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Given user is prompted to enter 4 digit pin
When pin in invalid for 4 times
Then user should be logged out</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Now for each of the steps, you can decide the best wireframe, frontend, and backend implementation strategies.</p>

<p>Note: The above gherkins don’t define how something should look. They just define behavior that would solve the user’s problem.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="bdd" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[BDD Deals with Solving Customer's Problems. It does not consider UI or any other implementation details. Implementation details are part of UI Wireframing, TDD and other activities.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vRONWHyF6MDLxwYnnUeZHvg9jPjWjKoxTOfaJdu_roqlYPvS2LA3FLhGp-h2xM2iUAF3I76yylz4pFd/pub?w=1232&amp;amp;h=875" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vRONWHyF6MDLxwYnnUeZHvg9jPjWjKoxTOfaJdu_roqlYPvS2LA3FLhGp-h2xM2iUAF3I76yylz4pFd/pub?w=1232&amp;amp;h=875" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Implementing an OAuth Server Manually</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/implementing-oauth" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Implementing an OAuth Server Manually" /><published>2023-03-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-implementing-oauth-server</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/implementing-oauth"><![CDATA[<p>This blogpost will cover what OAuth is and how I went about implementing OAuth. It does not include theorotical details. It includes practical questions that lead me to the implementation.</p>

<p>When you read a question, you can search for it yourself. I have provided all the resources that I used along the way below too.</p>

<p>I’ll explain OAuth in layman’s terms in the beginning and then go on to explain it in more technical terms.</p>

<p>OAuth is easier to implement than developers think. There are a lot of jargons involved. But you’ll find at its core it’s very easy and cost-effective.</p>

<h1 id="what-is-oauth-and-where-it-is-used">What is OAuth? And where it is used?</h1>

<p>OAuth is a protocol for allowing access to a user’s data to a third party app.</p>

<p>OAuth is not login. OAuth expects the user is logged in and has allowed the access.</p>

<p>You may have seen screen pages like these where you allow one application to access data from your Google account. This is done via OAuth.</p>

<p><img src="/images/implementing-oauth.png" alt="image.png" /></p>

<p>The above image is from redirecting to “authorize“ url.</p>

<h1 id="how-is-oauth-different-from-login-and-how-does-it-work">How is OAuth different from Login? And how does it work</h1>

<p>A normal login just requires username and password.</p>

<p>OAuth is a step that happens after login. If the user is not logged in OAuth step won’t happen.</p>

<p>For example, suppose you create an app called “Chain Mailer“ and you want access to the user’s Gmail data.</p>

<p>You initiate the OAuth flow, this means you redirect the user to Gmail with some special parameters. If the user is not logged in, he is asked to log in into Gmail but Gmail itself. Our “Chain Mailer” app has no control over what Gmail does or what the user does. We have just redirected to Gmail.</p>

<p>If the user logs in they’ll see the permissions page. And if they accept, the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3-Legged OAuth flow</code> would happen between Gmail and our Application.</p>

<p>Note: How OAuth Flow only happened after user logged in into the service.</p>

<p>After the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3-Legged OAuth Flow</code> our application would receive a special token called <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Authorization Token</code>. We can use this token while accessing data from Gmail.</p>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Authorization Token</code> would include information that we have the permission to access the data.</p>

<p>Note: From here on things would get technical</p>

<h1 id="how-i-implemented-the-oauth-server-myself">How I implemented the OAuth Server myself</h1>

<p>I’ll split the next parts into:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Learning Phrase</li>
  <li>Coding Phrase</li>
  <li>Nuances</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="learning-phrase">Learning Phrase</h2>

<p>Before implementing OAuth Server, I had done the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3-Legged OAuth Flow</code> with another service myself. So, I knew what the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3-Legged</code> flow is.</p>

<p>This is the first place to start learning about OAuth.</p>

<p>The questions you may ask here is:</p>

<ol>
  <li>What is OAuth?</li>
  <li>What is the three legged OAuth flow.</li>
  <li>How to use the access token. → Using the access token by adding a “Authorization“ Header with value “bearer {authorizationToken}“</li>
</ol>

<p>To implement it, I started reading up on Google, but I found it very challenging. Here’s how I learn’t OAuth and all the security concepts I needed to learn.</p>

<ol>
  <li>I started watching a YouTube playlist this gave me a broad idea about the implementation.</li>
  <li>I asked ChatGPT how to implement an OAuth server.
    <ol>
      <li>ChatGPT gave me useful responses that I was able to ask followup questions to.</li>
      <li>My questions included:
        <ol>
          <li>How to implement an OAuth server.</li>
          <li>What is JWT token?</li>
          <li>How to I validate a JWT Token?</li>
          <li>What is RSA algorithm?
            <ol>
              <li>I further jumped into learning about RSA via YouTube.</li>
              <li>Here’s my post on RSA: <a href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/rsa">RSA Algorithm</a></li>
            </ol>
          </li>
          <li>What’s JWK?</li>
          <li>What’s the difference between JWE and JWS?</li>
          <li>How to define different scopes?</li>
        </ol>
      </li>
    </ol>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>These gave me a basic idea of what to do.</p>

<p>I realized that I just need to create a 3-endpoints and one permissions page.</p>

<p>The Authentication (Login) is already handled. The permissions page comes one later after the Login one.</p>

<h2 id="implementation-phase">Implementation Phase</h2>

<p>With OAuth multiple third party application can register and access our service.</p>

<p>This means I needed to store information about multiple applications.</p>

<p>I created a DB record called OAuthClient where I stored</p>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">clientId</code> - A unique id given to the external application</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">hashedClientSecret</code> (a hashed version of client secret. Similar to how password is hashed and saved.)</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scopes</code> (permissions that are to be provided to application)</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">redirectUri</code> (uri where I would have to redirect).</li>
</ul>

<p>I would generate a clientId, clientSecret and add in scopes and provide these data to third party app.</p>

<hr />

<p>I created another DB record where I store information about the token given. I called it <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">OAuthToken</code>. This would include the following.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">clientId</code></li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">code</code> → this is a temporary code that would be resent from the external app to my oauth server during stage 3 of 3-legged Oauth Flow.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">accessTokenGiven</code> → A boolean value representing if the OAuth token was already granted for the particular code.</li>
</ul>

<p>Using these, I was able to issue OAuth tokens.</p>

<hr />

<p>I also needed JWT token generation.</p>

<p>I used a library to create JWTs and included all the information related to the user application and scope.</p>

<p>For generating JWTs I had to learn what <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">PEM</code> file is.</p>

<hr />

<p>I also had to create a public <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">JWK endpoint</code> which my api gateway would access to validate the token. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">JWK</code> is a standard way of sharing public keys for JWT token.</p>

<p>I also added a record for scopes. Which was something like</p>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scope</code> → unique name of the scope</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">description</code> → unique description of the scope used to show user what to do in the permissions page.</li>
</ul>

<p>Here’s my post on how I choose to define scopes: <a href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/oauth-scopes">Defining Scopes for your OAuth Service</a></p>

<h1 id="nuances">Nuances</h1>

<h2 id="oauth-works-protocol-is-snake-cased">OAuth works protocol is snake cased</h2>

<p>I initially implemented all endpoints as camel case. But it did not work. Then I had to modify it to snake case.</p>

<h2 id="oauth-formats">OAuth formats</h2>

<p>Formats within OAuth protocol are very fixed. Certain endpoints accept and return data in a particular format only and they don’t have randomness.</p>

<p>For example, the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">token</code> endpoint would always be in the following format.</p>

<div class="language-json highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"authorize_token"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"{jwtToken}"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"refrest_token"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"{token}"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="err">...</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>We can’t extend the format by adding our own stuff. But mandatory things would be preserved as it is. For that I had to read up the main OAuth specs a few times.</p>

<h1 id="my-thoughts">My thoughts</h1>

<p>After implementing OAuth server myself, I feel confident about other protocols. Protocols may seem too technical but at their core they are really easy.</p>

<p>Implementing OAuth helped me understand and get better at computer security. And also, helped me step into a much better principle developer role.</p>

<h1 id="resources">Resources</h1>

<p>Jump around these</p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t18YB3xDfXI">An Illustrated Guide to OAuth and OpenID Connect</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=996OiexHze0">OAuth 2.0 and OpenID Connect (in plain English)</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL1Nml43UBm6dOj4UuH-7a9e3wO6eL2SCi">OAuth 2.0 tutorial Playlist </a></p>

<p>ChatGPT</p>

<p><a href="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc6749">Main Spec: The OAuth 2.0 Authorization Framework</a></p>

<h3 id="my-blogposts">My Blogposts</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/oauth-scopes">Defining Scopes for your OAuth Service</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/rsa">RSA Algorithm</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><category term="oauth" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing OAuth server is easier than it looks and it saves money in the long run.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/implementing-oauth.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/implementing-oauth.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Have better variable and method names for technical layer by copying others</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/better-var-name-by-copying/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Have better variable and method names for technical layer by copying others" /><published>2023-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-18T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/better-variable-names-by-copying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/better-var-name-by-copying/"><![CDATA[<p>Writing good variable names clarifies your thinking. But it can be really really hard coming up with your own variable names.</p>

<p>If you are in a domain, you could pick up domain specific names.</p>

<p>For example, a common school software may have Students, Teacher, etc.</p>

<p>This maybe classic domain driven designs.</p>

<p>But in technical layers it can be harder to come up with variable names.</p>

<p>I started working with NodeJs Mongoose framework. I created my Model and was thinking of what method names should I use for common operations like <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">save</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">find</code> . There were multiple <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">find</code> operations and they were getting messy because it was hard to understand what is what.</p>

<p>In javascript, we don’t get an error if we are passing less number of parameters. For each <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">find</code> I made it was hard to understand what to pass.</p>

<p>Then I remembered how <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring Data</code></p>

<p>handles the same problem.</p>

<p>They use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">findBy{Attribute}And{AnotherAttribute}</code>.</p>

<p>Now my code became much much better. And I followed <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring Data</code> ‘s entire method naming style.</p>

<hr />

<p>If you are writing a custom library or working in a language that doesn’t have good variable/method names. You can adopt naming conventions of other projects.</p>

<p><a href="https://pytorch.org/">Pytorch</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.tensorflow.org/">Tensorflow</a></p>

<p>Spring Boot</p>

<p>UI: DevExpress Extreme</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="clean-code" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing good variable names clarifies your thinking. But it can be really really hard coming up with your own variable names.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stating the Truth When It Could Hurt</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth/state-truth-when-it-hurts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stating the Truth When It Could Hurt" /><published>2023-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-16T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth/v1-state-the-truth-even-when-its-hard</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth/state-truth-when-it-hurts"><![CDATA[<p>I often talk about truth and telling the truth all time time.</p>

<p>Many people agree with me that it’s a good thing to tell the truth.</p>

<p>But then comes parts where they start compromising telling the truth.</p>

<p>For example, they say I don’t want to hurt them so I won’t tell the truth there.</p>

<p>Or that “hinting” is same as telling the truth.</p>

<p>But truth isn’t something that you hide. Truth is actually not even something that you “say”.</p>

<p>It’s better to use a different vocabulary. State the truth.</p>

<p>We know that we don’t tell the facts. We state the facts.</p>

<p>Similarly, we state the truth. Meaning the truth passes through as it is.</p>

<p>For example, someone asks how we are doing?</p>

<p>Instead of saying I am doing really good. We say, I am better. If they drill down, I share what is really going on.</p>

<p>If someone asks why wasn’t this software delivery on time, I say, I haven’t been doing so well lately. Or that I haven’t been focused lately.</p>

<p>This is combined with honest action, to finish the work on time.</p>

<h2 id="a-recent-situation">A recent situation</h2>

<p>There is another situation I encountered. And it’s likely where many people are likely to lie.</p>

<p>I was in an Uber a few days ago. And the driver asked if he could take us offline. Offline means without the app. The driver would cancel the booking. And take us to the same destination without Uber. And I would have to pay him the same money. This way, the driver would not have his pay cut to Uber.</p>

<p>At the time, I did think Uber is a big company. But is it right to cheat against the big company. I thought let’s lie to Uber. I agreed to go offline. He canceled the booking and I snuck a deal to get 50 Rs. off the ride.</p>

<p>Pretty sweet. Now, the person who had booked the ride started getting calls from Uber. In the Uber app it showed that their is a cancelling fee of 38.10 Rs.</p>

<p>I thought Hmm. So, even after snugging a deal with the driver.</p>

<p>I got 11.90 Rs off if I add up the cancelling fee. That’s pretty bad.</p>

<p>The person who booked kept getting multiple calls from Uber to pay up.</p>

<p>Hmm. Uber help allowed selecting “My driver asked me to book without Uber”. I thought for a minute, what I should do. The person who had booked the Uber said that the Driver might lose his Job. I thought for a minute. And then decided I should side with the truth. I explained to the person that we should go with the truth and click the “My driver asked me to book without Uber” option. We did get out money back. 38Rs isn’t a big number. It’s about half a dollar.</p>

<p>Here why I choose “My driver asked me to book without Uber”.</p>

<p>The driver who did asked us for going offline, might also be convincing the same to other riders. And they maybe getting cancelling fees too.</p>

<p>Uber is a business built by hard working people. If they are providing a platform to earn, they should get the reward. The driver wouldn’t even have a job if Uber didn’t provide for it.</p>

<p>So, it didn’t make long term sense for the driver to try to betray his parent company.</p>

<p>If I side with the truth, the possibility that the driver no longer repeats the mistakes is created. It maybe possible that the driver chooses to still repeat the same mistakes. But at a minimum, he has an opportunity to choose a truthful path. And everything he does is truthful.</p>

<p>I also thought about how do court judges and people in administration do justice. Even though they know what is truth, they still may have humanly feeling to the person that may not have things in their favor. What should a judge do.</p>

<p>“We side with the truth”</p>

<p>Always. In every situation. No matter how big or small.</p>

<p>If I had told the truth with the intent of doing good. I would have explained the driver that the consequence of his actions. I should have denied his proposal. And that way, I would have given him a perspective that would have led him to a truthful path.</p>

<p>Since, customer is the king. Uber didn’t charge me anything. But it’s still weird to think that I was involved too.</p>

<p>For Uber the company, it costed 750 Rs. The money adds up to what they pay their employees. And everyone’s home runs.</p>

<ul>
  <li>To me it costed 700Rs. That’s fine.</li>
  <li>To the person who booked the uber. It costed multiple phone calls.</li>
  <li>To the driver may costed his and his family’s earning.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="truth-with-truthful-action-passes-through-without-hurting-us">Truth with truthful action passes through without hurting us.</h2>

<p>If the driver had been truthful, he wouldn’t have had to face this situation. And neither would we.</p>

<p>If I had been truthful, both we and the driver wouldn’t have faced the situation.</p>

<p>Because truth passes through without hurting us.</p>

<p>Truth passes through can be imagined and us just standing and truth passing across us. If we are lying, we engage against truth, and it hurts us. If we don’t engage against the truth and let is pass, it doesn’t hurt us.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-technical" /><category term="truth" /><category term="mature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why we should use the vocabulary 'stating'. And how can we state the truth.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You are really doing BDD when</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/you-are-following-good-bdd-when" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You are really doing BDD when" /><published>2023-03-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-11T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-you-are-following-good-bdd-when</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/you-are-following-good-bdd-when"><![CDATA[<p>You are really doing BDD if you answer yes to these questions:</p>

<ul>
  <li>BDD specifications drive the design of VDIs, prioritization and development.
    <ul>
      <li>Specs first VDIs later.</li>
      <li>Specs first Development later.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Any new decision made about the product functionality leads to an updated spec file.
    <ul>
      <li>Therefore the spec file is an integral part of every meeting.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Any dispute or confusion about what was decided is resolved by reviewing the spec file.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>You remember the specification files because you have read, modified and used them so much.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Everyone involved in the product life cycle (including non-technical people) knows what BDD is and has access to spec file.</p>
  </li>
  <li>When any new person who wants to understand the product is given the BDD file to understand it.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="bdd" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You are really doing BDD if you answer yes to these questions:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Economic Systems and Macroeconomics - Crash Course Economics - 3</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Economic Systems and Macroeconomics - Crash Course Economics - 3" /><published>2023-03-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-11T14:42:15-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/crash-course-econ-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/3"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B43YEW2FvDs" alt="" /></p>

<p>Like rolling stones tell us, we can’t get all that we want. because there are limited resources so we have to make choices.
***</p>

<p>There are 3 types of resource according to Karl Marx.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Land</li>
  <li>Labor</li>
  <li>Capital</li>
</ul>

<p>And economic system allows for</p>

<ul>
  <li>What we produce?</li>
  <li>How we produce it?</li>
  <li>Who gets it?</li>
</ul>

<p>There are two types of Economy based on who controls the resources and what the system allows.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Command Economy</li>
  <li>Free Market Economy</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>Adam Smith said</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It’s not from the benevolance of the butcher, the brewer or the baker that we expect our dinner, but from their regard to their own self interest.</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<p>Command Economy is controlled by the government. It decides what to do.</p>

<p>Free Market Economy is where a companies decides what they can produce based on the profits they receive.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Invisible Hand</strong>: The unintended social benefit resulting from individual actions.</p>

<p>Free Market Economy leads to “invisible hand” where you as a result of paying for something that leads to profit good things happen.</p>

<p>For example, if 1 of 2 competing car brands make better products, they’ll have all the capital and incentives of the free market i.e. more profits. Thus to compete the other brand has to innovate. #invisibleHand</p>

<p>Similar is not the case with command economy. Government can make a car and have no competition but it doesn’t have any special need to innovate.</p>

<hr />

<p>Planned/Command Economy is not all bad. Because there are many things Free Market economy can’t handle.</p>

<p>Things like Security, Roads, Education, etc are all things needed for a good functioning free market economy but can only be provided via Government i.e. Command Economy.</p>

<p>Also, government intervine where Free Markets are failing. For example, it can provide regulation on car safety standards or how much pollution is allowed or how should the workers be paid. All of these, saves more money in the long run.</p>

<p>North Korea is a command economy. New Zealand is a free market economy with very few taxes. Most economies of the world are mixed.</p>

<p>And many economies are and have been changing. For example, Canada 🇨🇦 went from mostly free market to providing Universal Healthcare.</p>

<p>While, China 🇨🇳 went from mostly socialist economy to free market.</p>

<p>Modern economies are neither completely free or planned, there’s a spectrum of government involvement.</p>

<p>We should not fix ourselves to one ideology or another and rather focus on what get’s the job done at the time.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It doesn’t matter if a cat is black or white, if it caches mice, it is a good cat.
~ Deng Xiaoping</p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<p>While we could absolutely abolish many things like poverty with a command economy, remember that in economic terms we always have trade-offs because we always have scares limited resources.</p>

<p>So, spending money to abolish poverty could lead to less money spend on health care or less money on security so a war that leads to more poverty!</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="circular-flow-model">Circular Flow Model</h2>

<p>There is also a circle ⭕️ where</p>

<p>Indivuals Purchase from Businesses. This way business get’s money.</p>

<p>To purchase from business, individual need money.</p>

<p>so individually provide their labor to the business. So individuals now have money.</p>

<p>Government steps in between to provide facilities to both businesses and individuals. And to get their money they tax both individuals and businesses.</p>

<p>wealthIsAlwaysTransfered because only government can generate more money. - Andrew Tate</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="crash-course" /><category term="econ" /><category term="summary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One service should serve multiple mediums (REST, Kafka, gRPC, etc)</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/separate-service/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One service should serve multiple mediums (REST, Kafka, gRPC, etc)" /><published>2023-03-10T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-10T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-separate-domain-and-connector</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/separate-service/"><![CDATA[<p>In a previous post, I talked about how we should separate Domain Layer from Technical code. Here’s another version of the same with respect to service.</p>

<p>A Service that handles tasks of a RestController isn’t very different from a rest controller.</p>

<p>We should separate out the Service from the Rest Controllers because we want to be able to re-use the service.</p>

<p>But if Service handles rest rest controller responses, it isn’t very different.</p>

<h2 id="an-ideal-service">An ideal service</h2>

<p><img src="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vT3KH3qfLmMQ0DDGtQL8uyol8YhCWqBEc1DJxuGJ5vS9gdNxYKf7vkIgb2ETVHrZOocCTJv4kAFDUtU/pub?w=1300&amp;h=740" alt="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vT3KH3qfLmMQ0DDGtQL8uyol8YhCWqBEc1DJxuGJ5vS9gdNxYKf7vkIgb2ETVHrZOocCTJv4kAFDUtU/pub?w=1300&amp;h=740" /></p>

<p>Here’s how you separate out connectors from the business logic.</p>

<p>Connector are mediums we use to communicate with the the outside world. Examples of connectors are Rest API connector (like RestController or RouterFunction+it’s Handler), Kafka Connector.</p>

<p>Services are code that implement the business logic.</p>

<p>All conversion from Entity to DTO or DTO to entity (i.e handle the request event and provide response in format needed by the client) should be handles at Rest API Connector.</p>

<p>The Rest API Connector is responsible for calling the service method between the request and the response.</p>

<p>For the service method, REST API connector is a downstream. So, it does not care about what format of data it sends. It’s just responsible for executing the business logic and sending the data in whatever is it’s format.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="web-development" /><category term="ddd" /><category term="clean-code" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your main business logic resides in your service. All other things are connectors]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vT3KH3qfLmMQ0DDGtQL8uyol8YhCWqBEc1DJxuGJ5vS9gdNxYKf7vkIgb2ETVHrZOocCTJv4kAFDUtU/pub?w=1300&amp;amp;h=740" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vT3KH3qfLmMQ0DDGtQL8uyol8YhCWqBEc1DJxuGJ5vS9gdNxYKf7vkIgb2ETVHrZOocCTJv4kAFDUtU/pub?w=1300&amp;amp;h=740" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Specialization and Trade - Crash Course Economics - 2</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Specialization and Trade - Crash Course Economics - 2" /><published>2023-03-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-04T14:42:15-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/crash-course-econ-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/2"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NI9TLDIPVcs" alt="" /></p>

<p>Adam Grant was the person who created the wealth of nations. He concluded that specialization and trading are better for everyone involved.</p>

<p>If you don’t specialize and trade, you’ll have to do everything yourself.</p>

<p>For example in the case of pizza, you’ll have to farm wheat, they make an oven and then even cook.</p>

<p>Instead, by specializing everyone’s opportunity cost improves.</p>

<p>The PPF profit possibility frontier helps understand the relationship between producing two products,</p>

<p>For example, if the us is producing 500 planes and it could use the same effort to produce 2000 shoes,
For every 1 plane they produce, they leave our 4 shoes.</p>

<p>If China can produce 100 planes or 800 shoes with the same effort, china for every 1 plane produced, leaves out 800 shoes.</p>

<p>It may seem that the US is better off here and should not trade, but if the US trades planes for shoes, they’ll be better off (need to learn here)</p>

<hr />

<p>Point outside the PPF curve is an impossibility
The point inside the PPF curve is inefficiency.
How do you maximize efficiency?
By specializing and trading.</p>

<hr />

<p>Self-sufficiency is inefficiency</p>

<hr />

<p>Wellness can be predicted by a variety of many economic predictors like GDP per capita, employee, and ent rate, by this we see statistically, most improvements came after Industrial Revolution.</p>

<p>We also see that countries that are voluntarily or involuntarily cut off from trading with other countries. like Iran Zimbabwe %</p>

<p>And countries like India and China that opened up the economy and started trading have been experiencing significant growth in %</p>

<p>Individuals and countries should specialize and do things that they have a competitive advantage in and then trade with others in what they have a competitive advantage in. This trade is mutually beneficial</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="crash-course" /><category term="econ" /><category term="summary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro to Economics - Crash Course Econ 1</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to Economics - Crash Course Econ 1" /><published>2023-03-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-04T14:42:15-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/crash-course-econ-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/1"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3ez10ADR_gM" alt="" /></p>

<p>Economics is not just a study of money or the stock exchange.</p>

<p>Economics is the study of people and their choices.</p>

<p>And this is based on two fundamental assumptions of Economics.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Scarcity</li>
  <li>Opportunity Cost</li>
</ul>

<p>You could be doing one thing but you are choosing to do something else. In that sense, you believe that doing one is a better use of your time than another. Therefore, your opportunity cost of one is greater than another.</p>

<p>Scarcity means there is a limited supply of resources.</p>

<hr />

<p>Economics is when people make choices. When a college student decides to pick major A over Major B.</p>

<hr />

<p>Many people believe that if you just put more money into healthcare, it would improve. But in many cases what we need is the right incentive. So, economics is also a study of incentives.</p>

<p>For example, you could provide the college with an incentive on the number of enrollments. But then college would play it to just enroll.</p>

<p>Then you modify it to incentivize the number of graduates, then you suddenly have colleges just passing people or lowering difficulty or only admitting smart kids.</p>

<p>So, it’s very important to get incentives right. Because wrong incentives can backfire.</p>

<hr />

<p>Most economists are in Microeconomics. Whether to launch the business snow or later? What to do when a competitor does x?</p>

<p>Macro is the study of a Nation and its decisions like inflation, unemployment, etc.</p>

<hr />

<p>Both Governments and the Free Market support each other. One can’t function without the other.</p>

<hr />

<p>There is always an opportunity cost. If you don’t want road accidents, you could remove all cards from the road. But you understand the opportunity cost and decide one is better than the other.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="crash-course" /><category term="econ" /><category term="summary" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The only differences between external_apps and internal_features in a plugin architecture</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/internal-vs-external-plugin" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The only differences between external_apps and internal_features in a plugin architecture" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-difference-between-third-party-and-first-party</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/internal-vs-external-plugin"><![CDATA[<h2 id="from-a-users-perspective">From A User’s Perspective</h2>

<p>First Party <strong>Default</strong> Apps are just product features.</p>

<p>First Party <strong>Installable</strong> Apps are apps that can be installed by the user.</p>

<ul>
  <li>These apps are not enabled by default</li>
  <li>These are provided by default.</li>
  <li>A user won’t even know that these are treated as an app by the platform company.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Third-party</strong> apps are created by third-party developers and can extend the core functionality of the first-party app.</p>

<ul>
  <li>These apps are not enabled by default.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="code-perspective">Code Perspective</h2>

<p><strong>These two types of apps are the same</strong>, except the first-party app doesn’t need Authentication to access Platform data, while the third-party app does.</p>

<p>A third-party app may utilize all capabilities that the plugin platform provides unless some capabilities are reserved for first-party apps.</p>

<p>In the previous post, I explained how we could define scopes for our resource would work.</p>

<p>I took the example of movies where an app is using 2 scopes: “<strong>read:movies</strong>” and “<strong>read:userinfo</strong>”</p>

<p>Let’s call this app, an external_app.</p>

<p>Now suppose we have an internal feature, which uses the same endpoints that “read:movies” and “read:userinfo” uses.</p>

<p>The only difference between external_app and the internal feature would be that the external_app will use OAuth and scopes to get access to the resource. While the internal_feature would not have to ask for permission to access the resource.</p>

<p>This means, once you create a scope, it’s fixed.</p>

<p>And this simplifies your development a lot.</p>

<hr />

<p>So, therefore, we need not treat internal features and external apps very differently.</p>

<p>At the platform level, both internal_feature and the external_app are just apps.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="architecture" /><category term="plugin" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[From A User’s Perspective]]></summary></entry></feed>