<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-13T13:26:59-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush Choubey</title><subtitle>Full Stack Developer - Cloud/Microservices</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Truthful Optimistic approach to bouncing back from major loss</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/dealing-with-loss" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Truthful Optimistic approach to bouncing back from major loss" /><published>2023-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-06T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-dealing-with-loss</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/dealing-with-loss"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/v1-dealing-with-loss.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@spaablauw?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Joppe Spaa</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/losing?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>The blog post may seem trivial to many readers. This could be because they haven’t faced a big loss in their life. The kind of loss this post talks about is achievement related. It’s not related to the loss of human life.</p>

<p>Many of us have experienced loss, this could be a loss of job or a sudden end of a relationship. And these can devastate us in the short term. This can be especially true if we work really really hard. We put in all our efforts and still, we lost.</p>

<p>There are a few approaches we take when facing a major loss.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Conjure up a story that keeps us away from reality.</li>
  <li>Examine, experience and accept reality as it is.</li>
</ol>

<p>In Julia Galef’s Scott Mindset, a book about clear thinking, she describes these approaches in a chapter on Coping Mechanisms. This article is an expansion to the original ideas of the book for experiences and accepting reality as it is.</p>

<p>The premise of this post is this: <strong>You can deal with failure better when you understand certain truths. <em>Understand, not just know.</em></strong> And by better I mean you can bounce back faster.</p>

<p>There is also the topic of how you not repeat the same mistake gain. But that’s for another time.</p>

<h2 id="dealing-with-loss-truthfully">Dealing with loss truthfully</h2>

<p>Understand and internalize these truths.</p>

<h2 id="settling-the-past">Settling the past</h2>

<h3 id="truth-1-karmafal-is-not-in-your-hands-only-karma-is">Truth #1: Karmafal is not in your hands. Only karma is</h3>

<p>We don’t control the outcome of our actions. We only control how we act. There are many factors outside of our control. We can influence them with our decisions. But we can’t control them directly.</p>

<h3 id="truth-2-it-doesnt-matter-if-you-win-or-lose-it-matters-how-you-play">Truth #2: It doesn’t matter if you win or lose, it matters how? you play</h3>

<p>Life is a series of games. If you cheat and win one game, it doesn’t mean you can cheat and win another. But if you lost the first game and didn’t cheat but kept improving and playing, you’ll eventually win a lot of upcoming games that come.</p>

<p>Therefore, it doesn’t matter if you win or lose. What matters is how you played.</p>

<h3 id="truth-3-you-can-only-do-your-best">Truth #3: You can only do your best</h3>

<p>Here’s a hypothesis: Can you do more than your best <strong>at a moment</strong>? For example, at a certain moment, you learned a certain knowledge and hold certain resources, but you don’t know what’s beyond that knowledge. Therefore, you could only do your best.</p>

<p>That does bet the question of did you give your best. But as long as you did give your best, it doesn’t matter. Cuz you couldn’t have done more than your best.</p>

<h3 id="truth-4-you-cant-win-all-the-time-its-a-simple-probability">Truth #4: You can’t win all the time. It’s a simple probability</h3>

<p>What were your chances of scoring 99th percentile?? 1/99 assuming you have studied hard and studied better than all the people who also studied.</p>

<p>We always have wins and losses. These are mixed across time.</p>

<h2 id="looking-at-the-future">Looking at the future</h2>

<h3 id="truth-5-will-this-matter-in-3-5-years">Truth #5: Will this matter in 3-5 years</h3>

<p>Almost all loss or win doesn’t matter in 3-5 years. We change our trajectory so much that we don’t care in the long term.</p>

<h3 id="truth-6-the-past-is-gone">Truth #6: The past is gone</h3>

<p>No matter how much we may want to change the past, it’s impossible. The only thing we can do is learn from it and use those lessons to shape our future. Accepting this truth can be freeing and allow us to focus on the present and future.</p>

<h3 id="truth-7-the-next-chance-is-still-here">Truth #7: The next chance is still here</h3>

<p>There is always another chance. Life is long enough to get important things done, and even if we fail at something today, we can try again tomorrow or pursue a different path.</p>

<h3 id="truth-8-losing-means-learning">Truth #8: Losing means learning</h3>

<p>We have time, and now we also have experience. This means the next time we are less likely to make the same mistake if we learn it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="peace" /><category term="non-technical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Instead of seeing failure as a personal flaw or a permanent setback, see it as an opportunity for growth and improvement. Focus on learning from your mistakes and using them to become better in the future.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-dealing-with-loss.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-dealing-with-loss.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Remind yourself of your core values at all times.</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/remind-yourself-of-your-core-values/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remind yourself of your core values at all times." /><published>2023-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-06T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-remind-yourself-of-your-core-values</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/remind-yourself-of-your-core-values/"><![CDATA[<p>Humans are forgetful. We have infinite (useless things) to attend to.</p>

<p>Keep your core values front and center. Base your life around them. Not anything or anyone else.</p>

<p>Wake up each day choosing to live your core values better.</p>

<p>Sleep each day reflecting on them. Choosing how you could improve you could improve your practices or how you could improve your values.</p>

<p>Keep a place where it’s visible at all times.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophical" /><category term="non-technical" /><category term="implementing-core-values" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humans are forgetful. We have infinite (useless things) to attend to.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let the world do what it wants to do, you follow your core values</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/let-other-people-see-your-values/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let the world do what it wants to do, you follow your core values" /><published>2023-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-06T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-let-other-people-see</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/let-other-people-see-your-values/"><![CDATA[<p>Your core values are who you are to the core. People around you should be able to guess your core values. Even without you explicitly telling them.</p>

<p>If they aren’t able to guess with a good degree of accuracy, you may have a branding issue or more likely you aren’t living to your core values fully.</p>

<p>At the same time, discussing your core values with others especially giving reasoning when you take certain decisions that others find weird is a good way to deepen your understanding and let others find holes in your values.</p>

<p>Explaining my core values to my friends and family has helped them understand me. And it has helped me be a more genuine version of myself.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophical" /><category term="non-technical" /><category term="implementing-core-values" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your core values are who you are to the core. People around you should be able to guess your core values. Even without you explicitly telling them.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let the world do what it wants to do, you follow your core values</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/follow-your-values/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let the world do what it wants to do, you follow your core values" /><published>2023-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-06T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-follow-your-values</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/follow-your-values/"><![CDATA[<p>Core values are long term. They aren’t short term.</p>

<p>They may have good shorterm impact too. But not always.</p>

<p>While you are following your core values, you’ll find people taking shortcuts. Hacking and bending reality to fit their short term purpose.</p>

<p>Many time you’ll also be tempted to go on the same path. To not pay attention to details. To skip consciousnly. You may want the same fast pace progress that other’s are having.</p>

<p>But don’t go down that path. Fast is an illusion. A puffed up reality.</p>

<p>Real long term progress is slow and takes months and years. You’ll likely stare into an abyss. But it’s way better to voluntarily choose to go and stare into the abyss. As more snd more time passed, you’ll see a light. A transformed version of you in every area of life.</p>

<p>So making your decisions based on what the world is doing. Let them take their path. You choose yours.</p>

<p>If you have carefully selected your core values, you believe these are your best bets. Choose your best bets no matter the short term impact.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophical" /><category term="non-technical" /><category term="implementing-core-values" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Core values are long term. They aren’t short term.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stepping aside from the game of “success” and comparison</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/step-aside-success/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stepping aside from the game of “success” and comparison" /><published>2023-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-01T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-step-aside-success</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/step-aside-success/"><![CDATA[<p>According to be Big 5 scale. I am high in conscientiousness and high in openness. Meaning I am hard-working and open to ideas. And this is a usual trait for societal success.</p>

<p>At about 16 years old, I came across self-help. And I was hooked. Exercising, Meditating, Morning Rituals, Reading Books, Quitting Social Media, etc. I have done and restarted these multiple times.</p>

<p>At the same time, I am someone who during his teen years was very jealous of other teens. If I see someone doing something better or I hear a young genius of the same age getting an offer from Google or making apps, I would be very very jealous and critical of myself.</p>

<p>As I have gotten older, I have resolved my jealousy of other people of similar age but also my jealousy of others in general. This article is a description of my current thought process.</p>

<p><img src="/images/v1-step-aside-success.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@dietmarbecker?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" title="‌">Dietmar Becker</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/comparison?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" title="‌">Unsplash</a></p>

<h2 id="comparison-with-others-is-a-stupid-game">Comparison with others is a stupid game</h2>

<p>In a previous blog post, I talked about Ethos, Pathos, and Logos, and how these persuasion techniques can be used beyond persuasion. One of them is we can identify what sort of game we are playing and choose what game we want to play.</p>

<p>For example, comparison with others is an ethos game. Ethos is character. You are more likely to listen to a doctor, who is well-dressed and from a prestigious college than to a random doctor who is not.</p>

<p>Ethos as a game means you are comparing yourself to others and trying to one-up yourself. “He earns less than me”. “I have a good-looking girlfriend, he does not”. Ethos game is a popular cultural name: Status Games.</p>

<p>Status games are externally driven. And what’s externally driven is almost always fragile.</p>

<p>Therefore, ethos/status games are fragile.</p>

<p>Today you are “more successful” than someone. Yesterday someone else was. Tomorrow someone else will be.</p>

<p>Start to learn to play piano and after a year you’ll find a child prodigy beating you at every note. Become a senior programmer with 10 years of experience and find out some random college kid understands concepts much more deeply.</p>

<p>Maybe you got lucky. Or maybe someone else got lucky. Good for you and good for them.</p>

<p>Most comparison/Ethos Games/Status Games are stupid. It’s a win-lose game. You should choose a win-win game. Make yourself better and make someone else also better.</p>

<h2 id="achievementsuccess-is-never-stable-its-in-constant-flux">“Achievement/Success” is never stable. It’s in constant flux.</h2>

<p>Simon Sinek has a wonderful video, we’ll see. Once upon a time, there was a guy who broke his legs. Everyone pities and the guys were sad. The monk said we’ll see. Then a few months later a war happened, and every man had to go to war. Guess who didn’t go to war? The guy who broke his leg. The guy is now happy. The monk says we’ll see. And the story goes on and on.</p>

<p>An achievement is a one-time event. It’s not an everyday event. And once you have success doesn’t mean you will stay “successful”. You or someone may lose their success and then have to start from scratch again. That’s life.</p>

<p>Maybe you have some opportunities that others didn’t have. Or maybe you earned your success. Now, you see someone else who has been way faster in his, should that matter? I would so no. Good for him. Good for you.</p>

<h2 id="stupidest-game-respect">Stupidest game: RESPECT.</h2>

<p>Earning respect externally is the stupidest game I can think of. It’s fragile.</p>

<p>People spend time crafting a perfect social media profile. Everyone trying to treat themselves like a celebrity. Hoping they get likes. Today everyone likes them. And they have made it part of their identity. Now, become too afraid to show the real them. They can speak freely because they are too concerned with pleasing people.</p>

<p>Then there are these stupid games,</p>

<ul>
  <li>“oh, he has 10 servants we have none.”.</li>
  <li>“They threw a lavish party where Narendra Modi came, look at you.” (the problem with this statement is “look at you” not the event itself.</li>
</ul>

<p>There are also “Attitude status YouTube Shorts” which are on the same level as stupid.</p>

<p>You should avoid the game of external respect. External respect is just a fragile ethos/status game. Instead, earn internal respect. How do you earn internal respect? By doing hard things, being ethical, and following logos (logic). The rest, how others think, and what they’ll say doesn’t and should not matter.</p>

<p>By stepping outside this “respect”, game and free yourself from others’ judgment.</p>

<h2 id="good-enough">Good enough.</h2>

<p>After one point it doesn’t matter.</p>

<p>Suppose you are earning 5 lakh rs per month. After this does it matter if you earn more? You can travel the world well. Your “lifestyle” does not change all that much.</p>

<p>The same is true with everything. Once you are fit enough, that’s good enough. You don’t need to try to get a bigger bicep for comparison with others.</p>

<p>Everything reaches a good enough point. If someone else reaches a good enough point good for them, if you reach, good for you.</p>

<h2 id="get-inspired-and-learn-from-others-but-remember-the-competition-is-you-vs-you">Get inspired and learn from others but remember, the competition is you vs you.</h2>

<p>Comparison for being jealous is stupid. Compare to become inspired but recognize that your goals may be different from theirs.</p>

<p>For your company to be successful, it doesn’t mean someone else company needs to be unsuccessful.</p>

<p>Restating the same premise: If I achieve something, good for me. If someone else achieves something, good for them. Aim for a Win-win.</p>

<p>At the same time, it’s unfair for you to compare yourself to others. You and they have different lives with different strengths, weaknesses, and challenges. Compare to who you were yesterday, not with who someone else is today <a href="Jordan Peterson">1</a>.</p>

<p>Comparing with your previous self gives you the best understanding of your progress and makes personalized decisions.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>You’ll always find someone better than yourself and at the same time “success” is in constant flux i.e. it can change with time. Therefore, you should enter the game of becoming jealous of other people’s success.</p>

<p>Avoid status games. It leads to pretending. They are win-lose. Play win-win games.</p>

<p>Recognize once you achieve a certain level of “output success”, it doesn’t matter what happens after it.</p>

<p>Get inspired and learn from others. But don’t compare yourself to others. The only perfect person you can compare yourself to is who you were yesterday.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="team-work" /><category term="non-technical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why comparison with others is stupid and why the only person you should compare to is who you were yesterday]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-step-aside-success.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-step-aside-success.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Decoding the difference between healthy love and unhealthy attachment, and choosing healthy love.</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/love-attachment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Decoding the difference between healthy love and unhealthy attachment, and choosing healthy love." /><published>2023-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-28T15:42:15-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-love-attachment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/love-attachment/"><![CDATA[<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@cbeloch?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" title="‌">Christopher Beloch</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/images/feelings/love?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" title="‌">Unsplash</a></p>

<h2 id="why-is-it-important-to-differentiate-between-love-and-attachment">Why is it important to differentiate between love and attachment?</h2>

<p>We pedestalize love. We feel it’s a cure-all for all problems. Maybe it is. But are we actually in love? or is it just an attachment?</p>

<p>Understanding the difference between love and attachment will help us make better decisions.</p>

<ol>
  <li>It’ll make us not do things out of attachment. Attachment leads to stupidity.</li>
  <li>It’ll help us understand and grow love. :)</li>
</ol>

<p>So once we understand our thought is based on attachment, we can break out of it.</p>

<p>Attachment is called Moh in Hindi. And it’s one of the great sins.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-the-difference-between-love-and-attachment">What is the difference between love and attachment?</h2>

<p>We often confuse love and attachment. Here is what the difference is.</p>

<p>If we are doing something or thinking something for the benefit of others, we are in love. If we are doing something or thinking of something for the benefit of ourselves and wrapping someone else in it to act a certain way it’s attachment.</p>

<p>The central focus of love is the well-being of the other. You may argue that healthy love is the well-being of both others and ourselves. Attachment on the other hand is just our well-being of ourselves.</p>

<h2 id="how-should-we-catch-ourselves-and-act-in-love-and-attachment">How should we catch ourselves and act in love and attachment?</h2>

<p>Below are three paths that can help you understand if you are in love or attachment.</p>

<h3 id="understanding-it-logically-can-be-used-day-to-day">Understanding it logically [Can be used day to day]</h3>

<p>Understanding your logical reasonings can give you a feel for if you are in love or just acting out of attachment.</p>

<p>The principle remains the same: if the focus is us, it’s attachment. If the focus is the well-being of another person, it’s love.</p>

<h4 id="example-1">Example 1</h4>

<ul>
  <li>I want someone to stay in my life, is attachment.</li>
  <li>I wish someone the best life he or she can have with or without me, is love.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="example-2">Example 2</h4>

<ul>
  <li>I want my kid to do what I want him to do, is attachment.</li>
  <li>I want my kid to do his best, is love.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Exercise</strong>:</p>

<ol>
  <li>You can also exercise this by listening to different songs and identify parts that are out of love and ones that are out of attachment.</li>
  <li>Think about how you acted the last time, were you doing something for yourself or the benefit of other.</li>
</ol>

<p>There is also a sacrificial element in love. We sacrifice our own desires for others.</p>

<h4 id="example-1-1">Example 1</h4>

<ul>
  <li>We don’t like walking. But the other person likes walking. They find it meaningful and a bonding time. We sometimes, maybe not often, go for a walk because the other person likes it.</li>
</ul>

<p>This can well be expanded into giving up our own comfort for the other person. Like, moving to a new city <strong>for them</strong>, because it makes them happy.</p>

<h4 id="example-2-1">Example 2</h4>

<ul>
  <li>The other person is facing a problem. And we give up doing what we most enjoy to solve their problem.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="understanding-via-attachment-styles">Understanding via Attachment Styles</h3>

<p>Attachment styles are how we relate to other people. For example, you may be <strong>avoidant</strong> of your sibling but <strong>anxious</strong> to your parents but <strong>assertively secure</strong> with your colleagues.</p>

<p>There are 4 attachment styles:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Secure</strong> → This should be our aim</li>
  <li><strong>Anxious</strong> → This makes you worried and overdo.</li>
  <li><strong>Avoidant</strong> → This is where you avoid your own partner</li>
  <li><strong>Anxious</strong> Avoidant → This is a mix of anxious and avoidant.</li>
</ol>

<p>You can have different attachment styles to different people. But in love, we usually have the same attachment style as we had with our parents in early childhood.</p>

<p>Anxious, avoidant and anxious avoidant are all unhealthy attachments.</p>

<p>By learning about your attachment style, you can identify behaviors that are common in that style. For example, I am becoming secure but anxious. Here are some common things I did.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Write a message and then delete it.</li>
  <li>Ping them constantly</li>
  <li>Fear something is going wrong and constantly seek validation.</li>
  <li>Think about them all day instead of working.</li>
  <li>Give up my own dreams to accommodate there’s.</li>
  <li>Watch the same shows as they watched and stopped watching what I liked.</li>
  <li>Not sharing how I really feel because it may lead to rejection.</li>
</ul>

<p>The list goes on and on.</p>

<p>For someone avoidant, they prefer independence. And have behaviors such as:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Not opening up.</li>
</ul>

<p>There are more but these are some I know but learning can help you understand yourself and the other person better.</p>

<p>If you are anxious or avoidant, you should aim toward becoming <strong>secure</strong>. I’ll write a post about it some other day.</p>

<h3 id="are-you-pedestalizing-love">Are you pedestalizing love?</h3>

<p>Attachment makes us control the outcome. It makes us irrational.</p>

<p>Do you feel only think about love? Or see it as a cure-all? If yes, you are attached.</p>

<h2 id="how-love-relates-to-giving-up-control">How love relates to giving up control?</h2>

<p>Attachment makes us control the outcome. It makes us irrational. We can’t control the outcome.</p>

<p>Love makes us give up on the outcome. Healthy love gives both yourself and the other person some control.</p>

<h2 id="we-cant-be-100-in-love-but-we-can-always-do-better-than-we-are"><strong>We can’t be 100% in love. But we can always do better than we are.</strong></h2>

<p>We can’t always be in love. We are selfish by nature and that isn’t a bad thing in moderation. We need to manage our self-interest and the self-interest of others.</p>

<p>We don’t want to be a giver (anxious) or just a taker (avoidant), we want a balance of both.</p>

<p>The best way to go about it is to identify your attachment style, understand when you acting out of love or attachment, act more in love and give up control. :)</p>

<p><img src="/images/v1-love-attachment.jpg" alt="" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="love" /><category term="team-work" /><category term="non-technical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Love is a selfless emotion that focuses on the well-being of the other person, while attachment is a selfish emotion that centers on our own well-being. It's essential to catch ourselves when we act out of attachment and try to shift our focus to acting out of love]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-love-attachment.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-love-attachment.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why should you be internally disciplined?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/internal-discipline/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why should you be internally disciplined?" /><published>2023-04-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-05-22T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-why-internal-discipline</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/internal-discipline/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/v1-internal-discipline.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jontyson?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Jon Tyson</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/hard-work?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p>

<p>I realized the root cause of why even when I created a had so many systems. I was failing. Because their systems were all external. I needed something internal that drives me. I needed Discipline.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-discipline">What is Discipline?</h2>

<p>Discipline is having a plan about doing or not doing something and then sticking to the plan regardless of how we feel.</p>

<p>We may feel good today and we do the tasks. We may feel bad today and we still do the tasks. And we do the task both on good days and bad days as if nothing happened. i.e. there is no performance degradation.</p>

<h2 id="much-of-lifes-success-is-not-in-the-intellect-its-a-repeated-process--execution">Much of life’s success is not in the intellect. It’s a repeated process / execution</h2>

<p>We pedastalize genius, insights and new. We think it’ll solve everything or the person who has these features will solve everything.</p>

<p>More often goes the uncool “actually doing the work”. It’s easy to come up with ideas. But only when an idea is implemented it becomes useful.</p>

<p>If you look at good leaders, even prime ministers like Narendra Modi, he may not be the best at foreign policy, but that’s not his job, his job is to decide to have the best foreign minister, and then remove any impediments or inefficencies. i.e. this does not require a 200 EQ, this requires an organized disciplined process. At the same time, you’ll find that the PM is disciplined and organized in all aspects of his life.</p>

<h2 id="internal-discipline-is-the-source-of-truth-and-it-gets-the-job-done">Internal Discipline is the source of truth and it gets the job done</h2>

<p>You cannot rely on motivation. Motivation is fickle and fragile.</p>

<p>Discipline on the other hand is antifragile. It gets the job done and done fully.</p>

<p>You can rely on discipline. It’s the only source of predicting the future. You can count on it.</p>

<h2 id="internal-discipline-gets-all-jobs-done">Internal Discipline gets all jobs done</h2>

<p>If the task is small, it gets done. If the task is big, it gets done. It doesn’t matter what the task is. Is it hard? Does it make you fearful? Does not matter.</p>

<p>If you have discipline. You get it done.</p>

<h2 id="internal-discipline-eliminates-the-need-for-how-searching-answers">Internal Discipline eliminates the need for “how” searching answers</h2>

<ul>
  <li>How do you work out? → You work out.</li>
  <li>How do you learn to program? → You learn to program.</li>
  <li>How do you wake up in the morning → You wake up in the morning.</li>
</ul>

<p>Discipline makes most “how” questions irrelevant. Therefore, it’s a time saver.</p>

<h2 id="internal-discipline-makes-you-stronger">Internal Discipline makes you stronger</h2>

<p>Internal discipline demands being strong and doing things despite the adversities we face. These adversities can be in the form of feelings, tiredness, weakness, or outside factors. Overcoming these daily makes us stronger.</p>

<h2 id="by-focusing-on-internal-discipline-the-goals-and-systems-will-take-care-of-themselves">By focusing on internal-discipline, the goals, and systems will take care of themselves</h2>

<p>You should be the driver of yourself. Not externalities.</p>

<p>Externalities even systems are fragile. Internal Self Discipline is Anti-Fragile!</p>

<p>The problem is your systems will also fail if you are lethargic and lazy. Internal Discipline will not allow that!</p>

<p>You will be better at managing that and updating your systems if you are disciplined! Therefore, by being disciplined your systems would also not fail.</p>

<p>When you have internal discipline, you may not need external discipline or external systems. You are internally driven.</p>

<h2 id="commitment-leads-to-discipline">Commitment leads to Discipline</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophical" /><category term="non-technical" /><category term="discipline" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Internal discipline is an antifragile source of motivation that gets the job done, eliminates the need for "how" questions, makes you stronger, and allows you to focus on achieving your goals without relying on external systems or motivators.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-internal-discipline.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-internal-discipline.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Karma and Karmafal - An Introduction</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/karma-karmafal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Karma and Karmafal - An Introduction" /><published>2023-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-20T15:42:15-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-karma-karmafal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/karma-karmafal/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/v1-karma-karmafal.jpg" alt="Karma and Karmafal" /></p>

<p>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@jessedo81?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">jesse orrico</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/IdjxBF_StBk?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p>

<h2 id="what-is-karma">What is Karma?</h2>

<p>Karma is the Hindi world for action. According to Hinduism, we should do the right action. And we should take the right action voluntarily despite the challenges we face because it is the best possible path.</p>

<p>Karma, the action, is always something in our control. The result of our actions, karmafal, is not in our control.</p>

<h2 id="karmafal-the-results-of-our-karma">Karmafal: The results of our karma</h2>

<p>There are things outside of us that we can influence, but it doesn’t mean that we control them. We don’t even control our bodies, we influence them with Karma, and the right Karma or even approximately right karma would push us in the right direction.</p>

<p>For example, let’s say you want to get fit, you start exercising and you influence the outcome of getting fit, but it doesn’t mean you get fit. It may be that you are following the wrong diet, which is fine, you just have to update your diet. Or it could be something outside of your control, like a disease like Thyroid which may be leading you to be overweight or underweight.</p>

<h2 id="detach-ourselves-from-controlling-the-outcome-control-the-input">Detach ourselves from controlling the outcome. Control the input</h2>

<p>Doing Karma is in our control. Having the Karmafal, the result of our karma is not in our control.</p>

<p>We are influenced by many things that weren’t our choice, neither those are results of our actions but are our responsibility. There is a randomness to life. Like in the previous example with a disease, it’s likely not our choice to have a disease, but let’s say we have it, now our best bet is to take good action going forward.</p>

<p>This may sound depressing, but it’s actually empowering. In any situation, we can’t control the results, but we do have the ability to influence the results.</p>

<p>We should abandon the idea of controlling the outcome. We can control the input, we can do our karma to our best and let the outcome be influenced, and the resultant tiny influence we see in the outcome may be enough.</p>

<p>This also keeps you free. When you are not attached to the outcome means that you are not terrified by it. For example, if you like someone, and they are doing something stupid if you are attached to how they may feel, you may never tell them how you feel. And they may continue to do something stupid. When you are not attached to the outcome, you can tell them how you feel (maybe you can learn to be kind), and your input may help them. To take action according to your input is their lookout and their action. It’s not something in your control, but you have influenced it and given them the tools and your thoughts to help them make a better choice.</p>

<p>We control how we play. We don’t control if it rains or not, we control if we go for a run. We don’t control if we get 1000 views, we control how well we present our ideas.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="further-reading">Further Reading</h2>

<p><a href="https://dailystoic.com/all-you-control-is-how-you-play/">Daily Stoic: You Control How You Play</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="responsibility" /><category term="non-technical" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Karma is the action we take, while Karmafal is the result of our actions, and by detaching ourselves from the outcome, we can focus on doing our best and live a more empowered life.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-karma-karmafal.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-karma-karmafal.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Simple Things to Improve Backend and Frontend Performance</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/backend-performance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Simple Things to Improve Backend and Frontend Performance" /><published>2023-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-backend-performance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/backend-performance/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="return-early-dont-create-objects-that-are-not-in-use">Return early. Don’t create objects that are not in use</h2>

<p><strong>Bad</strong></p>

<div class="language-java highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">//bad</span>

<span class="nc">User</span> <span class="n">user</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">dbCallToCallUsers</span><span class="o">();</span> <span class="c1">//DB Call Count 1</span>
<span class="nc">UserHomepageSettings</span> <span class="n">userhomePageSettings</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">dbcalltoCalluserSettings</span><span class="o">();</span> <span class="c1">//DB Call Count 2</span>

<span class="k">if</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">validate</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">users</span><span class="o">)</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="n">validate</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">userSettings</span><span class="o">)){</span>
  <span class="c1">// business logic</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><strong>Good</strong>:</p>

<div class="language-java highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nc">User</span> <span class="n">user</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">dbCallToCallUsers</span><span class="o">();</span> <span class="c1">//DB Call Count 1</span>
<span class="k">if</span><span class="o">(!</span><span class="n">validate</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">users</span><span class="o">)){</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">or</span> <span class="k">throw</span> <span class="nf">Exception</span><span class="o">();</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
<span class="nc">UserHomepageSettings</span> <span class="n">userhomePageSettings</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">dbcalltoCalluserSettings</span><span class="o">();</span> <span class="c1">//DB Call Count 2</span>
<span class="k">if</span><span class="o">(!</span><span class="n">validate</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">userhomePageSettings</span><span class="o">)){</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">or</span> <span class="k">throw</span> <span class="nf">Exception</span><span class="o">();</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="count-the-number-of-network-calls-in-a-flow-and-keep-it-at-minimum">Count the number of network calls in a flow and keep it at minimum</h2>

<p>This is similar to previous point. I try to make sure I have max 3 DB calls per operation. 1 is ideal.</p>

<h2 id="use-maps-and-sets">Use Maps and Sets</h2>

<p>Instead of using List prefer Sets and Maps. Searching a list of map is almost instant.</p>

<h2 id="reduce-copying-of-objects-from-one-form-to-another">Reduce copying of objects from one form to another</h2>

<p>Instead of converting from one object to another, to another, to another. Try to make sure you don’t have to convert the same object from one form to another multiple times.</p>

<h2 id="for-response-classes-reduce-copying-by-using-a-delegate-class">For response classes reduce copying by using a delegate class</h2>

<p>We often use “mapper” classes and methods to convert from one object to another. For example, from entity to DTO.</p>

<p>These usually copy the data from one object to another.</p>

<p>This has problems because suppose your original object is 10Mb in memory, when you copy it, you have to copy 10Mb object. Your RAM get’s filled and copying is generally slow.</p>

<p>Here’s a better way to do it with Delegate.</p>

<div class="language-java highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">UserResponse</span><span class="o">{</span>

  <span class="nd">@JsonIgnore</span> <span class="c1">//We want to ignore the source class</span>
  <span class="kd">private</span> <span class="nc">UserEntity</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="o">;</span>

  <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="nc">String</span> <span class="nf">getId</span><span class="o">(){</span>
    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">getId</span><span class="o">();</span>
  <span class="o">}</span>

  <span class="o">...</span> <span class="n">other</span> <span class="n">getters</span> <span class="n">that</span> <span class="n">are</span> <span class="n">similar</span>

  <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="nc">String</span> <span class="nf">getName</span><span class="o">(){</span>
    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">getFirstName</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="s">" "</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">getLastName</span><span class="o">();</span>
    <span class="c1">// Here we are converting from one form to another without copying.</span>
  <span class="o">}</span>
<span class="o">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Using delegate we reduce the amount of copying needed in the application.</p>

<p>If you are using <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">java</code> you can use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Lombok</code> library which provide a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">@Delegate</code> to do the same task as above without even writing your own getters. This will make your code very precise and fast.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="backend" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Return early. Don’t create objects that are not in use]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The many ways of using Ethos Pathos Logos</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth/ethos-pathos-logos" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The many ways of using Ethos Pathos Logos" /><published>2023-04-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-07T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth/v1-ethos-pathos-logis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth/ethos-pathos-logos"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>2000 years ago Socrates came up with his 3 Rehetorics. Ethos, Pathos, and Logos.</p>

<p>These Rhetorics and used extensively in persuasion techniques.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Ethos</strong> means the identity of the person to you. For example, if you are given a piece of advice from your father, you are more likely to accept it, rather than a stranger. Even if the advice is exactly the same. Ethos means using authority to persuade.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Pathos</strong> means emotions. For example, if you were seeing a YouTube video asking you to donate to a charity, the video would be more persuasive if it told the story of the people involved, how has their life been, and how your money would help them. Pathos means using emotions to persuade.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Logos</strong> means logic. For example, you see a sign while boarding the train that there is a gap between the train and the platform and you may slip in so walk carefully. (Maybe the example was too dark but you get the point.). Logos means using logic to persuade.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Any advertisement you see would include all three, ethos pathos, and logos. And you can find many YouTube videos if you search for “Example of Ethos Pathos Logos”.</p>

<p>When I first learned about it did make sense. But as time went on I found use cases for Ethos, Pathos, and Logos beyond persuasion. Whoever I talked to lit up when I explained the concept. Each and every person found it insightful.</p>

<p>(By the way, the sentence above is Pathos.)</p>

<p>This post is an exploration of the 3 Rhetoric applied in different ways, all of which are aimed at making well-informed decisions. Before the exploration, we should take a look at which of the Rhetoric is most useful and when.</p>

<h2 id="whats-most-important-ethos-pathos-or-logos">What’s most important Ethos, Pathos, or Logos?</h2>

<p>Throughout life, we face different challenges. The way we overcome those challenges is by finding a solution. The way to find a solution is to be logical.</p>

<p>Therefore, if you want to solve life’s problems, you need to be logical.</p>

<p>If you are logical, any situation you face could be solved.</p>

<p>This may be the reason why MBA graduates who were also engineers are preferred more than other MBA graduates. (By the way, the previous sentence was an appeal to Ethos)</p>

<p>If you want to make better decisions overall, you need Logos.</p>

<h2 id="ways-of-using-ethos-pathos-logos-framework">Ways of Using Ethos Pathos Logos Framework</h2>

<h3 id="not-getting-persuaded-easily-by-identifying-ethos-pathos-and-logos-in-an-argument-and-only-focusing-on-logos">Not getting persuaded easily by identifying ethos, pathos, and logos in an argument and only focusing on logos</h3>

<p>In an argument clearly distinguishes ethos, pathos and logos.</p>

<p>And then focus on the logos.</p>

<p>For example, suppose someone tells you not do to things a certain way. You ask a logos question like why? The answer you get is I said so which is an ethos answer.</p>

<p>Logos is truth. Truth cannot hurt you. Truth only leads to clarity. Therefore, Logos can’t hurt you and it will lead you to clarity.</p>

<h3 id="persuading-and-helping-people-better-by-understanding-the-situation-through-the-lens-of-rhetoric">Persuading and helping people better by understanding the situation through the lens of rhetoric.</h3>

<p>Suppose someone is trying to help you, but the help they offer is stupid. Many times we just dismiss the help. But we can and I believe it’s much better to help them form their arguments.</p>

<p>You can let them know that you understand they want the best for you (ethos), and you understand their sentiment (pathos) and you respect it (again pathos), and then you explain/ask them how their idea may not be ideal or maybe improved (logos).</p>

<h3 id="developing-a-better-personality-by-incorporating-all-three">Developing a better personality by incorporating all three</h3>

<p>We should develop a personality that encompasses all three.</p>

<p>If you are good with logic (logos), but are terrible at ethos and pathos. Then you should focus on the other two. Because even if your arguments are “logically” correct, you are unable to present them properly.</p>

<p>Similarly, if people listen to your and follow your advice i.e you have ethos, but your advice is terrible, you should focus on developing your logos.</p>

<p>Develop and incorporate all three.</p>

<h3 id="skipping-politics-misunderstandings-ego-games-and-status-games-by-always-focusing-on-logos">Skipping politics, misunderstandings, ego games, and status games by always focusing on logos</h3>

<p>Status games are all ethos and pathos. Avoid status games. I have skipped a lot of office politics by focusing my arguments only on work and not the person.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Focus on the problem. Not the person.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Sometimes you will make people hurt, but as long as you are focusing on logos, it may not matter all the much how they feel in this moment. And similarly, it may not matter how you feel at this moment.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-technical" /><category term="truth" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ethos, Pathos and Logos are techniques of persuasion. But are applications of it in making clear decisions and better interpersonal dynamics, especially in high-emotion situations.]]></summary></entry></feed>