<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-20T11:23:55-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush Choubey</title><subtitle>Full Stack Developer - Cloud/Microservices</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Living a truthful life</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Living a truthful life" /><published>2022-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/truth">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mountain-of-perspectives-what-is-true&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mountain of Perspectives&lt;/strong&gt;: What is true?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a 3 dimensional landscape. There are multiple people in it. And their are multiple mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These mountains are truths. Some mountain are tall. Some are short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are distributed accross the terrain. Some can see one mountain clearly. Some can’t. Some can see some part of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this terrain, if someone is tied, fog appears and they can’t see the mountain clearly at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore ultimately, we find that there’s no one mountain. What’s truth for one person may not be true for other. And the interpretation of what’s true may change as more information is gathered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be tricky when you first start with telling the truth. But you’ll get the hang of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-should-you-do-to-seek-truth&quot;&gt;What should you do to seek truth?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can control a few variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hold your opinions lightly and examine them regularly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Filter out Logical Fallacies. Fallacies are very easier to spot and you’ll sharpen your arguments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask good questions that aren’t biased.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask other’s for advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;still-not-convinced-why-we-should-always-strive-to-tell-the-truth&quot;&gt;Still not convinced? Why we should always strive to tell the truth?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living and speaking your truth makes you free&lt;/strong&gt;: Why lie when you can tell the truth and be free? And it will make things better? That’s double bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telling the truth is acceptance of how things actually are&lt;/strong&gt;: We are always asked to accept reality as it is. Acceptance helps us get clearer helping us make better decisions and avoid traps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth always comes in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;: No matter what you do, truth will eventually come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your body can feel when you are lying&lt;/strong&gt;.: When you lie or do something that is not truthful, your body reacts. Let’s say you hate something and you are not saying it. You’ll develop resentment and stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If we are not truthful, someone else will suffer&lt;/strong&gt;: The cost of lying isn’t something we always bear in the short term. Sometimes it’s others. Suppose you go to a doctor, and he doesn’t tell you that you might be in serious risk of a deadly disease and that now is a good time to avoid drinking? What impact would it have on you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Living and speaking truthfully orients you properly&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t lie, you’ll hesitant to slack of at work if you want to face daily standup the next day. Thus, orienting you to become a better person and get work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t live a lie, you won’t cheat on exams. This will orient you properly to become the kind of person that will pass the exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-we-usually-avoid-telling-the-truth-and-what-we-can-do-about-it&quot;&gt;How we usually avoid telling the truth and what we can do about it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;White Lies&lt;/strong&gt;: We should instead be as kind as possible but not lie. It’s important to recognize that white lies backfire bigger than just speaking the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-zero-trust-catching-lies-liars-and-protecting-yourself&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;: Zero Trust: Catching lies, liars and protecting yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liars can wrap you and your world view to get what they want. They often go un-noticed. They are like successful social black-hat hackers. You need good security to protect yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flash&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg class=&quot;octicon octicon-info octicon octicon-info octicon octicon-info octicon octicon-info octicon octicon-info octicon octicon-info octicon octicon-info&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M8 1.5a6.5 6.5 0 100 13 6.5 6.5 0 000-13zM0 8a8 8 0 1116 0A8 8 0 010 8zm6.5-.25A.75.75 0 017.25 7h1a.75.75 0 01.75.75v2.75h.25a.75.75 0 010 1.5h-2a.75.75 0 010-1.5h.25v-2h-.25a.75.75 0 01-.75-.75zM8 6a1 1 0 100-2 1 1 0 000 2z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Note: &lt;/strong&gt;There is a difference between not knowing the truth
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need zero trust. Zero trust that has 3 ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-truth/zero-trust.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zero Trust&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;Toast&quot;&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;Toast-icon&quot;&gt;&lt;svg class=&quot;octicon octicon-info&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M8 1.5a6.5 6.5 0 100 13 6.5 6.5 0 000-13zM0 8a8 8 0 1116 0A8 8 0 010 8zm6.5-.25A.75.75 0 017.25 7h1a.75.75 0 01.75.75v2.75h.25a.75.75 0 010 1.5h-2a.75.75 0 010-1.5h.25v-2h-.25a.75.75 0 01-.75-.75zM8 6a1 1 0 100-2 1 1 0 000 2z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;Toast-content&quot;&gt;Zero Trust is a concept in computer security used to protect distributed systems in cloud infrastructure. We can apply the same concepts to regular life.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verify Explicitly&lt;/strong&gt;: Have explicit systems to verify if what is spoken is true. Pull out your logical fallacies and cognitive bias lists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Least Privilage&lt;/strong&gt;: You don’t have to say everything to everyone. Only give people as much access as they need. They don’t need everything. They don’t need your full self. Your family needs your full self, not others. You need to be assertive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assume Breach&lt;/strong&gt;: Assume the person you are talking to has tendency to lie. Or atleast has tendency to speak truthfully as deligently as you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catching a liar&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lies are oversimplistic and tend to change overtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The liar has to keep a narrative of manything that aren’t true.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When pressed, they may try to blame on something else or bring up a totally irrelavent topic to distract us or place a straw man.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They won’t be specific.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They may twist their words slightly to fit their lie into truth. At such moments, note if they have a motivated reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you confront a liar? Depends on how serious the lie was?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flash flash-success&quot;&gt;
    &lt;svg class=&quot;octicon octicon-checklist octicon octicon-checklist octicon octicon-checklist&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M2.5 1.75a.25.25 0 01.25-.25h8.5a.25.25 0 01.25.25v7.736a.75.75 0 101.5 0V1.75A1.75 1.75 0 0011.25 0h-8.5A1.75 1.75 0 001 1.75v11.5c0 .966.784 1.75 1.75 1.75h3.17a.75.75 0 000-1.5H2.75a.25.25 0 01-.25-.25V1.75zM4.75 4a.75.75 0 000 1.5h4.5a.75.75 0 000-1.5h-4.5zM4 7.75A.75.75 0 014.75 7h2a.75.75 0 010 1.5h-2A.75.75 0 014 7.75zm11.774 3.537a.75.75 0 00-1.048-1.074L10.7 14.145 9.281 12.72a.75.75 0 00-1.062 1.058l1.943 1.95a.75.75 0 001.055.008l4.557-4.45z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Tip: &lt;/strong&gt;Stay away from people who explicitly lie or have manipulative behavior.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gain perspectives&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a good social connections, you’ll eventually know many common lies that other’s face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books like 48 Laws of Power and Law of Human Nature are also helpful here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementing-truth&quot;&gt;Implementing Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s easier to stop lying than it is to tell the truth&lt;/strong&gt;: Because most times you don’t know what truth is. So, if you stop lying, you eliminate almost everything. What remains is as true as things can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practicing speaking the truth as clearly as you can&lt;/strong&gt;: Take a step back and think through if what you are saying is truth. Truth is clear and precise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be able to search for the truth, you have to think. To think, &lt;strong&gt;you have to risk being offensive&lt;/strong&gt; sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to speak the truth, &lt;strong&gt;you have to give up on what you want&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell the truth + be useful&lt;/strong&gt;: You can always laugh. Panic is no good. Seeking truth is difficult when you are in panic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-flavours-of-truth-that-we-fail-to-accept&quot;&gt;Optional: Flavours of Truth That We Fail to Accept&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data&lt;/strong&gt;: Data can be in many forms. It can be text/numbers from a system or it can be observation from a real event. If you can’t see someone is continously treating you badly, you should accept that they treat you improperly. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rejection&lt;/strong&gt;: Rejection is a truth. No matter at what stage it is. This could be failure in an exam or a failure of relationship. The most rational thing to do here is to accept the rejection and move on. This acceptance is the acceptance of truth. Once we do accept it, we’ll be able to rethink things though and move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Desires&lt;/strong&gt;: We try not to accept our desires. Maybe you wanna have sex badly but you force yourself not to think about it. Thus this thought becomes your new prison. Instead, you can accept this fact and find a healthier alternative than to watch porn :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-nuances-about-truth&quot;&gt;Optional: Nuances about Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t be idealistic be realist&lt;/strong&gt;. Being ideastic is great for personal discipline. Bt specially with others it becomes too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth is good. But Panic is No Good&lt;/strong&gt;: You have to learn to be calm. And specially making someone else panic is no good. We are more likely to create something outof nothing when we panic. In that sense, we are creating truth from a lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belief presupposes truth&lt;/strong&gt;: Knock on the door and the door shall open. If you knock the right doo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-truth-and-other-concepts&quot;&gt;Optional: Truth and Other Concepts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ego&lt;/strong&gt;: Ego stops us from getting to the truth. To avoid ego, hold your opinions lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biases&lt;/strong&gt;: Biases are blindspots we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth and Good are tied&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are asked if you should lie for the greater good? And you say yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe, you are on the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truth and Peace are tied&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closer you are the truth. The more peaceful you are inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-resources&quot;&gt;Optional: Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EfEK-Pmi7v0&quot;&gt;Jordan Peterson - First stop lying, then speak your truth - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="truth" /><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Designing and implementing a Morning and Night Rituals for optimal life</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/morning-night-ritual" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing and implementing a Morning and Night Rituals for optimal life" /><published>2022-12-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-morning-night-ritual</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/morning-night-ritual">&lt;h1 id=&quot;designing-a-morning-and-night-ritual-for-optimal-life&quot;&gt;Designing a Morning and Night Ritual for optimal life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-morning-and-night-rituals-are-essential-why-they-arent-replaceable-by-mid-day-activity&quot;&gt;Why morning and night rituals are essential? Why they aren’t replaceable by mid-day activity?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morning and Night are essential time because they provide the start and end to the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By starting the day of right, we can increase the probability of having a good day. By ending the day right, we can increase the probability of having a good next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning and the nights can be well planned and be more structured than  mid days where plans have to adopt day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this stability provided by a stable structure, they can become essential tools to take care of our needs, reset and work on long-term goals which we miss in daily mid-day planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning and nights are more personal and handled individually than mid days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-plan-your-morning-and-night-ritual&quot;&gt;How to plan your morning and night ritual?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the 3 parts we need to plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Morning should provide a jump start to the day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A good night sleep should be in adequote amount  and provide essential rest and relaxation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Night ritual: Should prepare us to have a good next day and ease in the process towards relaxation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here my take on how to plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;morning&quot;&gt;Morning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wake up at least 1.5 hours before&lt;/strong&gt; you have to be out or before a computer screen. This will give you an ample time to start day off right and not rush. In case you woke up late or have less time on hand, you can do as many things as time allows. No need to rush.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make bed&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure it’s reset so that when you come back it’s perfect. This carries our organization that you did last night. Remember, bed is only for sleeping and fucking.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take care of Hygiene&lt;/strong&gt;. Drink Water. Poop. Brush. Wash Face. Sit for 20 minutes. You want to sit only once in a day right? Don’t bring your phone. You likely have unprocessed thoughts from the good night sleep you had. And you have a good space to pause and reflect. :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go out in the sun&lt;/strong&gt;. Sun is vital for our body. It improves your mood, produces more testosterone, manages circadian rhythm and helps you sleep better at night. Therefore, get as much sunlight as possible. It’s better to the rest of the activities in sun. Expose as much of your skin to the sun as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt;. It can be little. 5-6 minutes. Or the 7-minute workout. Just get yourself moving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you can &lt;strong&gt;g&lt;/strong&gt;o have a shower**. hot+cold bath. Relax your body. And get dressed and sharp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post-exercise your mind is likely active and with bath and being properly dressed, it’s ready to be sharpened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read and reflect&lt;/strong&gt;. Read about 10-20 minutes of something that you are reading. This is non-fiction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditate&lt;/strong&gt;. This can be guided. Make yourself calmer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you can take 2 minutes of break like you do at the gym and look at the well planned day you set last night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sleep&quot;&gt;Sleep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aim to have 8 hour of bed time. So, it you are going to start your work at 9, you wake up 1.5 hours before at 7:30. And you have your sleep for around 8 hours so 11:30 bed time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to have a relaxing sleep to start next day right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;night&quot;&gt;Night&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like morning, start your night ritual at 1.5 hours before bed minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activities we have at night are all of relaxing nature.  It also serves as a place to handle small things that we won’t have to think about in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If dinner at your home is prepared by someone else, you can adjust activities in this list. Just make sure it’s consistent and stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean up your room&lt;/strong&gt;. So that it’s organized. You want to have your environment reset.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have dinner with family&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the place you can put your phone is airplane mode or turn off internet on a minimum. This time is a good time to bond with family and catchup over the day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a walk outside alone&lt;/strong&gt;. You can spend around 20-30 minutes. It’s a great place to rewind and reflect and walking would also help your with digestion post dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan your 3 MITs&lt;/strong&gt; Most Important Things for the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout clothes and pack your bags&lt;/strong&gt; for tomorrow. This will help you be sharper. Looking and feeling sharp increases your performance. You can also get a shave if you need to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now that it’s the end of the day, you might wanna &lt;strong&gt;clear out all your thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;. Nights are a great place for writing. Mornings are great for editing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fill in 5-minute journal&lt;/strong&gt;. This should serve as a reset to end your day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dim your lights&lt;/strong&gt;. Make sure the room is cold.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sleep&lt;/strong&gt;. You can use deep breathing to help ease into sleeping. While trying to sleep, along with deep breaths you might reflect on your day. Think about next or talk. It’s your space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace of 8 hours of sleep. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember this, morning, sleep and nights are sacred and they need to be protected, prioritized and planned well. The result is a 20x increase in effectiveness and consistency towards optimal performance. So, this time isn’t wasted, it’s invested with a much higher return on investment than anything that happens mid-day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="time" /><summary type="html">Designing a Morning and Night Ritual for optimal life</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My experience working with MongoDB</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/sql-and-no-sql" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My experience working with MongoDB" /><published>2022-12-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-sql-no-sql</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/sql-and-no-sql">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-sql-and-no-sql/header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Header&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to work with SQL in the past. Nowadays I have been working with MongoDB. Here has been my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nosql-is-simple&quot;&gt;NoSQL is simple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NoSQL is much much more simpler than SQL. There are no need for multiple table. You can just nexts documents into one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless something is an actual needs to be treated like Entity, you don’t need a separate table/collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no need to go write a separate create query. Just push something to the DB and it gets saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference here is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SQL works on concept of schema on write. The data needs to have a particular schema.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NoSQL works on Schema on read. The data can be with any format, but it’s job of reader to intepret it the way it wants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like working with file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-integrities-and-foreign-keys&quot;&gt;What about integrities and foreign keys?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These maybe important for certain applications. But for most the simplicity of NoSQL is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For NoSQL, the backend-application which is responsible doing operations on the DB is the one than maintains the DB state. If you really need foreign key like constraint, you can just code it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;browsing-data&quot;&gt;Browsing Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browing a JSON document store is painful in tree view. This is because you have to expand out each row to see what’s in it. If you are using a NoSQL database, still use the table view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The painful tree view&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-sql-and-no-sql/tree-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tree View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table view&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-sql-and-no-sql/table-view.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Table View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://studio3t.com/knowledge-base/articles/table-view/#restore-default-view&quot;&gt;Image source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="database" /><category term="no-sql" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-sql-and-no-sql/header.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-sql-and-no-sql/header.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Actually solve the problem.</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/actually-solve-the-problem" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Actually solve the problem." /><published>2022-12-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-solve-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/actually-solve-the-problem">&lt;h2 id=&quot;people&quot;&gt;People&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s with people  who try to ease situations without ever solving the problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like “Oh tumhara maan nahi hai? Maat karo”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English: “You don’t wanna do it? Don’t do it”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like what the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh you don’t feel okay.” Just rest. Keep resting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if it solves the problem. 🤷🏽‍♂️ The problem remains, and just takes a different form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;life-is-full-of-difficulties&quot;&gt;Life is full of difficulties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In relationship, there are times when one or both parties have fears stopping them. It’s easy for one of them to back off. Maybe they are anxious or avoidant. It’s like, does it solve the problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, the problem remains. The next relationship, they go to, they’ll face the same problem.
Then when should change path&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One Jordan Peterson criteria is: If the other path is harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brain will try to default to easy path. If the other path is harder. Then you should take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also say that, find good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: Not moving out of India because you are scared. Doesn’t solve the problem. You shouldn’t be scared. Go move out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-you-face-the-dragon-the-dragon-becomes-smaller&quot;&gt;When you face the dragon, the dragon becomes smaller&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are not willing to face what you want to face, the problem becomes bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you face what you are afraid of head on. Looking the dragon in the eye, the size of the dragon decreases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uS8NNkt3Q9I?controls=0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-like-damn-life-is-full-of-suffering-but-you-are-stronger&quot;&gt;It’s like damn, life is full of suffering. But you are stronger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is full of suffering. But that’s if you believe it so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you tune your perspectives, life is full of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And each challenge you face, you become stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you become stronger, it’s fun and amazing. You have become an hero of some kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid of challenges. Face them head-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually solve the problem you are facing to the best of your ability. You’ll get stronger!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="responsibility" /><summary type="html">People</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i0.wp.com/halflinghobbies.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hho_dragon.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i0.wp.com/halflinghobbies.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/hho_dragon.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do I write?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/why-i-write" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do I write?" /><published>2022-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-15T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-why-i-write</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/why-i-write">&lt;p&gt;Writing clarifies my thought more than anything. It converts chaos into an order of some kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The better I write and explain, the better I get at solving interpersonal problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing protects me against the Dunning-Krugger effect. The effect is where one has learned a bunch of things but isn’t aware that he knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because writing builds up documentation of progress. It’s something that I can look back on and derive insights and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing serves as a public view of my knowledge and ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It serves as a great self-promotion on a resume and during job interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own writing provides a fall back for my future self when re-learning or making important decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-why-i-write.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Why I write?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@aaronburden?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Aaron Burden&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/writing?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="non-professional" /><summary type="html">Writing clarifies my thought more than anything. It converts chaos into an order of some kind.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-why-i-write.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-why-i-write.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keep messages unread</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/messages-unread" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep messages unread" /><published>2022-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-15T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-unread</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/messages-unread">&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to read every message, every email, every notification and every new video you receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life gets calmer once you relax and let some things be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why rush? When you can just wait for things to collect and then read all of them at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try the switch and see within a month, how many unwanted things you were putting your attention to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="peace" /><category term="non-professional" /><summary type="html">You don’t need to read every message, every email, every notification and every new video you receive.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-why-i-write.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-why-i-write.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Adapting to Project Reactor / Webflux Mindset</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/webflux-mindset" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adapting to Project Reactor / Webflux Mindset" /><published>2022-12-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-15T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-adapting-to-reactor-mindset</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/webflux-mindset">&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-using-block-the-event-loop&quot;&gt;No using .block() the event loop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-you-are-going-to-block-block-it-the-reactive-way&quot;&gt;If you are going to block, block it the reactive way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;methods-should-always-return-a-mono-or-flux&quot;&gt;Methods should always return a Mono or Flux&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until something is part of the return chain tree, it won’t be executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-monoerror-instead-of-throwing&quot;&gt;Use Mono.error() instead of throwing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mono methods should not throw anything&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-java highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;flatmap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pojo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;throw&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;RunTimeException&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;})&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-java highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;flatMap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pojo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Mono&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;RuntimeException&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-monofromfuture-to-convert-from-completablefuture-to-mono&quot;&gt;Use Mono.fromFuture to convert from CompletableFuture to Mono&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-collectlist-only-when-needed&quot;&gt;use .collectList() only when needed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-keep-things-within-mono-flux-chain&quot;&gt;Always keep things within mono flux chain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to hold on to a previous mono flatMap return is nested mono, flux call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But try to keep things as flat as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="concurrency" /><summary type="html">No using .block() the event loop</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Implementation GDPR - Download and Delete A Users Data in Microservice World</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/gdpr" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Implementation GDPR - Download and Delete A Users Data in Microservice World" /><published>2022-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-08T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-gdpr</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/gdpr">&lt;p&gt;Implementing GDPR-compliant microservices to get all user data and delete a user’s data can seem very hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I think it’s way too easy to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach described below can work at the enterprise level for enterprise apps. Just replace &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;enterprise&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{userId}&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{enterpriseId}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-gdpr.png&quot; alt=&quot;GDPR Implementation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, we can it in 4 steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every data record should have &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{userId}&lt;/code&gt; indexed. Even messaging services like Kafka with a database backup should be indexed. Even storage services like S3 be segregated as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{userId}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have all microservices have a DELETE &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/gdpr/user/{userId}&lt;/code&gt; endpoint: This endpoint hard deletes all user’s data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have all microservices have a GET &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/gdpr/user/{userId}&lt;/code&gt; endpoint: This endpoint returns all data from a user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have an orchestrator GDPR microservice: This will call all other microservices for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/gdpr/user/{userId}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case of getting data, it will collect all the data, upload it at some location for a certain number of days and notify the user about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact same interface is needed to hard delete data from backend ups as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: none&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mermaid&quot; src=&quot;https://mermaid.ink/svg/eyJjb2RlIjoiZ3JhcGggTFJcbmFbZmE6ZmEtc2VydmVyIEdEUFIgXFxuICpPcmNoZXN0cmF0b3IqIFxcbiBNaWNyb3NlcnZpY2VdIC0tPiB8XCJERUxFVEUgL2dkcHIvdXNlcnMve3VzZXJJZH0gXFxuIEdFVCAvZ2Rwci91c2Vycy97dXNlcklkfVwifCBNMVtmYTpmYS1zZXJ2ZXIgTWljcm9zZXJ2aWNlIEFdXG5NMSAtLT4gfFwiUGFydGl0aW9uIG9uIHt1c2VySWR9XCJ8IE0xXG5hIC0tPiB8XCJERUxFVEUgL2dkcHIvdXNlcnMve3VzZXJJZH0gXFxuIEdFVCAvZ2Rwci91c2Vycy97dXNlcklkfVwifCBNMltmYTpmYS1zZXJ2ZXIgTWljcm9zZXJ2aWNlIEJdXG5NMiAtLT4gfFwiUGFydGl0aW9uIG9uIHt1c2VySWR9XCJ8IE0yXG5hIC0tPiB8RGVsZXRlIGRhdGF8IENbZmE6ZmEtZGF0YWJhc2UgQmFja3Vwc11cbkMgLS0-IHxcIlBhcnRpdGlvbiBvbiB7dXNlcklkfVwifCBDIiwibWVybWFpZCI6bnVsbH0&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><category term="compliance" /><category term="system-design" /><summary type="html">Implementing GDPR-compliant microservices to get all user data and delete a user’s data can seem very hard.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-gdpr.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-gdpr.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Developing better self-awareness with QuantifiedSelf - Observability for personal life.</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/quantified-self" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developing better self-awareness with QuantifiedSelf - Observability for personal life." /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-quantified-self</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/quantified-self">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-mean-by-the-observability-of-personal-life&quot;&gt;What do I mean by the Observability of personal life?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantified self means tracking certain things in our life so that we can make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These decisions are made so that we can course-correct them if we are straining away from something important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And therefore, it would make us more self-aware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-we-need-it&quot;&gt;Why do we need it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our fast-paced world, we take on too many things at once. We are constantly distracted by attention-seeking entities like marketing companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this, we forget the take care of the most important person we know. Us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the problem lies in just taking care of ourselves enough. But it’s way more helpful to have proactive systems in place. So that we are guided towards taking care of ourselves. Therefore, this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-we-do-to-implement-it&quot;&gt;What can we do to implement it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before implementation details, it’s important to determine a few factors first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The goal is to make more informed decisions. The goal is not to distract us.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We must live a balanced life: healthy, wealthy and wise. Or you could say, healthier, wealthier and wiser. All aspects, not just one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, each day may not be perfect. And we need certain randomness in place for the best decision to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being too perfect will lead to anxiety. And as we already know: #PanicIsNoGood (Zeus from Thor: Love and Thunder).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some I tried to implement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-your-healthy&quot;&gt;Track your healthy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check your weight over time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need not be perfect every day and can be random, just over time. Being too perfect is good for the short term when u want to improve something, but not good for the long term as it leads to anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regularly get preventative body checkups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a year or once every two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-your-time&quot;&gt;Track your time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life cycle app&lt;/strong&gt;: Automated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shows how much time you spent and where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/lifecycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lifecycle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://northcube.com/&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screentime&lt;/strong&gt;: Automated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phones do come with apps that make you more aware of the time you have spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/screentime1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screentime1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/screentime2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screentime2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome Extensions&lt;/strong&gt;: MindHero: Automated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracks time spent on websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/mind-hero.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mind Hero&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mindhero/opjbphlikplllhehiaafnglngompagni&quot;&gt;MindHero - Chrome Web Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wakatime.com/&quot;&gt;WakaTime - Dashboards for developers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be mindful of how much time you spend attentive with family&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Family is the most important part of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-your-memories&quot;&gt;Track your memories&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photographs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diary writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal diary to write down thoughts and other entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-your-money&quot;&gt;Track your money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CRED App&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In India, CRED app gives accurate summary of credit card info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/cred.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CRED&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-your-writing&quot;&gt;Track your writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grammarly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grammarly also publishes a weekly email with insights about your writing. It also suggests improvements that can be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/grammarly1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grammarly1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-quantified-self/grammarly2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grammarly2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-decisions&quot;&gt;Making decisions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t check the data every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most apps allow for useful prompts and summaries that can be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-limitations&quot;&gt;What are the limitations?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//TODO&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><summary type="html">What do I mean by the Observability of personal life?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do microservices need an API client sdk for HTTP and Messaging?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/api-client-sdk" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do microservices need an API client sdk for HTTP and Messaging?" /><published>2022-12-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-03T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-api-client</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/api-client-sdk">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-api-client/header.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amazon SDK&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Amazon SDK&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-microservice-usage-ramp-up&quot;&gt;How does microservice usage ramp up?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microservice usage scales very fast. At first, a single service is the APIs. Suddenly there is a bunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each implements the same methods to access the same rest APIs. Each one of them would implement contract testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a wasted effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-api-client/without-api-client.png&quot; alt=&quot;Without API Client&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;api-client-sdk&quot;&gt;API Client SDK&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can, as an alternative, create one client code and let everyone use it. Or one client in each programming language that uses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us the following advantage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only the client code deals with the format of the API.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only the client code needs to be contract tested.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the endpoints of the API change, only the client code needs to be changed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We can create a single @Value for the base URL for the client and inject it via a config server for all applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we need to add micrometer-prometheus usage metrics for an API, we have one destination.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we need to retire an API, we just add @deprecated and release the client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client would also include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Request validation: To avoid unnecessary network calls.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Request Body POJOs: So that everyone uses the same format.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Response Body POJOs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standard Exception handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-api-client/api-client.png&quot; alt=&quot;Without API Client&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;message-client&quot;&gt;Message client&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same can be used for messaging like Kafka, where the client can include POJOs format and methods to publish messages in case of incoming webhooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, an API client would help reduce the efforts of all developers in developing and using an API. The developers using the client need not be concerned with how the API works internally, weather it works on REST, Graph QL, gRPC, etc. They just need to send and receive data in using the right client provided POJOs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="microservices" /><category term="distributed-systems" /><summary type="html">Amazon SDK</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-api-client/header.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-api-client/header.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>