<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-11T02:13:45-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush Choubey</title><subtitle>Full Stack Developer - Cloud/Microservices</subtitle><entry><title type="html">RSA Algorithm</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/rsa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RSA Algorithm" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-rsa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/rsa">&lt;p&gt;RSA is an asymmetric key encryption algorithm and was first published in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSA was created by Ron Rivest, Adi Shamir and Leonard Adleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-rsa/rsa-creators.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding their photo for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSA works on the concept of modular arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In RSA, we have a public and a private key. We use the private key to decrypt and the public key to encrypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that the private key should not be shared. But the public key can be shared with anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private Key = Key
Public Key = Lock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 5 steps in RSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take two prime numbers p and q. (Eg: p=2, q=7)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; . &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; is the product of p and q. (N = p*q = 2*7 = 14)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(N)&lt;/code&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is the number of co-primes less than N. (Eg. 1, 2, 5, 7 and 11 are co-primes to 14; therefore &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(n)&lt;/code&gt;  is the count = 6)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This can also be calculated with a formula &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(p-1)(q-1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eg; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(N)&lt;/code&gt;  = (2-1)(7-1) = 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the public key (e) such that&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 &amp;lt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;  &amp;lt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(N)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E should be co-prime with Phi(N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eg. e = 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the private key (d) such that&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(e*d) mod &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(n)&lt;/code&gt; = 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eg: (5*d) mod (14) = 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you calculate this you’ll see a pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5*1 = 5; mod 6 =  5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5*2 = 10; mod 6 = 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 mod 6 = 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 mod 6 = 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 mod 6 = 0
This pattern is expected since (5*6)%6 will be 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s pick a large &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;D = 11&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to encrypt you’ll do the following,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(value^e) mod N
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To decrypt, you’ll do the following,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(encryptedValue ^d) mod N
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4zahvcJ9glg&quot;&gt;Eddie Woo: The RSA Encryption Algorithm (1 of 2: Computing an Example)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oOcTVTpUsPQ&quot;&gt;The RSA Encryption Algorithm (2 of 2: Generating the Keys)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.drexel.edu/~jpopyack/IntroCS/HW/RSAWorksheet.html&quot;&gt;RSA Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><summary type="html">RSA is an asymmetric key encryption algorithm and was first published in 1977.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-rsa/rsa-creators.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-rsa/rsa-creators.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/traditional-roles" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant?" /><published>2023-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-31T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-traditional-roles</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/traditional-roles">&lt;p&gt;What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant?
In a world of narcissist, nihilism, pleasure, many are tempted to believe that this is all life has to offer. That’s until they decide to take responsibility. They stop being all talk, and convert their potential to actuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along that path comes a point. What to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have already covered needs. One of two types of responsibility a human should adopt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will provide a guide to need to do i.e. duties. Duties are traditional synonym for responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-we-should-look-at-traditional-roles&quot;&gt;Why we should look at traditional roles?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more you look at the history and the past, the more you can see the future.
~ Winston Churchil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that have worked for a numbers of years have value in them. It’s not always the case that what’s new has value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our case, around 100 years ago, most of humanity lived under extreme poverty. So, before 100 years ago, most humans were adapted to a world where they had to work on their duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these times, each person tried to adapt to their best skill. And similarly, men and women adapted to the skill that suited them the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men are usually stronger physically. This made them good at jobs like being a soldier and building buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women are usually physically less strong and have a kind nature. This made them good at caring, managing households.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both men and women worked together to build our modern world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing was that they “had” to do their duties and as well as possible. In the modern world, most duties have become optional or are at least perceived to be optional. This optionality results in a lack of purpose for most people. People don’t know what to do. So they opt for what’s available, momentary pleasure and are in a pit of nihilism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pre-modern world provides a much much better alternative. Traditional roles provides the purpose of life that modern alternatives do not. Even if you are modern, if you feel lost then start here with the traditional. Then adapt your plans overtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementing-the-traditional-roles&quot;&gt;Implementing The Traditional Roles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before jumping further, here is the mindset you should develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with at least what’s your strength, if you are masculine, pick traditional masculine duties first. If you are feminine, pick traditionally feminine duties first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are set in one role, start picking up things from the other role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no-problem in picking being caring as a man or being a provider as a women. But try starting with your duties first as these may come much more naturally to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;duties-of-a-man&quot;&gt;Duties of a man&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A man has three duties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem Solve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you were living in a jungle in 1600s, what would you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would provide for your family, protect them from dangerous and solve problems like shelter by building a house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To provide&lt;/strong&gt;, a man must be useful enough. In the modern world being useful enough means providing the world what it wants. #capatalism (I love capitalism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To protect&lt;/strong&gt;, a man must be strong physically and must be strong mentally to face the problems that come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the modern world, there seems to be no-need for such strength, but it seems useless not to have such physical and mental strength. This conclusion is because we still have protection duties. Going down an alley and a thief with a knife shows up. What would you do? Would you panic or would you handle the situation calmly. Therefore, a man must develop his physical body well to be useful in any situation and his mental strength as well so that he can face obstacles that come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To problem solve&lt;/strong&gt;, a man must be learn, not give up and be-humble enough to adapt to the situations. Many times this means facing the void of not knowing anything, but trying anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;duties-of-a-women&quot;&gt;Duties of a women&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A women has three duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nurture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="responsibility" /><summary type="html">What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant? In a world of narcissist, nihilism, pleasure, many are tempted to believe that this is all life has to offer. That’s until they decide to take responsibility. They stop being all talk, and convert their potential to actuality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to plan mid-day?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/plan-mid-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to plan mid-day?" /><published>2023-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-plan-mid-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/plan-mid-day">&lt;p&gt;The mid day is the time where you can be the most active. This is ideally, 1.5 hours after waking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make mid day a success, it’s best to have completed the morning ritual. If the morning ritual is not complete find the best parts of the morning ritual to complete. The morning ritual can provide you with great focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as part of night ritual, your room and setup might already be clean and ready to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you can divide the mid-day into two parts—first half and second half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half is pre-lunch. This is where you’ll likely be the most active. Fix your lunch time to around 1:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daily standup starts at 9. And I pay attention to it. It’s a great time for me to learn what’s happening in the team and note down concepts that I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spend time learning a few minutes glancing at things I don’t know. And discussing any impediments I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can work between 10 to 1. 3 hours. This would include a 2 hours pomodoro sprint. This activity is chosen carefully and is a part where no learning is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I need to learn something, I can watch youtube videos or open up documentation. But remember this time is protected. No one should distract me between 10 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="time" /><category term="planning" /><summary type="html">The mid day is the time where you can be the most active. This is ideally, 1.5 hours after waking up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I use ChatGPT as an AI Assist?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/chatgpt-assist" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I use ChatGPT as an AI Assist?" /><published>2023-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-how-i-use-chatgpt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/chatgpt-assist">&lt;p&gt;I have also been thinking about AI Assist. ChatGPT is too good and it can help me with a lot of things. For instance,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finding improvements to my blog. “How can I improve: {text}”. I might also add in more context: “Make this more professional: {text}”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is what I used yesterday to improve my LinkedIn bio and description. It was too baby like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be an excellent first, reviewer. And reduce feedback time by a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main way I want to use it is to teach me rather than do it itself. So, I would prefer the asking “How can I improve this text: {text}” over “Improve this: {text}?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because I want to be better myself. And not rely on an automated tool all the time. So, ChatGPT becomes a self improvement and clarity improvement and learning tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summarisation&quot;&gt;Summarisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ChatGPT can also summarise really well, and since I have really long blogposts and really long morning pages, I think that summarisation would make things really nice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe I can also have my week summarised by passing it my weekly journaling. The problem here is that I can’t pass private data, rather I should not pass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The summary feature is also available in Google Chat, where it summarizes the most useful points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explanation&quot;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can ask ChatGPT for explanation of things or for debugging. Finally, it is a corpus of entire human insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain me like I am 5 or comparing one thing to another on a particular aspect are excellent questions to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think AI is revolutionising us. This is really really huge. And I really love being a part of this. I totally understand, the disruption this is causing and going to cause is much much more than we anticipated, and it’s only going to get started. Jobs would evolve and have to evolve because that’s the only way to stay relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just 2023, what would happen in upcoming years? Damn. It’s a fun time to be alive.—So that was all about ChatGPT, I have asked it many personal questions that I wouldn’t have asked to anyone. And it has helped me a lot. Thank you OpenAI. I hope I can contribute to the world in as useful way and you do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="inputs" /><summary type="html">I have also been thinking about AI Assist. ChatGPT is too good and it can help me with a lot of things. For instance,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Desk Setup</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/desk-setup" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Desk Setup" /><published>2023-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-desk-setup</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/desk-setup">&lt;p&gt;This is how it should like like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-desk-setup/1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-desk-setup/2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-desk-setup/3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Books are divided into values, business and technical&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-desk-setup/4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Values books are in order. Left being truth. And rightmost being team work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-desk-setup/5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-desk-setup/6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="systems" /><category term="setup" /><summary type="html">This is how it should like like.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Blindspots</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/my-blindspots" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Blindspots" /><published>2023-01-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-my-blindspots</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/my-blindspots">&lt;h2 id=&quot;anxious-attachment&quot;&gt;Anxious Attachment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be very objective of what is actually happening if it is actually mutual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wc87y6an_g&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="truth" /><summary type="html">Anxious Attachment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Need for Optimizing Inputs in the Modern World</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/inputs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Need for Optimizing Inputs in the Modern World" /><published>2023-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-inputs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/inputs">&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-needs&quot;&gt;Human Needs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human beings and all other animals have needs. And these needs are what drive us to move. Unfulfilled needs lead to pain. And fulfilling that need reduces or mitigates that pain. We can call it pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pleasure can be big or small. But the main thing here is: Needs drive us to pursue a solution that would reduce pain and move us toward pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tradeoffs-between-different-solutions&quot;&gt;The tradeoffs between different solutions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everything, there are multiple solutions to a problem. Some solutions are better than others. Some solutions are readily available. Some solutions require effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our body, over a million years, has been adapted to respond to our environment and needs. A part of it is also repeated exposure and training. If the environment requires us to be stronger, like an instance where we are picking up a lot of weight. We become stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the environment no longer requires us to be stronger, the body will adapt and put its resources where they can be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change our body &amp;amp; mind goes through is proportional to the problem we are trying to solve. If we are trying to solve a harder problem, our body and mind will adapt more to solve the harder problem and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-modern-world&quot;&gt;The Modern World&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, there were many problems we faced that are solved now with advances by human civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, we were required to be strong and develop the skill of hunting, that got replaced when agriculture came along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, apart from feeling up time that was used during hunting, the second-order consequence of this is that we aren’t as strong as our ancestors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of this phenomenon in everything we input in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the input in our life requires or pushes us towards becoming better, we’ll respond to the environment by becoming better. Similarly, if input pushes us towards becoming worse, we become worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the model of hunting, inputs can sometimes be eliminated or replaced by other inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We face inputs all the time and more in the modern world. We can optimize our inputs so that the best ones stay and keep making us better. Over some time, we’ll find ourselves getting better and better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the upcoming series of posts, I’ll highlight how we can identify and eliminate negative inputs and find and incorporate positive ones. Doing so would make us smarter, faster, better, and more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="inputs" /><category term="mature" /><summary type="html">Human Needs</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start your project with Continuous Delivery till “PROD”</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/continuous-delivery" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start your project with Continuous Delivery till “PROD”" /><published>2023-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-continuous-delivery%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/continuous-delivery">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/continuous-delivery.png&quot; alt=&quot;Continuous Delivery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@ilumire?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Jelleke Vanooteghem&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/chuzevDl4qM?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software developers and businesses all around the world nag release. There is an emotional low and high point associate with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because till something is released, we developers secretly know the work we did isn’t bug free. We cut shortcuts to complete feature after feature and when it comes time to release, the emotional down starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is a cycle of Manual Deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-continuous-delivery/emotional cycle of manual delivery_.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: Atlassian (Linked below.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manual Deployment is a big deal for both developer and business. But there is a better alternative that forces developers and business to get more intentional and produce high quality work faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post talks about that process and why it’s needed. At the end of the post, you’ll find links to other blogs that can be useful read along with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;software-delivery-early-vs-late&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Delivery&lt;/strong&gt;: Early vs Late&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing for a project is delivery. Delivering a software early means it’s impact is early. Money now is better than money tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gist is one of the core principles of The Agile Manifesto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our highest priority is to satisfy the customer through early and continuous delivery of valuable software.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We often wait a long time before delivering a software. This include making sure all the features are developed and test. But the only step we actually need to deliver something is to put it on PROD. Most features aren’t related to deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phases-of-software-developement-zero-to-one-and-one-to-n-phase&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phases of Software Developement&lt;/strong&gt;: Zero-To-One and One-To-N phase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software development can be divided into to phrases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-To-One Phase&lt;/strong&gt;: This is where you create something new.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-To-N Phase&lt;/strong&gt;: This is where you work on top of what you created to enhance it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero-To-One phase is the delivers the gist of the project: The MVP. It solves the core problem customer faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero-To-One is the start of the project. It’s important to create a stable foundation here to ensure a high quality base. In terms of team allocation, you want to have your best developers working during this phase. (I’ll be writing more on team allocation later)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The One-to-N part is easier. You have something that works and you want to add a bunch of additional enhancements to it. If you had a good Zero-To-One phase, you have a stable base to build on. So for team allocation, you can have many begineer developers paired with a experienced developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-build-a-deployment-pipeline-first&quot;&gt;Why you should build a deployment pipeline first?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delivering a working software that solves customers problem is the most important task. You have to have infrastructure (server, DB, configuration, etc) ready and perfectly aligned. And there should be no issues between them. Many times this involves making code changes to adapt to the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not solve the most important task early?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early on, during the zero-to-one phase, the amount of code to manage is less. Therefore, you can make code adjust easily compared to later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nature of early project phase is largely learning and research. Therefore, there is enough time at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By having deployment solved. Whatever you code &amp;amp; commit next, can reach in the hands of customers the fastest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#eatThatFrog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, develop your delivery pipeline as soon as you scafforld (create the base) of your project. Step 2. Start using it. In most cases, once you only create this pipeline once and then update the pipeline as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;addressing-the-misnomer-of-deploying-this-early-to-prod-without-proper-testing-will-lead-to-low-quality&quot;&gt;Addressing the misnomer of “deploying this early to prod without ‘proper’ testing will lead to low quality”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common misnomer is that deploying to prod early will lead to low quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is the opposite: Having to deploy early and often means you are forced to improve your engineering process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means, developers are forced to be more intentional about what they work on, in what order and ensure highest quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a learning period in everything new we do. We can’t expect us or others to do something perfectly on the first try. But as we make mistakes, we create systems and processes that ensure the mistakes doesn’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continous delivery pipeline is comparable to TPS: Toyota Production System. Any mistake that is made is rectified by improving the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s say a team adopts continous delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On their first day, a developer commits and his code reaches from dev, qa, uat to PROD and users start using it. It so happened that their was a logical bug in the code deployed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rather than scraping the continous delivery pipeline, the team decides to find why the problem was caused and improve the pipeline. They find that the code quality itself was low and their were logical bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To fix this issue from happening in the future, the team adopted better engineering practices.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They add Sonar lint, a popular linter to quicky check and ensure code meets standard.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They also adopt TDD and enforced a rule that build passes only when the test coverage is 80%.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Now, the problem for fixed for life.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sonar Lint became a step in the delivery pipeline. And TDD became a habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time a developer comes and commits something, the stages in the delivery pipeline ensures that the code is deliverable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any problem we face should be solved via the delivery pipeline. Ideally, without any human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many things that can be the part of delivery pipeline. I’ll be adding more posts on this soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several practices that support a continuous delivery. Some include,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/atomic-commits&quot;&gt;atomic commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tdd&quot;&gt;TDD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/implementing-kanban&quot;&gt;the kanban&lt;/a&gt; pull system and walk-the-board-from-right strategy,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/feature-flagging&quot;&gt;feature-flagging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;#morePostsSoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional--why-not-having-a-delivery-pipeline-is-risky&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;:  Why not-having a delivery pipeline is risky?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous section we covered how quality improves with a continous delivery pipeline. Here are reason why the amount of risk of not having a continuous delivery pipeline is higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only PROD is the place where we can deliver and know what the real status of the deliver is. Not having something used by the users means you don’t know what the real impact of your software is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making enhancements on something that is not-delivered is largely futile. Discussion over thing that hasn’t been made isn’t the same as having discussion over something that is made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the project is de-prioritized, then all work is lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly for the joy of coding &amp;amp; committing something is only complete when having it reach prod as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-how-to-spot-fake-continuous-delivery&quot;&gt;Optional: How to spot fake continuous delivery?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continous Delivery means software is always in a releasable state to PROD.
This mean a each new commit is of highest quality and is releasable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies and teams I have talked to say they do continuous delivery but they don’t. Their defination is this: We deploy to our dev environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dev is not prod. #PRODisPROD Prod is where real users are. Prod is where value is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-your-first-delivery-would-be&quot;&gt;What your first delivery would be?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your first delivery would be likely something very small and unusable. &lt;a href=&quot;/atomic-commits&quot;&gt;An atomic commit&lt;/a&gt;. A un-responsive login page perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having something delivered to PROD, doesn’t mean it has to be available to general public to use. At this stage, you need &lt;a href=&quot;/feature-flagging&quot;&gt;feature flagging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One your software crosses the MVP mark, you can release the flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional-what-should-you-learn-to-make-a-delivery-pipeline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;: What should you learn to make a delivery pipeline?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connect with a DevOps person and collaborate to build the CI/CD pipeline. Try to learn from them how to make one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that’s not possible, learn a CI/CD tool. Jenkins is a common one. Other popular ones include Gitlab CI and GitHub Actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If time is in a crunch, make simple bash scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, this was the sort of script I created because I didn’t understand how to do something in Jenkins. The files below are not real, they are illustrations of what I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;script-create-env.sh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; “Enter ENV name”
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;read &lt;/span&gt;end
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;destinationTool&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; init “APPNAME-&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ENV&lt;/span&gt;”
// other commands on &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;destinationTool&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
npm run build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;script-deploy.sh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; “Enecho “Enter ENV name”
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;read &lt;/span&gt;end
npm run push &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$ENV&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-from-other-articles&quot;&gt;Notes from other articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-case-for-continuous-delivery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thoughtworks.com/en-in/insights/blog/case-continuous-delivery&quot;&gt;The Case for Continuous Delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One of the main uses of continuous delivery is to &lt;strong&gt;ensure we are building functionality that really delivers the expected customer value&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Second, continuous delivery &lt;strong&gt;reduces the risk of release and leads to more reliable and resilient systems&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Implementing CD has second-order effects that &lt;strong&gt;reduce the costs of software development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When HP Laserjet Team Implemented CD they found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Overall development costs reduced by ~40%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programs under development increased by ~140%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development costs per program reduced by 78%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resources driving innovation increased by 5x&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continuous-delivery-pipeline-101&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/continuous-delivery/principles/pipeline&quot;&gt;Continuous delivery pipeline 101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describes different continuous delivery pipelines. CD needs a Repeatable reliable process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;must-read-continuous-delivery-business-value-benefits-challenges--metrics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MUST READ&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/continuous-delivery/principles/business-value&quot;&gt;Continuous Delivery: Business Value, Benefits, Challenges &amp;amp; Metrics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explains the business benifits of continuous delivery. They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased Velocity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased Productivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased Sustainability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Done” means released&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teams should fearlessly automate themselves out of their jobs, and move on to new projects.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In case you feel stalled, shift gears. &lt;strong&gt;Know how to give your team a car when all they have asked for is a faster horse&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jumpstart with the help of experienced champions who will see you through this initial hump. &lt;strong&gt;People, after all, are your greatest assets&lt;/strong&gt; and train them to do the right thing. &lt;strong&gt;Make it easy to do the right thing, and hard to do the wrong thing&lt;/strong&gt;, and you will be pleasantly surprised at the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article is worth sharing with your business team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;continuousdelivery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/ContinuousDelivery.html&quot;&gt;ContinuousDelivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You’re doing continuous delivery when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Your software is deployable throughout its lifecycle&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Your team prioritizes keeping the software deployable over working on new features&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Anybody can get fast, automated feedback on the production readiness of their systems any time somebody makes a change to them&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You can perform push-button deployments of any version of the software to any environment on demand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A continuous deployment pipeline helps improve value delivery and deployment frequency without reducing quality, rather it enforces quality. The team following continuous delivery is forced to be intentional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real continuous delivery is delivery to PROD. All else is fake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuous Delivery is a combination of development improvements and business improvements, forcing both to be more deligent and set good processes for release. The teams that follow CD see a 5 to 10 times increase deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practices like the following support continuous delivery:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/atomic-commits&quot;&gt;atomic commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tdd&quot;&gt;TDD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/implementing-kanban&quot;&gt;the kanban&lt;/a&gt; pull system and walk-the-board-from-right strategy,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/feature-flagging&quot;&gt;feature-flagging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="devops" /><category term="continuous-delivery" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/continuous-delivery.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/continuous-delivery.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Template for Gherkin Specs</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/template-for-gherkin-specs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Template for Gherkin Specs" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-07T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-template-for-gherkin-specs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/template-for-gherkin-specs">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-feature&quot;&gt;@tagPlaceholder1 @tagPlaceholder2
Feature: A new feature
  Author - Ankush #this is the main person who write is specs
  Dislaimer - This spec is complete, to the best of my knowledge, but if I forgot something, please tell me.

  Amigos -
      Developers - Team Name (Members participating)
              QA -
         Product -
        Designer -

  Estimated Release Date - 12/3

  Open Issues -
  Side Note -

  Personas (if needed) - 
    - User 
        Age -
        Background - 

  Scenario: 
    Mock UI - NA
    Card Number - NA
    
    Technical Note -  NA
      Testing Note - NA
    Marketing Note - NA
     Doc Team Note - NA

    Given {past tense}
     When {present tense}
     Then {future tense}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;more-resources-to-check-out-to-update-this-article&quot;&gt;More Resources to check out to update this article:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.blog/2020/04/06/a-practical-guide-to-writing-technical-specs/&quot;&gt;A practical guide to writing technical specs - Stack Overflow Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bdd" /><summary type="html">```feature @tagPlaceholder1 @tagPlaceholder2 Feature: A new feature Author - Ankush #this is the main person who write is specs Dislaimer - This spec is complete, to the best of my knowledge, but if I forgot something, please tell me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Separating_request,_entity_and_response</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/2023/01/07/Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Separating_request,_entity_and_response" /><published>2023-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-11T02:13:30-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/2023/01/07/Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/2023/01/07/Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1tsu2S_EnDds8oIRiiip4rwl2qhXEq-Se?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;underline&quot;&gt;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1tsu2S_EnDds8oIRiiip4rwl2qhXEq-Se?usp=sharing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is a major concern for web applications. One of the ways to achieve this is by using the least access principle. This means only exposing things that are necessary and hiding the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a typical web application, we perform CRUD operations on entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite common to have the same entity object be requested, saving to DB and response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the roles of classes mentioned above,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;API endpoints: deals with input objects. In this case, a single one entity.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Service and Repository: deal with manipulating and saving entities to the database. And sending the same entity as response.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Entity: Has 3 roles. Input Object, Output Object and being object stored in database.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Code Sample:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Entity&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repository&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way is problematic since it,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Many fields used for one role (like input) won’t be used for other role (like storing to DB)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Internal details are exposed in output&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Validations are harder for inputs&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many linters recommend having a separate DTO object for this task. This is a step up over the usual entity but isn’t sufficient as most of the time the entity and DTO are exact replicas of each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a better alternative to this, which is to separate inputs, output and entity classes entirely..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Code Sample:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Request Object:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empty Body Response:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response With Body:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response Assembler:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ankushchoubey.com/assets/img/2023-01-07-Separating_Request,_Entity_and_Response/media/image10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As you can see from the example above, there are many request objects and a single response object. Each of these requests and responses can have different fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API endpoint&lt;/strong&gt;: deals with getting different formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service &amp;amp; Repository&lt;/strong&gt;: only deal with manipulating entity files based on the type of request. It then either sends a response directly if there is no body or offloads it’s work to a response assembler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response Assembler&lt;/strong&gt;: job is to create a response. There may be multiple types of responses which response assembler may assemble&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can also be requests and responses that have no body at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Request params maybe enough for GET and DELETE request&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Similarly, HTTP status code and response header maybe enough for responses&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;If an object is created, then 201 CREATED with response headers like location without a body may be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP suggests but does not enforce any kind of rules over requests and responses. But by following them as closely as possible, we can ensure communicating intent without transfer of bulky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits of this approach is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Request, Response and Entity classes have a clear separation of concern. Each deal with their own specific usage.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Therefore, no extra fields are added to each. If new fields are to be added to one part, they may or may not concern other parts.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Securing the application becomes easier as less internal details are leaked.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Tip: In most cases, the response object requires some fields from the entity. Commonly DTOs are created and data from entities is copied to response using some sort of mapper. There is a better alternative which is to use the Delegate pattern. The getters of response class can delegate to getters of entity class. In Java specifically, this can be made easier by using Lombok’s @Delegate annotation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1tsu2S_EnDds8oIRiiip4rwl2qhXEq-Se?usp=sharing</summary></entry></feed>