<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-23T14:21:29-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush</title><subtitle>Random Thoughts</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Post Format</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/post-format/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post Format" /><published>2050-09-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/post-format</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/post-format/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/switch-jobs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-steps&quot;&gt;Writing Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I write from POV that how I got the this idea and how I thought about it, readers will know thinking behing an idea and not just the preachiness. Plus, I’ll always have the right words to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Task&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Done&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Structure Done&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Thoughts Written&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Thoughts Edited&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Grammar Check Done&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Perfect Grammarly Score:&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Image Added  https://www.canva.com/&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Links to Other Posts if Any&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tags Added&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Released Publically&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="draft" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/n-plus-one.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/n-plus-one.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Strategies on “Truth”</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/truth-stratergies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strategies on “Truth”" /><published>2022-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-24T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/truth-stratergies/">&lt;p&gt;There are family of algorithms/strategy to seek truth. Each one applies to specific cases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Telling truth to yourself completely is most important and easiest&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you aren’t specific. Aka you are wage. Then you aren’t telling the truth&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are with other people and you are not letting them talk, probability is high that you’ll miss the truth&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are saying something memorized, or talking too fast, probability is high you’ll miss the truth&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While understanding something, only if you can explain it deeply. Then you know it. -&amp;gt; Truth&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best way to do it is to actually teach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tests/Questions asked by other or ask by yourself. Unhide thefog. Let’s you get specific. Truth is always specific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though counter is specific isn’t always truth but it is still the best guess&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you seek truth, no matter what you are doing or how bad it seems, you’ll be good in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Problem with truth is acceptance. So point 1 makes it easier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Like all core values, you have to realize truth completely to accept and integrate it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On one level, all of truth is just effective communication/speech&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expression of Intend is more important than expession of facts. Expression of intend isn’t always words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Truths are true events or facts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you sre going to do something is not the truth. It’s a possibility. We mistake this and believe we done it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have done something, it’s a truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is along the lines of why sharing what we are going to do isn’t complete truth yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="core-values" /><category term="truth" /><summary type="html">There are family of algorithms/strategy to seek truth. Each one applies to specific cases</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Strategies on “Team Work”</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/team-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strategies on “Team Work”" /><published>2022-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-24T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/team-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/team-work/">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Treat others the way you want to be treated. Treat yourself the way you want to be treated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everyone’s problems/expectations are similar on one level:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;everyones want to share and want to be really listened to their point of view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone want to feel safe and safe enough to trust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone wants to he respected: respected of boundaries (hopefully healthy ones).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone want people to support them even if it’s little.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone has ego.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you criticize the person, you poke the ego.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you critize an approach, then probability that their ego will be poked in a healthy way and it will be on your side or atleast open to discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is to say you don’t want somone to win or lose. You want Win-Win. Win-Win is a win for all parties to a certain degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To build trust, you have to trust and try opening up. But open up on solid ground. You don’t want to be naïve because opening up increases probability of being hurt but also it won’t reciprocate. You want to build trust “together”, not being trust one sided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything in “Team Work” is about doing things “together”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;This one is recent for me&lt;/em&gt;: Let everyone (others and yourself) choose and solve their own local problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have right to choose what they want to focus on. You may suggest or lead by example. But forcing you opinions rebounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus forcing opinions assumes that one really knows “life” which probably no one does fully.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="core-values" /><category term="team-work" /><summary type="html">Treat others the way you want to be treated. Treat yourself the way you want to be treated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elements of Good API Design</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/good-api-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elements of Good API Design" /><published>2022-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-19T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/elements-of-good-api-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/good-api-design/">&lt;p&gt;Here are somethings about API design that I recently learn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An HTTP Rest endpoint is divided into following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;API name and Method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Request&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resposne&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;naming&quot;&gt;Naming&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good API design has good naming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to always have API that refer t some “items”/”entity” nouns&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so this is better&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/ducks → get all ducks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/ducks/{id} → get duck by duck id&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;rather than&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/getAllDucks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/getDuckById&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any good API has upper format rather than lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always have plural names&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;request&quot;&gt;Request&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;request-methods&quot;&gt;Request Methods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that name is sorted, how to we call these, let’s say we want to delete duck, in the bad way we could have had an API like /deleteDuckById&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even better is to use HTTP Methods. HTTP Methods provide intend to your API and reduce the number of API endpoints to remember at least from point of view of consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to read it you read it something like this,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intend → API Name&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GET → /ducks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GET → /ducks/{id}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DELETE → /ducks/{id}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;POST → /ducks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, POST isn’t supposed to be bulk insert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;request-headers&quot;&gt;Request Headers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some common onces are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;content-length&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;response&quot;&gt;Response&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;response-status-code&quot;&gt;Response Status Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many standard response codes available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;200 → OK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;201 → Created (Supposed to not have response body)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;response-body&quot;&gt;Response Body:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAL Format&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;response-headers&quot;&gt;Response Headers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are standard respose headers available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Location of newly created resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;customizing-the-protocol&quot;&gt;Customizing the protocol&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTP does not reenforce a lot of rules. Even though it it recommended ways are set,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I though Google would follow protocol to the bone but they too don’t. Looking at google drive through Chrome’s network tab, I found they have their own way of doing things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="middleware" /><category term="draft" /><summary type="html">Here are somethings about API design that I recently learn’t.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on Reading Documentation</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/reading-documentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on Reading Documentation" /><published>2022-02-16T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-16T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/reading-documentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/reading-documentation/">&lt;p&gt;Reading documentation is the best way to learn a particular technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A well written documentation is similar to a book and reading it has a similar effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation presents the original developer’s philosophy behind the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depth of knowledge you gain with documentation can potentially remove hundred of hours of un-neccesary Stackoverflow searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a difference between knowing something syntactially and knowing the philosophy behind a technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most documentations are about 2-5 hours of reading Max.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find having a highlighter extension in Chrome to be extremely useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the usual, the appendix sections contains many gems like FAQs and common references which make things easier.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software-engineering" /><summary type="html">Reading documentation is the best way to learn a particular technology.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Articulate Fully</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/articulate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Articulate Fully" /><published>2022-01-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-29T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/articulate-fully</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/articulate/">&lt;p&gt;Being able to articulate something fully is the whole game of a knowing if you have a clear mind or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often you may find that by talking to someone, you are able to find solution to your own problems by yourself. This is because you Before you weren’t able to articulate completely what you’re thinking. By forcing yourself to articulate you make yourself more clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are stuck at something, be it anything of a kind: A problem you are trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emotional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abstract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe anything than bother’s you should be fully articulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is articulate it fully and hopefully as easy as possible. Even forced articulation is better than no articulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple ways one can force articulation some of them are mentioned below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explain-at-five-levels&quot;&gt;Explain at five levels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the practices one can person is explain it to pretend or really explain 5 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A child&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A teenager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A collage kid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A adult&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A expert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contemplate&quot;&gt;Contemplate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;while contemplating you want to fix certain variables about your problem, and then explain the rest and try to fix those too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find the best way to contemplate is to perform at formal sitting meditation with eyes closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;talkexplain-to-someone-else&quot;&gt;Talk/Explain to someone else&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="core-values" /><category term="truth" /><summary type="html">Being able to articulate something fully is the whole game of a knowing if you have a clear mind or not.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Personal Budgeting</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/personal-budgeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Personal Budgeting" /><published>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/budgeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/personal-budgeting/">&lt;p&gt;Many times discussing governments spending, it is discussed how while a budget was allocated, the government didn’t spend as much or they spent more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the Education budget was set at 20 billion but only 5 billion was spent. Or they overspent which ate up other areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, these discussions assume that spending the complete budget allocated is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underspending&lt;/strong&gt;: Not doing enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overspending&lt;/strong&gt;: Doing too much and eating into other areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same can be applied to resources of one’s #life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe these are the most important resources a person spends on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Budget&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attention Budget&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Money Budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, given the premise above, the goal is to have a specific time, attention, and money budget for each important area of life and major activity. It isn’t ideal to set budgets for everything (else you won’t have an attention budget).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time (in hours) and money (in currency) are easily quantifiable. Attention isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For attention, the game becomes imaginary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways to imagine this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Count the number of decisions in a day:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Imagine you have 100 decision points in a day.
 The more number decisions you take, the probability of you making a bad decision increases.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Number of context switching
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Multitasking is the worst&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="core-values" /><category term="time-matters" /><summary type="html">Many times discussing governments spending, it is discussed how while a budget was allocated, the government didn’t spend as much or they spent more.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time Assets and Liabilities</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-assets-and-liabilities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time Assets and Liabilities" /><published>2022-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-26T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/time-assets-liabilities</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/time-assets-and-liabilities/">&lt;p&gt;Time is the most precious finite resource we have. We should make good use of it. If we do, we make time our ally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any resource, one can think of time in numeric terms. This allows us to categorize activities as assets that add back time or liabilities, which take time away. Our goal then is to create more time-assets with high time-ROI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;80% of our activities during a given day are not new. They are merely routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So essentially, carefully observing, choosing, and forming our habits would lead to more &lt;strong&gt;time-assets&lt;/strong&gt; and less &lt;strong&gt;time-liabilities&lt;/strong&gt;. Usually, time-assets and time-liabilities are opposites of each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most time-liabilities snap our attention and lead us to care about wrong things. Therefore, time-assets help us course correct. Therefore, time management is closely linked to attention management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most time assets are generatlly slower and more stuctured which is why they are usually avoided. Time liabilities on the other hand feel easy to get started with so they are done more. So, one needs to make it easy to get started on time-assets and harder to get started on time-liabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the most impactful time-assets and liabilities are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time-Assets&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Time Liabilities&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Even a little bit of planning, something like 10 minutes alone creating a written plan could save hours, days, or even years. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Planning allows course correction. Ideally, don’t start working without a plan.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rushing&lt;/strong&gt;: Though it may seem you are making progress. The probability is higher that you are moving in the wrong direction. It’s better to fix a plan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5 Min Rule&lt;/strong&gt;: Don’t allow yourself to be down or procrastinate for more than 5 minutes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During such time ask yourself: Is this worth the return on my time?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Remember you can’t live forever.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Forever Rule: &lt;strong&gt;The opposite of 5 min rule&lt;/strong&gt;: Letting fear/laziness/indecision stop you.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WIP Limit&lt;/strong&gt;: Focus on a few things and complete them. If your WIP limit is exceeded, don’t add work on newer tasks unless older ones are complete.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trying to change people&lt;/strong&gt;: You cannot change people. You can suggest but cannot force. Leading by example. It’s the best option you have.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pomodoro&lt;/strong&gt;: Working in Pomodoros keeps you focused. If you can’t work with Pomodoro, you haven’t planned carefully enough.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To have Pomodoro sessions.&lt;br /&gt;1. Create a distraction-free zone.&lt;br /&gt;2. Plan your tasks. Ideally, pick a deliverable.&lt;br /&gt;3. Put on headphones and play instrumental/&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLx65qkgCWNJIs3FPaj8JZhduXSpQ_ZfvL&quot;&gt;focus music&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;4. Work on the task using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pomofocus.io/&quot;&gt;a Pomodoro app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;5. Stick to break schedule religiously. Get away from the room during the break but no internet. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;One Pomodoro is better than zero Pomodoro.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During normal decision-making, one can calculate the ROI of their actions: think about how much time you’ll invest and how much return you’ll get back. This calculation needs to be a specific number in terms of both hours and percentage even if it’s an estimate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="core-values" /><category term="time-matters" /><category term="philosophical" /><summary type="html">Time is the most precious finite resource we have. We should make good use of it. If we do, we make time our ally.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maintaining Documentation</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/documentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maintaining Documentation" /><published>2022-01-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-25T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/documentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/documentation/">&lt;p&gt;We ideally want to write code so well that someone reading the code can understand it in one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the ideal isn’t always practical in the real world because people come from different backgrounds and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you want to make sure your documentation is as perfect as possible given the project scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the API/Library is going to be used by the public, it needs to be perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2022-01-25-documentation/shared-between-single-team-multiple.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem is maintaining up-to-date documentation. These are a few things I have learned recently about this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: left; width: 300px;&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vS1EYND3yzq_zmJEZ1rEJogTD9tbXucE2k33rcUYIVTcA2ZQZlYfPf_MSVk8kvHZhjcKo7fByRiXFpy/pub?w=453&amp;amp;h=723&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-best-way-to-document-is-to-automate&quot;&gt;1. The best way to document is to automate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like Swagger for APIs and storybook from UI components make it very easy to auto-document code in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-encourage-use-of-your-own-documentation&quot;&gt;2. Encourage use of your own documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your own documentation would help you find and fix bugs in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, You could encourage your team to use Swagger UI instead of Post Man for testing APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-for-within-the-team-have-a-shared-wiki&quot;&gt;3. For within the team: Have a shared wiki&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wiki helps keep everyone in sync and like the previous point, encourages updations wherever necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-tests-are-also-documentation-of-sorts-but-for-the-internal-team-only&quot;&gt;4. Tests are also documentation of sorts but for the internal team only.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tests capture what the code would do. So for a new dev on a team, going and reading through tests can give him an idea of what the code does.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="clean-code" /><summary type="html">We ideally want to write code so well that someone reading the code can understand it in one go.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vS1EYND3yzq_zmJEZ1rEJogTD9tbXucE2k33rcUYIVTcA2ZQZlYfPf_MSVk8kvHZhjcKo7fByRiXFpy/pub?w=453&amp;amp;h=723" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://docs.google.com/drawings/d/e/2PACX-1vS1EYND3yzq_zmJEZ1rEJogTD9tbXucE2k33rcUYIVTcA2ZQZlYfPf_MSVk8kvHZhjcKo7fByRiXFpy/pub?w=453&amp;amp;h=723" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Code Reviews and Pair Programming</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/code-reviews/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code Reviews and Pair Programming" /><published>2022-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T15:52:08-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/code-reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/code-reviews/">&lt;p&gt;Code reviews allow having a much high quality of code. And pair programming is the best way to do code reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, if less code is being reviewed then more bugs are found. If more code is reviewed, reviewer gets lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 lines of code: 10 isues
500 lines of code: no issues “looks fine”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one should air for small and early code review -&amp;gt; continuos code reviews- is this pair programming?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays there are also Pair Programming AI like Kite.ai and GitHub Copilot that may be interesting to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other benigits of pair programming are,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You get to learn about new techniques like how someone uses their IDE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You get to learn about the person/team too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You get to learn about the code base faster if you are pairing up with someone who has experience with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While pair programming is most effective in person, the best way I could find in an online setting is by using remote-destop software that code reviews can interact directly with the code. Screenshare’s aren’t as effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;partner will show you more efficient ways of doing things including how to use ide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may happen that pairing up isn’t ideal and one has to review code later, in that case github/gitlab do provide option to comment on a piece of code. The programmer may submit the code to reviewer for review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fQ-x-T34z9w&amp;amp;ab_channel=AtlassianTechTV&quot;&gt;Pair Programming at Atlassian with Lucy Bain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software-engineering" /><category term="clean-code" /><summary type="html">Code reviews allow having a much high quality of code. And pair programming is the best way to do code reviews.</summary></entry></feed>