<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-04T02:03:38-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush Choubey</title><subtitle>Full Stack Developer - Cloud/Microservices</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Specialization and Trade - Crash Course Economics - 2</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Specialization and Trade - Crash Course Economics - 2" /><published>2023-03-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-04T14:42:15-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/crash-course-econ-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/2">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NI9TLDIPVcs&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Grant was the person who created the wealth of nations. He concluded that specialization and trading are better for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t specialize and trade, you’ll have to do everything yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example in the case of pizza, you’ll have to farm wheat, they make an oven and then even cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, by specializing everyone’s opportunity cost improves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PPF profit possibility frontier helps understand the relationship between producing two products,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if the us is producing 500 planes and it could use the same effort to produce 2000 shoes,
For every 1 plane they produce, they leave our 4 shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If China can produce 100 planes or 800 shoes with the same effort, china for every 1 plane produced, leaves out 800 shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem that the US is better off here and should not trade, but if the US trades planes for shoes, they’ll be better off (need to learn here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point outside the PPF curve is an impossibility
The point inside the PPF curve is inefficiency.
How do you maximize efficiency?
By specializing and trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-sufficiency is inefficiency&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wellness can be predicted by a variety of many economic predictors like GDP per capita, employee, and ent rate, by this we see statistically, most improvements came after Industrial Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also see that countries that are voluntarily or involuntarily cut off from trading with other countries. like Iran Zimbabwe %&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And countries like India and China that opened up the economy and started trading have been experiencing significant growth in %&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals and countries should specialize and do things that they have a competitive advantage in and then trade with others in what they have a competitive advantage in. This trade is mutually beneficial&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="crash-course" /><category term="econ" /><category term="summary" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro to Economics - Crash Course Econ 1</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to Economics - Crash Course Econ 1" /><published>2023-03-04T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-04T14:42:15-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/crash-course-econ-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/crash-course/econ/1">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3ez10ADR_gM&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economics is not just a study of money or the stock exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economics is the study of people and their choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is based on two fundamental assumptions of Economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scarcity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunity Cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could be doing one thing but you are choosing to do something else. In that sense, you believe that doing one is a better use of your time than another. Therefore, your opportunity cost of one is greater than another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarcity means there is a limited supply of resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economics is when people make choices. When a college student decides to pick major A over Major B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people believe that if you just put more money into healthcare, it would improve. But in many cases what we need is the right incentive. So, economics is also a study of incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you could provide the college with an incentive on the number of enrollments. But then college would play it to just enroll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you modify it to incentivize the number of graduates, then you suddenly have colleges just passing people or lowering difficulty or only admitting smart kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it’s very important to get incentives right. Because wrong incentives can backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most economists are in Microeconomics. Whether to launch the business snow or later? What to do when a competitor does x?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macro is the study of a Nation and its decisions like inflation, unemployment, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Governments and the Free Market support each other. One can’t function without the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always an opportunity cost. If you don’t want road accidents, you could remove all cards from the road. But you understand the opportunity cost and decide one is better than the other.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="crash-course" /><category term="econ" /><category term="summary" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The only differences between external_apps and internal_features in a plugin architecture</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/internal-vs-external-plugin" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The only differences between external_apps and internal_features in a plugin architecture" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-difference-between-third-party-and-first-party</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/internal-vs-external-plugin">&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-a-users-perspective&quot;&gt;From A User’s Perspective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Party &lt;strong&gt;Default&lt;/strong&gt; Apps are just product features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Party &lt;strong&gt;Installable&lt;/strong&gt; Apps are apps that can be installed by the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These apps are not enabled by default&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These are provided by default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A user won’t even know that these are treated as an app by the platform company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party&lt;/strong&gt; apps are created by third-party developers and can extend the core functionality of the first-party app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These apps are not enabled by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-perspective&quot;&gt;Code Perspective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These two types of apps are the same&lt;/strong&gt;, except the first-party app doesn’t need Authentication to access Platform data, while the third-party app does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A third-party app may utilize all capabilities that the plugin platform provides unless some capabilities are reserved for first-party apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous post, I explained how we could define scopes for our resource would work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the example of movies where an app is using 2 scopes: “&lt;strong&gt;read:movies&lt;/strong&gt;” and “&lt;strong&gt;read:userinfo&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s call this app, an external_app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now suppose we have an internal feature, which uses the same endpoints that “read:movies” and “read:userinfo” uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only difference between external_app and the internal feature would be that the external_app will use OAuth and scopes to get access to the resource. While the internal_feature would not have to ask for permission to access the resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means, once you create a scope, it’s fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this simplifies your development a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, therefore, we need not treat internal features and external apps very differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the platform level, both internal_feature and the external_app are just apps.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="architecture" /><category term="plugin" /><summary type="html">From A User’s Perspective</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Defining Scopes for your OAuth Service</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/oauth-scopes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defining Scopes for your OAuth Service" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-oauth-scopes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/oauth-scopes">&lt;p&gt;Here’s my thinking on how we should design scopes for OAuth. And how many a proper REST API could simplify the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a rest API, we have resources. Our resources are usually accessed with just a noun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies&lt;/code&gt; to get all movies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies/{movieId}&lt;/code&gt; to get a specific movie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PUT&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies&lt;/code&gt; to modify a movie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies&lt;/code&gt; to add a new movie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DELETE&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies/{movieID}&lt;/code&gt; to delete a movie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Outh scopes are a restriction on resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, we would have scopes for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;movies&lt;/code&gt; resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can append this with the kind of method that can be run on the resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;read:movies&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; allows &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; calls on &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies&lt;/code&gt; REST API resource&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;write:movies&lt;/code&gt; → allows &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt; calls on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/movies&lt;/code&gt; resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;read:userinfo&lt;/code&gt; → allows &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET&lt;/code&gt; calls on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/userinfo&lt;/code&gt; resource&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the app is submitted to our “App Store“, the app developer declares an app, they are using a particular scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s say an App that shows user recommendations has asked for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;read:movies&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;write:movies and&lt;/code&gt; read:userinfo&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt; &lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app developer has declared why they use each of the scopes. While declaring, they decide they aren’t using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;write:movies&lt;/code&gt; scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, they remove it. Or while reviewing the app submission application, the App Store platform rejects the request for accepting &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;write:movies&lt;/code&gt; and asks for more clarifications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><category term="oauth" /><summary type="html">Here’s my thinking on how we should design scopes for OAuth. And how many a proper REST API could simplify the process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating DB smoothly with a migration script</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/db-migration-script/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating DB smoothly with a migration script" /><published>2023-03-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-03T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/db-migration-script</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/db-migration-script/">&lt;p&gt;If you are transferring from one DB to another and want to make sure it happens properly, this is the mechanism you can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same mechanism could be used to migrate multiple tables. And can be implemented in SQL stored procedure or stored procedure equivalent in the DB of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add these additional columns to your source table
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is_migrated&lt;/strong&gt;: default false&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;migrated_date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is_error&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;error_description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a DB migration script which
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Copies a batch of data from one table in source DB to one table in dB.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The batch size could be 1000. You don’t want the batch size to be too small because it could be slow. You don’t want it too high to be able to recover better.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Whenever a batch is a complete update the is_migrated and migrated_date in the source DB. Then pick up the next batch where is_migrated is false.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If there is an error, set &lt;strong&gt;is_error&lt;/strong&gt; to_ true _and add &lt;strong&gt;error_description&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;error_description&lt;/strong&gt; could be an exception that is thrown.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Once the script is done, check for &lt;strong&gt;is_error: true&lt;/strong&gt; and fix those errors in the script itself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Run the script by copying the data from PROD to your testing environment.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix your scripts if you find &lt;strong&gt;is_error: true&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Once all is fixed, re-copy data from PROD to your testing environment and run again.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You want to make sure everything works perfectly so that you won’t have to do much during the PROD run.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Once you find all bugs are fixed, run the migration script in &lt;strong&gt;PROD&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="database" /><summary type="html">If you are transferring from one DB to another and want to make sure it happens properly, this is the mechanism you can use.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Core Beliefs from Feb 2023</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/my-core-beliefs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Core Beliefs from Feb 2023" /><published>2023-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-12T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-core-beliefs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/my-core-beliefs/">&lt;p&gt;I choose my core-beliefs very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-dont-and-wont-do-things-that-i-want&quot;&gt;I don’t and won’t do things that I want.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will do and do do things that I need or things that need to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both are a form of responsibility. Need being respo to self. Need to be done means respo to others. Because my wants can always be something that’s not good for me. But my needs are always good for me because they are essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-wont-lie-i-wont-utter-a-word-that-i-know-is-a-lie&quot;&gt;I won’t lie. I won’t utter a word that I know is a lie.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I won’t manipulate to get what I want. But I can state it simply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I don’t know what the truth is. But atleast when I’m speaking I’ll stop and reformularw when i’m about to utter a lie so that i’ll be as truthful as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the same line. I won’t ever manipulate or lie to get what I want. But I’ll state them clearly as I can. And see if I can hget it. If I do get it via an ethical parh good. Or else I’ll try another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-dont-attack-the-person-i-attack-the-action&quot;&gt;I don’t attack the person. I attack the action.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want toxicity and/or problem to end. It doesn’t help to attack the person because person gets defensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need a better way to explain this. I can say I want toxicity to end or problem to end. But I need something more definitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;there-are-no-shortcuts-there-are-no-hacks&quot;&gt;There are no shortcuts. There are no hacks.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortcut is a lie. The hack does not get you anywhere.
I am not afraid to voice my opinion where it’s needed and necessary.
I am speak the truth. And I understand there are no shortcuts. And no hacks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-dont-revolve-my-life-around-women&quot;&gt;I don’t revolve my life around women.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a man, it’s tempting. And sometimes I feel insecure FOMO. But there are more important things to do in my life. I have responsibilities and I need to fulfil them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, it’s not like it helps. Having someone that you trust solves that area only. Not other areas! And if I try to burden someone, it’s not god for them, it’s not good for me. I do my part. And them do theres.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophical" /><category term="for-future-me" /><category term="decision-making" /><category term="non-professional" /><category term="matured" /><summary type="html">I choose my core-beliefs very carefully.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Core Values Summary from Feb 2023</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v3/my-core-values/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Core Values Summary from Feb 2023" /><published>2023-02-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-12T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v3/v3-core-values-summary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v3/my-core-values/">&lt;p&gt;I have 7 core values and these help me live authentically, get the most out of life and be a peaceful cheerful and charming person in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core of my core values in &lt;strong&gt;Clarity&lt;/strong&gt;. Clarity refers to clarity of thought. I aim to have clear thinking in every moments. Towards this aim, I adopt habits and patterns that help such as being truthful, developing observability via Data Collection and Meditation and seeking truth by understanding biases, fallacies and loaded language. My core values also help me with clarity and setting a proper realistic vision for myself. Overall, clarity is about truth and a proper vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second core value is &lt;strong&gt;Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;. Responsibility helps me be stronger instead of weaker. I believe weakness leads to problems and this includes any and all times of weakness. Responsibility like clarity is a continuous process. We choose to act strongly in face of difficulty is a plus plus towards responsibility. We should start with taking responsibility of ourself completely (which includes taking care of our physical/mental heath/ our finances) and then responsibility of things around us (empowering others, helping family, the baton), in this order. We often act in ways that make us move towards a downward path. But we always have the choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarity and Responsibility are my fundamental values. These values form the basis of the next 3 values that are very implementation focused and can be easily measured. The last 2 values, fulfill the larger purpose and the missing peace of living a great life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My third value is &lt;strong&gt;Inputs&lt;/strong&gt;. Inputs refer to optimizing all the inputs we face in day to day life, the things that capture our attention. We often act in ways that make us move towards a downward path. A lot of times this is because we get inputs from our environment that push us. In the modern world, we have a lot of abundance. This abundance brings us problems because they try to replace many natural things. Social media trying to replace social life makes us feel lonely. Processed food makes us unhealthy. Porn makes us depressed, lonely and hedonistic. News makes us think what “recent” and whats “someone’s opinion” is more important than “tried-and-true“ and what’s “fact“. We keep using our willpower against these modern inputs, we need strong boundaries. Doing so would eliminate things that makes us worse and as a result we get a little stronger. To become even stronger, we can incorporate ancient weapons: fasting, meditation and exercise, all of which are aimed to voluntarily experience short term pain but have maximal long term benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have eliminated stupid things and added good things, we can move towards automation and goal achievement via &lt;strong&gt;Systems&lt;/strong&gt;. The core value 4. Systems accelerate progress towards our goals. By being methodical, we can achieve anything with much more clarity and ease. By creating habits, routines, taking on training (and sometimes retraining), semi-automated systems (like kanban) and automated systems of the modern world, we optimize what’s left from inputs and makes sure everything runs smoothly. This provides logarithmic big O in terms of effort put in compared to exponential positive results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fifth core value is &lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;. Time and attention are our non-renewable resources. Clarity, inputs and systems regain our attention. Our attention saves us time and we need time because we have a finite life. Our lives are average 80 years. The way we can make the most of this life is by spending it properly on the things that make the most impact and not wasting it. By being mindful about our mortality, we get clarity, we remove things that aren’t useful and we optimize and nurture things that are important to us. At the same time, we can also increase our time, taking steps towards our longevity. Time allows us to do more of what we want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the above, we achieve a greater level of peace. And now, we aim to accelerate that peace further with last two core values: team and adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 6th core value is &lt;strong&gt;Team&lt;/strong&gt;. “Team” is about understanding the dynamics between yourself and people around you. This dynamic is sometimes a dichotomy. You want to help others yet not so much that they keep relying on you. You want to do things yourself yet you something should rely on others. “Team” makes us let of over reliance on ourselves and trust the knowledge of instincts of others. (Though we should always verify. #dichotomy). A large part of life would be with people. We are social animals to the core and we love to live in tribes. And we love to “Love” too. Being around people make us happy, people make us (or demand from us) the best version of ourself and in-turn this leads to best version of themselves. If you didn’t get any of what was written here, start here relationships with people around you make you more cheerful  happy person. #Win-Win&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last core value is &lt;strong&gt;Adventure&lt;/strong&gt;. Adventure is about the heroes journey. We get excited by video games, by movies and by books. We love listening to stories (especially real life ones) where people who faced challenges were able to overcome it. That’s adventure. Adventure gives us calling to something that is bigger than we are. And ideally, if one has clarity, takes care of responsibility, is focused, organized, fast and has a team, that’s perfect addition to well formed adventure cuz all of them are tools and weapons in terms of facing the BOSS. The unknown. Our adventure starts when we decide to face the dragon of unknown. And this leads us to courage. So, if you are facing a problem that seems large or you are seeing something that frightened you, take your weapons, do you pushups, face that monster with all the knowledge under your belt. Only you can do it! So be your hero!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first 2 core values give me the right direction. The next 3 values accelerate the progress towards them. And the final 2, bring the greatest the world has to offer. Overall, these 7 makes me healthier, wealthier, wiser and the best version of myself for the world and therefore they are best bet is very situations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophical" /><category term="for-future-me" /><category term="decision-making" /><category term="non-professional" /><category term="matured" /><summary type="html">I have 7 core values and these help me live authentically, get the most out of life and be a peaceful cheerful and charming person in the process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RSA Algorithm</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/rsa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RSA Algorithm" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-rsa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/rsa">&lt;p&gt;RSA is an asymmetric key encryption algorithm and was first published in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSA was created by Ron Rivest, Adi Shamir and Leonard Adleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/v1-rsa/rsa-creators.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding their photo for inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSA works on the concept of modular arithmetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In RSA, we have a public and a private key. We use the private key to decrypt and the public key to encrypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that the private key should not be shared. But the public key can be shared with anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private Key = Key
Public Key = Lock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 5 steps in RSA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take two prime numbers p and q. (Eg: p=2, q=7)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; . &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; is the product of p and q. (N = p*q = 2*7 = 14)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculate &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(N)&lt;/code&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is the number of co-primes less than N. (Eg. 1, 2, 5, 7 and 11 are co-primes to 14; therefore &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(n)&lt;/code&gt;  is the count = 6)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This can also be calculated with a formula &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(p-1)(q-1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eg; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(N)&lt;/code&gt;  = (2-1)(7-1) = 6&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the public key (e) such that&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 &amp;lt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;  &amp;lt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(N)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E should be co-prime with Phi(N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eg. e = 5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the private key (d) such that&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(e*d) mod &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Phi(n)&lt;/code&gt; = 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eg: (5*d) mod (14) = 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you calculate this you’ll see a pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5*1 = 5; mod 6 =  5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5*2 = 10; mod 6 = 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 mod 6 = 3&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25 mod 6 = 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 mod 6 = 0
This pattern is expected since (5*6)%6 will be 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s pick a large &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;D = 11&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to encrypt you’ll do the following,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(value^e) mod N
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To decrypt, you’ll do the following,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(encryptedValue ^d) mod N
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4zahvcJ9glg&quot;&gt;Eddie Woo: The RSA Encryption Algorithm (1 of 2: Computing an Example)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oOcTVTpUsPQ&quot;&gt;The RSA Encryption Algorithm (2 of 2: Generating the Keys)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.drexel.edu/~jpopyack/IntroCS/HW/RSAWorksheet.html&quot;&gt;RSA Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><summary type="html">RSA is an asymmetric key encryption algorithm and was first published in 1977.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-rsa/rsa-creators.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/images/v1-rsa/rsa-creators.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/traditional-roles" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant?" /><published>2023-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-31T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-traditional-roles</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/traditional-roles">&lt;p&gt;What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant?
In a world of narcissist, nihilism, pleasure, many are tempted to believe that this is all life has to offer. That’s until they decide to take responsibility. They stop being all talk, and convert their potential to actuality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along that path comes a point. What to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have already covered needs. One of two types of responsibility a human should adopt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will provide a guide to need to do i.e. duties. Duties are traditional synonym for responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-we-should-look-at-traditional-roles&quot;&gt;Why we should look at traditional roles?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more you look at the history and the past, the more you can see the future.
~ Winston Churchil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that have worked for a numbers of years have value in them. It’s not always the case that what’s new has value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our case, around 100 years ago, most of humanity lived under extreme poverty. So, before 100 years ago, most humans were adapted to a world where they had to work on their duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these times, each person tried to adapt to their best skill. And similarly, men and women adapted to the skill that suited them the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men are usually stronger physically. This made them good at jobs like being a soldier and building buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women are usually physically less strong and have a kind nature. This made them good at caring, managing households.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both men and women worked together to build our modern world today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing was that they “had” to do their duties and as well as possible. In the modern world, most duties have become optional or are at least perceived to be optional. This optionality results in a lack of purpose for most people. People don’t know what to do. So they opt for what’s available, momentary pleasure and are in a pit of nihilism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pre-modern world provides a much much better alternative. Traditional roles provides the purpose of life that modern alternatives do not. Even if you are modern, if you feel lost then start here with the traditional. Then adapt your plans overtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementing-the-traditional-roles&quot;&gt;Implementing The Traditional Roles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before jumping further, here is the mindset you should develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with at least what’s your strength, if you are masculine, pick traditional masculine duties first. If you are feminine, pick traditionally feminine duties first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are set in one role, start picking up things from the other role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no-problem in picking being caring as a man or being a provider as a women. But try starting with your duties first as these may come much more naturally to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;duties-of-a-man&quot;&gt;Duties of a man&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A man has three duties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Problem Solve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you were living in a jungle in 1600s, what would you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would provide for your family, protect them from dangerous and solve problems like shelter by building a house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To provide&lt;/strong&gt;, a man must be useful enough. In the modern world being useful enough means providing the world what it wants. #capatalism (I love capitalism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To protect&lt;/strong&gt;, a man must be strong physically and must be strong mentally to face the problems that come up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the modern world, there seems to be no-need for such strength, but it seems useless not to have such physical and mental strength. This conclusion is because we still have protection duties. Going down an alley and a thief with a knife shows up. What would you do? Would you panic or would you handle the situation calmly. Therefore, a man must develop his physical body well to be useful in any situation and his mental strength as well so that he can face obstacles that come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To problem solve&lt;/strong&gt;, a man must be learn, not give up and be-humble enough to adapt to the situations. Many times this means facing the void of not knowing anything, but trying anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;duties-of-a-women&quot;&gt;Duties of a women&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A women has three duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nurture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="responsibility" /><summary type="html">What are the traditional roles of a man and women? And why they are relevant? In a world of narcissist, nihilism, pleasure, many are tempted to believe that this is all life has to offer. That’s until they decide to take responsibility. They stop being all talk, and convert their potential to actuality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to plan mid-day?</title><link href="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/plan-mid-day" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to plan mid-day?" /><published>2023-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T14:52:08-06:00</updated><id>https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/v1-plan-mid-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ankushchoubey.com/v1/plan-mid-day">&lt;p&gt;The mid day is the time where you can be the most active. This is ideally, 1.5 hours after waking up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make mid day a success, it’s best to have completed the morning ritual. If the morning ritual is not complete find the best parts of the morning ritual to complete. The morning ritual can provide you with great focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as part of night ritual, your room and setup might already be clean and ready to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you can divide the mid-day into two parts—first half and second half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first half is pre-lunch. This is where you’ll likely be the most active. Fix your lunch time to around 1:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daily standup starts at 9. And I pay attention to it. It’s a great time for me to learn what’s happening in the team and note down concepts that I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spend time learning a few minutes glancing at things I don’t know. And discussing any impediments I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can work between 10 to 1. 3 hours. This would include a 2 hours pomodoro sprint. This activity is chosen carefully and is a part where no learning is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I need to learn something, I can watch youtube videos or open up documentation. But remember this time is protected. No one should distract me between 10 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="non-professional" /><category term="time" /><category term="planning" /><summary type="html">The mid day is the time where you can be the most active. This is ideally, 1.5 hours after waking up.</summary></entry></feed>