<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-20T11:02:23-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ankush</title><subtitle>Random Thoughts</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On one level companies are their to make money.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/for_profit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On one level companies are their to make money." /><published>2020-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/companies-make-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/for_profit/">&lt;p&gt;I often argue on the point of companies should providing value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on one level, maybe one of the most important level all companies are their to make money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing value is often never well defined and their can be many ways to look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even employees working in a company getting a steady paycheck, raising a family, having health insurance for themselves and their family is a valuable thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every company is in an industry, geographic location or stage of growth where they can be good at everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most painful part is when company drops it’s employees. It usually does not happen because the company is evil. But because dropping employees is lesser evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either you drop employees (and resources) or let the whole boat sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big world events like Pandemic or recession always remind us how important and valuable money is for companies and for individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I often argue on the point of companies should providing value.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t try to force sale on people who are not your user base</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/forced_sale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don’t try to force sale on people who are not your user base" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/forced-sale</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/forced_sale/">&lt;p&gt;Many Comapnies try putting limited time offers making people decide to put money down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have fallen victum myself multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Gyms
• Education sites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• For middlemen companies such as shops and e-commerce sites. It matters less.
• They are middlemen, they don’t actually care about the customers. They care about sales and money 💰.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for companies which sell product themselves, they risk one every important factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if your the user does not like your product? He was half sure about buying your product. Now he will tell everyone in his connection to not purchase your product. Plus he’ll also mention to them not to fall for your “sales presentation”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done so myself multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Word of Mouth sale is quite underrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize they have limited time offers every other day. 😑 I could have waited before jumping to their sales presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Many Comapnies try putting limited time offers making people decide to put money down.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Opportunity Cost</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/opportunity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opportunity Cost" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/opportunity</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/opportunity/">&lt;p&gt;If I am a lion 🦁 should I be chasing mice 🐁 or should I be chasing a deer 🦌.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus — saying no to a dozen good ideas so that you can put your resources on things that really matter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If I am a lion 🦁 should I be chasing mice 🐁 or should I be chasing a deer 🦌.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Facade companies</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/Facade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Facade companies" /><published>2020-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/fascade-companies</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/Facade/">&lt;p&gt;Companies which don’t actually care about solving a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are here only for money, increasing valuation, getting more investor, getting sales by tactics such as selling themselves (coupons), brand brand, social media post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then when everything is all set, the founders will exit without hesitation. Not because the problem has been solved but because they didn’t care about the solving the problem at all. It was just a facade.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Companies which don’t actually care about solving a problem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Time tracking over programmers is stupid</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/time_tracking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time tracking over programmers is stupid" /><published>2020-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/timetracking-is-stupid</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/time_tracking/">&lt;p&gt;The job of programmer is essentially to think and then implement a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is better to not write for an hour when you don’t have your thoughts organized in your mind than to write for an hours and then spend all week trying to fix and fiddle with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When starting initially students are thought to write down the algorithm, make flowcharts, etc. and it is understandable that as you get more experience programming you may want to skip that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specially if the problem is something you have already worked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t implement something without giving it thought. Take time to get your thoughts organized. You are not sitting in an exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I say timetracking is stupid is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somedays you realize you have written bunch of code and it works but works like crap but you cannot do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then next day you come back to it… it’s still ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days later you realize that the work you have been doing for the past several days is already done in an Open Source Module. And you discard whatever you had coded up to that point and start from scratch again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming requires a lot of “research” and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The job of programmer is essentially to think and then implement a solution.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Make your code configurable.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/code_configurable/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make your code configurable." /><published>2020-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/make-code-configurable</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/code_configurable/">&lt;p&gt;In one of the posts I wrote previously I explain how programming has become configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have made your software that might be part of it that might need change. Most changes are simple such as:
Increasing the the font
Changing colors
Somethings that work should work on specific environments or domains
Features such as storage location&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resident hard coding everything, make these things configurable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that can be changed with just a click of a button or by changing properties or via Database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small things such as these should not take any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if there is something that some uses like and there is something that other users like, then give them the option to choose it themselves by making the configuration available to them via UI.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In one of the posts I wrote previously I explain how programming has become configuration.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When you are just starting out, don’t try to imitate the expert.</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/imitating_experts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When you are just starting out, don’t try to imitate the expert." /><published>2020-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/imitating-experts</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/imitating_experts/">&lt;p&gt;Imitate after you have a firm base to understand what and why they are doing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts have hard time explaining things they have internalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to copy them at-least initially will likely lower your confidence and make you waana skip and go home and sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People on YouTube have a “perfect execution” and they usually don’t show how much work goes behind it. A way to look behind their work is to look at them performing Live or streaming Live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For programmers, it can be helpful to look at GitHub commits too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Imitate after you have a firm base to understand what and why they are doing something.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Middleman</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/middlemen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Middleman" /><published>2020-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/middlemen</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/middlemen/">&lt;p&gt;Middlemen companies are weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They provide services from one company to either another company or to consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some example of middlemen services are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stripe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Car Dealers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile Wallets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food Delivery Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ride Sharing Apps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most online e-commerce website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason middlemen are able to operate is because the source company is too complex for most normal people or companies to understand. So they make it convenient for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this also is risky if source company can easily provide the facility themself. Then there is no need of middleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like when Tesla decided to not sell their cars through dealership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Middleman companies sometimes act as affiliate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The source company deals with creating the product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The middlemen deal with selling the product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Middlemen companies are weird.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Support shows how much the company really care</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/support/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Support shows how much the company really care" /><published>2020-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/support</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/support/">&lt;p&gt;It is a part of company which is I feel is often overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customers who come to support actually use your product and they care enough that they are not jumping switch to another app. Instead they are here to get their problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just about pushing a product out. Getting money and then doing nothing. Care for your customers. Not just because they are paid for you and that they will likely continue to use your product … but because it a human thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it easy for them to contact you as easy and fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They may want their problem solved quickly: call link&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe they don’t like talking: put chat link or support email up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the producers side, it also helps to have support costs low by providing FAQs, help guide and improvements to the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple &amp;amp; Tesla do wonderful customer service. Even Samsung when they recalled all their exploding Note 10s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find banks and telecom companies are worst at customer service. Heck they even charge fees without much explanation. The reason customers remain is because jumping to another customer is longer process. They’ll probably jump when an easy transparent option is available (I’ll jump too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some companies which I had interaction with and have excellent customer support service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apple&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cure.fi&quot;&gt;Cure.Fit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wakingup.com/&quot;&gt;Waking Up App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dayoneapp.com/&quot;&gt;Day One App&lt;/a&gt; - These guys never disappoint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pepperfry.com/&quot;&gt;PepperFry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbanladder.com/&quot;&gt;Urban Ladder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swiggy.com/&quot;&gt;Swiggy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is a part of company which is I feel is often overlooked.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Samurai to Modern Army in 10 years</title><link href="www.ankushchoubey.com/samurai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Samurai to Modern Army in 10 years" /><published>2020-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>www.ankushchoubey.com/samurai</id><content type="html" xml:base="www.ankushchoubey.com/samurai/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;… if we dig deep in our history and our doctrine, and remember that &lt;strong&gt;we are not descended from fearful men&lt;/strong&gt; … &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;product img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/samurai/1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan 🇯🇵 was closed to the world for most of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had a history of Samurai and the real encounter they had with outsiders was during Mongol invasion. Whom they had defeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They always were and thought of themself as militarily strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forced-to-upgrade&quot;&gt;Forced to upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the modern age, they suddenly realized that they were on side of the prey, not predators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They feared becoming colonized by westerners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The possibility was very real and they realized they needed to upgrade and upgrade fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-upgrade&quot;&gt;The Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 10 years that followed, they sent their scholars to all around the world and gathered information about everything good they could find about the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like education, military, etc, and then added their own Japanese twist to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took Europe around 100 years to upgrade, going through multiple revolutions during the period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Japan, there were many missteps along the way but in 10 years, they went from a culture of the swordsman to a modern one and were never colonized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few lessons that can be taken from this over-simplistic snippet. These can be applied to business and life in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always upgrade ourself to deal with current and future problems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be flexible enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/observe&quot;&gt;Learn by observing others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop your ego. Move on with times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;history-cannot-be-put-in-such-simple-terms&quot;&gt;History cannot be put in such simple terms.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of missteps with their way and the way the world was in general. I recommend listening to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dancarlin.com/product/hardcore-history-62-supernova-in-the-east-i/&quot;&gt;Hardcore History: Super Nova in the East&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardcore History is a long podcast. I think the below clip captures the essence of this post. &lt;em&gt;(Go fullscreen!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b_iU_gnn28U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post and its content were inspired by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Piece: Wano Arc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghosts of Tsushima &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dancarlin.com/product/hardcore-history-62-supernova-in-the-east-i/&quot;&gt;Hardcore History: Super Nova in the East&lt;/a&gt; (cannot recommend this enough)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/222611-we-must-not-confuse-dissent-with-disloyalty-we-must-remember#:~:text=We%20will%20not%20be%20driven,%2C%20for%20the%20moment%2C%20unpopular%E2%80%9D&quot;&gt;Edward R. Murrow&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cover photo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playstation.com/en-in/games/ghost-of-tsushima-ps4/&quot;&gt;Ghost of Tsushima: PS4&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">… if we dig deep in our history and our doctrine, and remember that we are not descended from fearful men … 1 Edward R. Murrow &amp;#8617;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/samurai/1.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="www.ankushchoubey.com/images/samurai/1.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>